There is one final distinction we
need to understand going forward
because it's going to come up at
every stage of the design lifecycle,
qualitative versus quantitative data.
At every stage of the design lifecycle,
we're interested in
gathering data from users.
Early on that might be
descriptions of what they do
when they're interacting with a task.
Or it might be measures of how long
certain tasks take to complete,
or how many people judge
a task to be difficult.
Later on, though, it might be whether or
not users prefer our new interfaces or
how much better they
perform on certain tasks.
Now data will always fall into one
of two categories, qualitative and
quantitative.
Quantitative is probably
the easier one to describe,
quantitative data
describes anything numeric.
When data is summarized numerically,
we can perform statistical tests and
summaries on it,
draw formal conclusions, and
make objective comparisons.
Now there are a lot of strengths
of quantitative data, but
those strengths come in large part
because quantitative data only
captures a narrow view of what we
might be interested in examining.
It's very strong for
a very small class of things.
Qualitative data covers
pretty much everything else.
Qualitative Data covers descriptions,
accounts, observations,
it's often in natural language.
It could be open ended survey responses,
or interview transcripts, or
bug reports or
just your personal observations.
Because of its flexibility, qualitative
data gives us a much broader and
more general picture of
what we're examining.
But the cost is that it's hard to
generate formal conclusions based on
qualitative data.
Qualitative data may be
more prone to biases.
Now in some circumstances,
we can convert qualitative
data into quantitative data.
For example,
we could count the number of surveys
respondents to an end of course survey
who mentioned course difficulty
in their free response questions.
Now the free response question
would be qualitative data but
numerically summarizing it
generates quantitative data.
Generally speaking, though,
quantitative data and
qualitative data serve different
purposes in a design life cycle.
I've heard it described quantitative
data provides the what,
the qualitative data provides the how or
the why.
When performing need finding or
when doing some initial prototype
evaluations, we're likely interested in
users' qualitative descriptions of their
tasks or
their experiences with the interface.
It's generally only after a few
iterations that we start to be
interested in quantitative analysis,
to find numeric improvements or changes.
We can also use these in conjunction
with one another, collecting both
quantitative and qualitative
data from the same participants.
That's referred to as a mixed method
approach, it's a mix of qualitative and
quantitative data to paint a more
complete picture of the results.