Let's do a quick exercise on
quantitative versus qualitative data.
Let's imagine we're doing end of
course evaluations for some class.
For each of the following types of data,
mark whether it would be considered
quantitative or qualitative.
You can skip ahead, if you don't want to
listen to me read all these out.
We have responses to on a scale of 1
to 5, rate this course's difficulty,
responses to how much time did you spend
per week on this course, responses to
what did you like about this course,
count of students Students mentioning
office hours to the above questions,
percentage of students that completed
the survey, responses to a forum topic
requesting non-anonymous course reviews,
the number of participants in a
late-semester office hours session, and
the transcript of the conversation of
that late-semester office hours session