Quantitative data is numeric.
Any of these things that can
be measured numerically,
really qualify as quantitative data.
Many of these things are things
that we can just count.
We count the number of students
mentioning office hours.
We count the number of participants.
Here we basically count the number of
students that completed the survey and
divided by all
the students in the class.
And here we have them count how
many hours per week they think
they spend in the course.
The first option can be
a little bit tricky.
On a scale of one to five in a numeric
scale, but because students have to
choose one, two, three, four or five,
it's not a continuous numeric scale.
For example, we have no way of
guaranteeing the student sees
the difference between a three and
a four as the same as the difference
between a four and a five.
The types of analysis we can do on the
first kind of data, are more limited.
But nonetheless it's still
is measured numerically, so
it still is quantitative data.