Within the general category of quantitative data,
there are a number of different subdivisions.
These are important because they inform what kind of conclusions we
can generate and what kind of statistical test we can perform.
We'll talk about statistics more when we talk about evaluation,
but it's important to understand what type of data you're
gathering during all phases of the design lifecycle.
So, first, there are four major distinctions in quantitative data: nominal,
ordinal, interval, and ratio data.
Nominal data is also referred to as categorical data.
It arises when we observe the number of instances of different categories.
So, for example, if we asked a bunch of users,
how do you typically commute to work?
These would each be different categories.
Our data would be the number of people that fell into each category.
Ordinal data is similar to nominal data,
but there's some explicit ordering to those different categories.
So, for example, we might ask on a scale of 1-5,
how would you rate your level of satisfaction with your commuting method?
The user would choose highly dissatisfied,
dissatisfied, neutral, and so on.
These are still categories,
but there's an ordering to them.
But, what's important here is that we don't actually
know how big the gaps between these categories are.
It could be that users perceive only a small difference between
neutral and satisfied or only a small difference between satisfied and highly satisfied.
They might perceive the difference between satisfied and highly satisfied as smaller,
for example, than the difference between dissatisfied and highly dissatisfied.
That's where interval data comes in.
With interval data, we do know the exact difference between values.
Imagine if we asked commuters at what time do you leave for work in the morning?
We know that the difference between 6:00 AM and 8:00
AM is the same as the difference between 8:00 AM and 10:00 AM.
So, the interval between the different options is the same,
but that can still lead to some strange comparisons.
8:00 AM isn't twice as late as 4:00 AM.
It's four hours later, but just because eight is twice as much as four,
it doesn't mean 8:00 AM is twice as late as four 4:00 AM.
We know the intervals between the numbers,
but we don't know their ratios.
We often talk about this in the context of temperature.
Sixty-four degrees isn't twice as warm as 32 degrees even though 64 is twice 32.
With interval scales, there is no zero-point,
only intervals between numbers.
That brings us to the fourth kind of quantitative data, ratio data.
Ratio data is just like interval data except it has a zero point.
So, that means we can actually use ratios.
If we ask our commuters how long it takes them to get to work,
we know that someone who says 30 has twice as long a commute as someone who says 15,
and 15 is twice as long as 7.5, and so on.
So, those are our four general types of quantitative data.
But, there are more subcategories that come up among these two.
For example, with nominal data,
we can have single nominal and multi-nominal data.
Our question here is can a person being more than one category at the same time?
Earlier when we had this question,
we phrase it as single nominal.
We ask users to choose only one of these options,
but it would be entirely possible to have users who take
different forms of transportation on a regular basis.
So, why force him to choose only one.
With multi-nominal data we might let them choose more than one option.
So, any given user can fall into multiple categories.
If you read about quantitative data,
you'll see that ordinal data can also be-multi ordinal.
But, to be honest, I've never seen a compelling example of when that might happen,
so I'm not going to show one here.
With nominal data, we can also have binary and non-binary data.
This distinction is a little bit more straightforward.
The example we've already shown is non-binary.
There's more than two different options.
Binary nominal data has only two categories.
This might seem like a silly distinction,
but it's actually important because the type of statistical tests we do with
binary data are a little bit different from
the types of statistical tests we do with non-binary data.
This distinction between binary and non-binary data can also apply to ordinal data.
Non-binary ordinal data is pretty straightforward.
It's a one to five scale or a one to seven scale or anything like that.
But, we can still have ordinal binary data.
For example, what grade did you earn in driver's ed.
We would interpret an implicit ordering between Fail and Pass.
So, that would make an ordinal data,
but there's still only two options, so it's binary data.
With both interval and ratio data,
there's also a distinction between discrete and continuous.
Discrete means it's something countable.
So, if we ask how long is your average commute in minutes,
we're generally expecting people to give an answer in a whole number.
We're not expecting someone to say it takes 15.245 minutes.
So, that would be discrete.
It's a countable number of minutes.
If, on the other hand,
we were to put sensors in people's cars and actually time how long their commutes are,
we would arrive at continuous data.
We would get values like it takes on average 31.2513 minutes for you to commute,
and just like that distinction between binary and non-binary data,
these distinction sometimes informs the type of statistical tests we're supposed to use.
So, these are general categories of
quantitative data as well as some smaller distinctions that might be relevant.
In practice I can share that actually I find relatively
few times in our work where we use interval data.
Using when we're dealing with real numbers,
we're dealing with numbers that have a zero-point like time or number of occurrences.
Similarly, the type of statistical tests that we use for
interval and ratio data are almost always the same.
We similarly use some of the same tests for nominal and ordinal data.
But, I'm getting ahead of myself a little bit.
For now, what's most important is just to understand what kind of data you're collecting.