User-centered design is design that considers the needs
of the user throughout the entire design process.
As far as we're concerned, that's pretty much just good design.
But oftentimes, that isn't the way design is done.
Design has often done to meet
some functional specification of what the tool must technically be able to accomplish,
instead of considering the real needs of the user.
Or sometimes people will go through an entire design process,
believing they understand the needs of the user without ever really checking.
User-centered design is about prioritizing the user's needs,
while also recognizing that we don't know the user's needs.
So, we need to involve them at every stage of the process.
Before we start, we need to examine the user's needs in depth
both by observing them and by asking them direct questions.
After we start designing,
we need to present our design alternatives and prototypes to the user to get feedback.
When we near a design that we like,
we need to evaluate the quality of the design with real users.
Having a good working knowledge of HCI principles helps us go through this more quickly,
but we can't design great interfaces just by applying guidelines and heuristics alone.
We have to interact with our users,
understand their needs, and involve them in the evaluation.