When we talk about user-centered design,
we throw around the word user as if
it's pretty obvious what it means.
The user is the person who uses
the interface that we create, right?
However, that's not the only
person in whom were interested.
There are multiple
stakeholders in this design,
and we want to explore how our design
is going to affect all of them.
The user themselves is what we
call the primary stakeholder.
They're the person who
uses our tool directly.
Secondary stakeholders are people who
don't use our system directly, but
who might interact with
the output of it in some way.
Tertiary stakeholders are people
who never interact with the tool or
even interact with it's output, but
who are nonetheless impacted
by the existence of the tool.
So let's take a couple
of examples of this.
Imagine we're designing a new grade
book tool that makes it easier for
teachers to send progress
reports to parents.
Teachers would interact with the tool,
inputting grades and feedback.
And so teachers would be
our primary stakeholders.
Parents receive the output of that tool.
Parents receive the progress reports.
And so they're secondary stakeholders.
They interact with the output of the
system, but not with the system itself.
Students don't use the system at all,
and maybe they don't even see the
progress reports unless parents decide
to share them.
But they're nonetheless affected
by the existence of this system.
So they're tertiary stakeholders.
School administrators might be another
stakeholder, but where they fall in
this would differ based on how
the school sets up the relationship.
If they can use the tool
to directly monitor and
intervene in student progress,
they might be primary stakeholders.
If they just see aggregated
progress reports so
they can monitor things,
they might be secondary stake holders.
If they never interact with
the system in any way,
they're nonetheless likely affected
by the fact the system is there.
And so they'd be tertiary stakeholders.
In designing this tool, we need to keep
all three kinds of stakeholders in mind.
For example,
how does parents having more consistent
access to great information
affect the students?
It might foster increased involvement by
parents, but it might also facilitate
helicopter parenting, where parents are
too controlling over their kid's school
work and prevent them from developing
the necessary metacognitive skills and
self discipline that they need
to succeed later in life.
User-centered design isn't just about
catering to the user in the center of
this diagram, but
it's also about looking at the impact
of our designs on all the stakeholders.