You might actually come from a software
engineering background, and so
while user-centric designs
sounds obvious to some people,
you might have experienced
the other side of the coin.
In many industries and domains,
software engineers are still left to
design user interfaces themselves.
There's a fantastic book about this
called The Inmates Are Running
the Asylum, by Alan Cooper.
Where he compares technology
to a dancing bear at a circus.
He notes that people marvel
at the dancing bear,
not because it's good at dancing,
but because it dances at all.
The same way, people marvel at
certain pieces of technology not
because they work well, but
because they work at all.
The book was released in 2004 and
since then the user has become more and
more a focal point of design.
And yet there is still places where
individuals with little ACI background
are designing user-facing interfaces for
one reason or another.
Since it's a stronger chance you've
worked in software engineering,
reflect on that a bit.
Have you seen places where software
engineers, data scientists, or
even non-technical people were put in
charge of designing user interfaces?
How did it go?