I encountered this in my first job,
actually.
Somewhere between my freshman and
sophomore years at Georgia Tech,
I had a job as a user interface
designer for a local broadcast company.
I designed an interface, then I handed
it over to a team of engineers for
implementation.
Late in the process, the requirements
were changed a bit and new configuration
screen was needed that the engineers
just went ahead and looked up.
We got the finish tool and
it all worked beautifully and perfectly,
except for this configuration screen.
It was a list of over
50 different settings,
each with 3 to 5 radio
buttons to the side.
Each setting was a different length.
Each radio button label
was a different length.
There was kind of placed
all over the campus.
There was no grid.
It was illegible.
It was unusable, but
it was technically functional.
It met the requirements described in
terms of what the user must be able to
do, just not how usable it was.
Fortunately, there's a greater
appreciation of the value of
user-centered design now
than there was then.
So, many spaces have become so
crowded that the user experience is
what can really set a company apart.
I've actually been noticing a trend
lately toward new user experiences
around really old tasks.
I use an app called stash to buy and
sell small amounts of mutual funds.
Buying mutual funds has
been around forever and
E-Trade has even been doing
that online for a long time.
What differentiates stash
is the new user experience.
Automated investing, simple tracking,
simplified summaries.
User experience design really has
become a major differentiator between
success and failure.