At every stage of this design life
cycle, we're interested in gathering
information from the user to
better inform our designs.
To do that, we need a number of methods
to actually obtain that information.
Fortunately, there are a number of
methods we can employ to try to gather
the information we need.
And in fact,
the majority of this unit will go
through all these different methods.
These will become
the tools in your toolbox.
Things you can call upon to grab the
information you need when you need it.
Not the many of this method are so
well-developed that you can cover them
in the entire units,
or even entire courses.
For example, we'll spend about three or
four minutes talking about
naturalistic observation.
And yet, there are entire textbooks and
courses on how to do naturalistic
observation really well.
The goal of this is to give you
enough information to get started and
enough to know what you
need to explore next.
Remember, one of the original goals of
this class was not just to understand
more HCI but also to understand how
big the field of HCI actually is.