Almost any interface on the computer
can be analyzed from the perspective of
distributed cognition but right now,
I'm most interested in my email.
My email is an unbelievable extension of
my longterm memory because whenever I
see anything in email,
I know I don't actually need to
commit it to my own long-term memory.
It's there, it's safe forever and
if I ever need to find it again,
I'll be able to find it.
Now, finding it might
take some work sometimes,
but rarely as much work as
manually remembering it.
For me, I also mark messages as unread
if I'm the one they're waiting on, or
if I need to make sure
I come back to them.
And so, my email is an external memory
of both all my communications via email,
and tasks that are waiting
on me to move forward.