There are lot of creative ways
we might tackle this problem.
One might be a base social video
game relationship around something
like tender.
Tinder, if this is still around
by the time your watching this,
is a dating app were you express
interest in another's in are only
connected if they also
express interest in you.
We can apply the same
colonoscopy to video games.
You can set it such that My Contacts
can't just look up my game
playing habits.
But if they're also playing or
interested in playing,
they'll learn that I am playing as well.
In terms of social cognition,
that's kind of getting at
the idea of an in-group.
Your behaviors are only seen
by those who share them and
thus are in no position to judge them.