Like distributed cognition, situated action is
strongly concerned with the context within which people interact.
But unlike distributed cognition,
situated action is not interested in the long-term and
enduring permanent interactions amongst these things.
That's not to say that the theory denies the existence of long-term memory,
but just has a different focus.
Situated action focuses on humans as improvisers.
It's interested, not in the kinds of problems that people have solved before,
but in the kinds of novel situational problems that arise all the time.
So, for example, this is the first time I'm filming with my daughter on camera.
I don't know how she'll act.
I don't have contingency plans about how to react
if she acts strangely or if she distracts me from my script.
I'm just going to figure this out as I go along.
This is the kind of interaction that situated action is interested in,
and that's important for us as interface designers.
While we like to think we're in charge of structuring task for our users,
in reality, the tasks that we perform are growing out of this interaction.
We can try our best to guide it in certain directions,
but until we actually get our hands on it,
the task doesn't exist.
The task of me filming with my daughter didn't exist until this moment.
Once we've got our hands on it,
the task is what we do and not what we design.
So, as users, when we use an interface,
when we actually do something,
we're defining the task as they go along.
So, there are three kinds of ways here.
One, we must examine the interfaces we design within the context in which they're used.
Two, we must understand that the task that the users
perform grows out of this interaction with our interfaces. We don't define it.
Three, we can try to structure it as much as we can,
but until users get started,
the task itself doesn't exist.
Once they get started, they play a significant role in defining the task.