Situated action gives us a valuable
lens to examine issues of memory.
We mention in our lessons on memory and
on design principles that
recognition is easier than recall.
People have an easier time
recognizing the right answer, or
option when they see it rather
than recalling it from scratch.
That's in part because memory is so
context dependent.
Recognition provides the necessary
context to identify the right option.
Relying on recall,
means there's little context to cue
the right answer to the users memory.
Now I encountered
an interesting example of
the value of situated
action a little while ago.
My mother just had surgery.
And so I would often go over
to help her out with things.
And everytime I would go over,
she'd have four, five favors to ask me.
Inevitably I would forget
a couple of those favors and
have to be reminded, but
she would always remember.
Why was she so much better able
to remember the favors than me?
Does she just have a better memory?
She didn't make a list.
She didn't write them down or
anything like that.
So the distributed cognition perspective
doesn't find an external memory being
used or anything like that.
My hypothesis from the perspective
of situated action,
is that she has the context
behind the tasks.
She knows why they need to be done.
She knows what will
happen if they aren't.
For her,
they're part of a broader narrative.
For me, they're items on a list.
I have no context for why they're there.
Or what would happen if they're undone.
For her,
they're easy to remember because
they're situated in a larger context.
For me, they're difficult
because they're isolated.