Activity theory is a massive and
well developed set of theories regarding
interaction between various
pieces of an activity.
The theory as a whole is so
complex that you could teach
an entire class on it alone.
It predates HCI.
And in fact, activity theory is one of
the first places the idea of interacting
through an interface actually came from.
In our conversations about HCI though,
there are three main
contributions of activity theory
that I'd like you to come away with.
First, when we discuss
designing tasks and
completing tasks through an interface,
we risk missing a key component.
Why?
We could jump straight to
designing the task, but
why is the user completing
the task in the first place?
That can have significant
implications for our design.
Activity theory generalizes our unit of
analysis from the task to the activity.
We're not just interested
in what they're doing, but
why they're doing it and
what it means to them.
Our designs will be different, for
example, if users are using a system
because they're required to or
because they choose to.
Notice how this is similar to
our discussion of distributed
cognition, as well.
In distributed cognition, we were
generalizing the unit of analysis
from a person,
to a system of people and artifacts.
Here, we're generalizing the unit of
analysis from a task to an activity
surrounding a task.
In both ways, we're zooming out
on the task and the design space.
Second, activity theory puts an emphasis
on the idea that we can create low level
operations from higher level actions.
We saw something similar
to this with GOMS models,
where methods were made up of operators.
This has a special
historical significance.
Before activity theory and similar
theories reached HCI in the 1980s,
HCI was largely concerned
with minute things,
like how quickly a person can click
a button or type in a command.
Activity theory helped us zoom out from
those low level interactions, those low
level operators, to general user needs
at the action or the activity levels.
And third,
activity theory points out that actions
by the user can actually move up and
down this hierarchy.
A common example of
this is driving a car.
The first time you drove a car,
shifting gears between park and
drive was a very conscious
action made up of operators like
grabbing the gear shift and moving it
in the right direction and letting go.
You had to think about how to press the
button, which way to push the stick, and
when to release it.
However, after driving a few times,
shifting gears just
becomes second nature.
It becomes more like an operator.
It shifted from being a conscious goal
to an operator in your broader driving
behavior.
Notice a similarity here to our
previous discussion on learning curves.
How quickly an action moves from being
a conscious action to a subconscious
operator is also a function of how good
the learning curve is on that design.
Notice also, this is similar to
the question of invisible interfaces.
A good invisible interface helps users
focus on their actions inside the task,
rather than the operators they
use to interact with the system.