Cognition on its own is interested in thought processes and
experiences and we naturally think of those as occurring inside the mind.
But distributed cognition suggests that models
of cognition should be extended outside the mind.
This theory proposes expanding the unit we use to analyze intelligence from
a single mind to a mind equipped with
other minds and artifacts and the relationships among them.
So, let's take an example of this.
Amanda, give me a hard addition problem.
1,238 plus 6,437.
Okay, can I do that in my head? No, I
also can't even remember the numbers you just read to me.
But I have a pen and paper here and using those,
I can easily write down the numbers,
so give those numbers to me again.
1,238 plus 6,437.
Okay. Using that, I can now do the calculations by hand and the answer is 7,675.
Now, did I get smarter when I grabbed the pen and paper?
Not really, not by the usual definition of smarter at least.
But the system comprised of myself, the pen,
the paper, is a lot more than just my mind on its own.
The cognition was distributed amongst these artifacts.
Specifically, the paper took care of remembering the numbers for
me and remembering and tracking my progress so far.
So, instead of adding 1,238 plus 6,437,
I was really just adding eight plus seven,
three plus three, two plus four, and so on.