Distributed cognition is a perspective on analyzing systems that helps us
emphasize the cognitive components of interfaces themselves.
It helps us look at things we designed as extensions of the user's own cognition.
We can view anything from notes on a desktop to
the entire Internet as an extension of the user's own memory.
We can view things like Gmail's automatic email filtering
as offloading cognitive tasks from the user.
In looking at things through this lens,
we focus on the output not just of people into
interfaces but on the combination of people and interfaces together.
So, what are they able to do together that neither of them could do individually?
As we close this lesson,
think about this in terms of your chosen areas of HCI.
What are the cognitive components of the areas with which you're dealing?
How do augmented reality and wearable devices
offload some of the users cognition onto the interface?
In educational technology or in HCI for healthcare,
what are the tasks being accomplished by the systems comprised of users and interfaces?