In this lesson, we've talked about
distributed cognition and a couple of related theories.
The commonality of all these theories was
their emphasis on context and integrated systems.
Distributed cognition is interested in how cognition can be
distributed among multiple individuals and artifacts all working together.
By taking a distributed view of interface design,
we can think about what the combination of
our users and our interfaces are able to accomplish.
Situated action and activity theory give additional perspectives on this.
Focusing respectively on the importance of ad hoc improvisation
and the need to emphasize users' motives beyond just their goals.
The common ground for all these theories is that
our interfaces are not simply between the user and their task,
but they also exist in some kind of greater context.