In order to understand the application
of distributed cognition to the cockpit,
it's important for
us to first understand what
challenge it's addressing.
The technical reasons for
this are a bit complex, and
I strongly encourage reading the full
paper to get the full picture.
But to understand the simplified
description I'll give here,
here's what you need to know.
When a plane is descending for landing,
there exists a number of different
changes the pilots need to make
to the wing configurations.
These changes are made at different
speeds during the descent.
When the plane slows
down to a certain speed,
it demands a certain change
to the wind configuration.
The speeds at which these
configuration changes must happen
differ based on a number
of different variables.
So for every flight there's a unique
set of speeds that must be remembered.
That's why the title of this paper is,
How a Cockpit Remembers Its Speeds,
Speeds, plural.
It isn't just remembering
how fast it's going now,
it's remembering a sequence of speeds
at which multiple changes must be made.
The configuration changes to the wings
must be made during the descent at
narrowly defined times.
That creates a high cognitive load.
Pilots must act quickly.
And mistakes could mean the deaths
of themselves and hundred of others.
So how do they do this?
First, the pilots have pages
that contain the speeds for
their descent,
based on different parameters.
The cockpit itself has an entire
booklet of pages like this.
So we know that the cockpit has
its pilots who are responsible for
actually reasoning over things.
But that booklet forms that cockpits
long term memory of different speeds for
different parameters.
Then, prior to the descent, the pilots
find the page from that booklet
that corresponds to their
current parameters.
They pull it out and
pin it up inside the cockpit.
That way,
the sheet is accessible to both pilots.
And they're able to check one
another's actions throughout.
This becomes one form of
the cockpits short term memory,
a temporary representation
of the current speeds.
At this point,
we have to attribute knowledge of
those speeds to the cockpit itself.
If we were to isolate either pilot,
they would be unable to say what
the speeds are from memory, but
without the pilots to interpret those
speeds, the card itself is meaningless.
So it's the system of the entire
cockpit, including the pilots,
the booklet and the current
card that remembers the speeds.
Then as the pilots begin the descent,
they mark the different speeds right on
the speedometer with
these little speed bugs.
The speed bugs tell them
which speeds to remember
in a way that can just
be visually compared.
When they see the speedometer
pass a speed bug,
they know it's time to
make a certain change.
This is like the working memory for
the cockpit.
The short-term memory stores the numbers
in a way that the pilots can
reason over, but
the speed bugs on the speedometer
store them in a way that they can
very quickly just visually compare.
They don't need to remember the numbers
themselves, or do any math.
All they have to do is visually compare
the speed bugs to the current position
of the speedometer.
So what do we see from
the system as a whole?
Well, we see the long term
memory in the book of cards.
We see a short term memory
in the card they selected.
We see a working memory in
the speed bugs on the speedometer.
And we see decisions on when to make
configuration changes distributed across
the pilots and these artifacts.
No single part of this cockpit,
not the pilots, not the speed bugs,
not the cards, could perform the action
necessary to land a plane on their own.
It's only the system as
a whole that does so.
That's the essence of
distributive cognition.
The cognition involved in landing
this plane is distributed
across the components of the system.
This is a deeper notion than just
using interfaces to help us do tasks.
The important thing here is
that these different interfaces
serve cognitive roles in the system.