Distributed cognition is deeply
related to the idea of cognitive load.
Recall the cognitive load refers to
your minds ability to only deal with
a certain amount of
information at a time.
Distributed cognition suggests
that artifacts add additional
cognitive resources.
That means the same cognitive load
is distributed across a greater
number of resources.
Artifacts are like plugging
extra memory into your brain.
Driving is a good example of this.
Sometimes while driving, you're
cognitive load can be very, very high.
You have to keep track of
the other cars around you.
You have to keep track of your own
speed to monitor your route planning.
You have to make predictions
about traffic patterns.
You have to pay attention to your own
level of gasoline, or in my case,
electric charge.
You might be attending to something in
your car as well, like talking to your
passenger, or keeping an eye on
your child in the back seat.
It can be a big challenge.
A GPS is a way of off-loading one of the
tasks, navigation, on to another system.
And thus, your cognition, is now
distributed between you In the GPS.
Turn on cruise control and now it's
distributed across the car, as well.
Your off loading the task of
tracking your speed to the car.
Every task you also de-artifacts,
decreases your own
personal cognitive load.