Something important to note is
that distributed cognition isn't
really another design principle.
Distributed cognition is more of
a way of looking at interface design.
It's a way of approaching the problem
that puts your attention squarely on how
to extend the mind across artifacts.
We can actually view many of our
design principles as examples of
distributed cognition.
So this is my computer,
and when I set this up,
I wasn't thinking about it in
terms of distributed cognition.
And yet we can use distributive
cognition as a lens through which to
view this design.
For example, I always have my
calendar open on the right.
That's a way of off loading having to
keep track of my daily schedule in
working memory.
It bugs me if I have a teleconference
to attend or somewhere I need to go.
In fact I rely on this so
much it gets me in trouble.
It doesn't keep track of
where I need to be for
a given meeting and if I fail to
keep track of that in working memory
I might end up at home when I
need to be at Georgia Tech.
We can even view trivial things like
a clock as an example of distributed
cognition that prevents me from
having to keep track of the passage
of time manually.
The point is that distributed cognition
is a way of looking at interfaces and
interface design that focuses your
attention on what systems as a whole can
accomplish as opposed to
individuals on their own.