Distributed cognition is a fun one
to reflect on because we can take it
to some pretty silly extremes.
We can go so far as to say that
I don't heat up my dinner.
The system compromised of myself and
the microwave heats it up.
And I offload the need to track the time
to cook on to my microwave's timer.
And that's a perfectly valid
way of looking at things.
But what we're interested in
is places where interfaces
don't just make our
lives more convenient.
We're interested in places where
they systems comprised of us and
interfaces are capable of doing more,
specifically because those interfaces
exhibit certain cognitive qualities.
The systems might perceive,
they might remember, they might learn,
they might act on our behalf.
In some way they're all floating
a cognitive task from us.
And as a result, the system
comprised of us and the interface,
is capable of doing more.
So reflect on that a bit, what is the
place where the system comprised of you
and some number of interfaces is
capable of doing more than you alone?
Specifically, because of the cognitive
qualities that the interfaces possess.