[NOISE] Feedback cycles are the way in
which people interact with the world,
and then get feedback on
the results of those interactions.
We'll talk about the ubiquity
of those feedback cycles.
Then we'll talk about the gulf of
execution, which is the distance between
a user's goals and the execution of the
actions required to realize those goals.
Then we'll talk about
the Gulf of evaluation,
which is the distance between
the effects of those actions and
the user's understanding
of those results.
We'll discuss seven questions we should
ask ourselves when designing feedback
cycles for users and
we'll also look at applications of these
in multiple areas of our everyday lives.