It's not a coincidence that I'm
filming this in my basement.
This actually happened
to me a few weeks ago.
The circuit to our basement was tripped,
which is where we keep our modem, so
our internet was out.
Now this is a brand new house and it was
the first time we tripped a breaker, so
I pulled out my flashlight and
I opened the panel.
And none of the labels over here clearly
corresponded to the breaker I was
looking for over here.
I ended up trying every single one
of them and still it didn't work.
I shut off everything in the house.
Why didn't it work?
In reality,
there was a reset button on the outlet
itself that had to be pressed.
The only reason we noticed it was
because my wife noticed something out of
the corner of her eye turning on and
off as I switched these.
That was a terribly
large gulf of execution.
I knew what I wanted to accomplish,
I could translate it into the system's
terms easily, reset a breaker.
But figuring out the actions to
accomplish that goal was very difficult.
That's a large gulf of execution.
How was that?
>> [SOUND] What?
Sorry, I wasn't paying attention.
>> You weren't watching?
[LAUGH] So I have no way of
knowing if that was good or not?
Isn't that a terrible
gulf of evaluation?
I joke, but a lack of feedback
on your performance at a task,
whether it be filming, like I'm doing
now or doing a project like you’ll
do later in our material, presents the
same kind of poor gulf of evaluation.