Well, what do we know?
We know the car was off.
We know this is clearly the power
button based on how it's labeled and
where it's located.
And most importantly,
when I pressed it we heard kind
of a happy confirmation-y sound.
So did the car turn on?
Actually, it didn't.
To turn this car on you
have press the brake petal
while pressing the on button.
The car doesn't do a great job
of helping us across that goal
of execution.
There's no indicator that you're doing
it wrong until you've actually already
done it wrong.
But the car does give us
a short gulf of evaluation.
If you do it incorrectly, an alert pops
up on the dashboard letting you know you
need to press the brake pedal and
then press the on button.
The output presented
is easy to interpret.
As presented in the context of when
you need to know that information, so
you kind of understand that it’s
a response to what you just did.
So here we have some trouble
with the gulf of execution but
the gulf of evaluation
is still pretty short.
So now that I see this message
I press down the brake pedal,
press the on button [SOUND]
and now the car is on.