So here are a few ideas that I had.
We know that the screen can show
an alert when you try to turn the car on
without pressing the brake pedal down.
Why not show that alert as soon as
the driver gets in the car every time?
That doesn't widen the gulf of
execution for an expert user, but
it does narrow it for a novice user,
because even a novice can see that alert
the first time they get in the car.
But what still throws me off to this day
is the sound the car makes when you try
and turn it on.
Watch.
[SOUND] Did the car turn on?
No.
It didn't that time.
[SOUND] Now it turned on.
So it plays the same sound initially
when you press the button and then plays
a different follow up sound to confirm
that the car actually turned on.
I know why they do this, that one
sound just confirms that you pressed
the button successfully while the other
sound confirms that the car turned on.
But for me, I would just as soon have
two different sounds confirm whether or
not you just pressed the button or
whether the car turned on.
That way, just the presence of a sound
confirms the fact that the button was
pressed and the nature of the sound
confirms the effect of that press.