I asked you earlier to pick an area of HCI in which you're
interested and reflect on it as you go through this course.
Depending on the area you selected,
feedback cycles can play a huge number of different roles.
In health care, for example,
feedback cycles are critical to helping patients manage their symptoms.
That relies on the results of certain tests being easy to interpret and evaluate.
Feedback cycles are also present in some of
the bigger challenges for gesture-based interactions.
It can be difficult to get feedback on how system interpreted
a certain gesture and why it interpreted it that way.
Compare that to touch, where it's generally
very easy to understand where you touched the screen.
So, think for a moment about how
feedback cycles affect the area you chose to keep in mind.