There are a few things we could do here.
We might build some kind of
buzzer into the card reader to
let the customer know when
they can take their card out.
That would make sure that
they don't leave without it.
ATM machines often do this, actually.
They'll ring a buzzer until the card and
the cash are removed.
But that's noisy and
potentially irritating.
It would mess with the ambiance of
a restaurant or something like that.
We could do something super complicated,
like pair the credit card
with a smartphone and
ring the phone when it gets too
far away from the credit card.
But that requires adding some new
technology to every single credit card,
which could be a pretty big expense.
So what about something simpler?
Why not force a customer to remove the
credit card in order to get the receipt
and their goods?
Unless they're going to walk away
without what they came to buy,
that'll ensure that they
remember their card.