Here are five quick tips for bridging gulfs of execution.
Number one, make functions discoverable.
Imagine a user is sitting in front of your interface for the very first time.
How would they know what they can do?
Do they have to read the documentation, take a class?
Ideally, the functions of the interface will be discoverable.
Meaning that they can find them clearly labeled within the interface.
Number two, let the user mess around.
You want your user to poke around and discover things,
make them feel safe in doing so.
Don't include any actions that can't be undone.
Avoid any buttons that can irreversibly ruin their document or set up.
That way the user will feel safe discovering things in your interface.
Number three, be consistent with other tools.
We all want to try new things and innovate,
but we can bridge gulf of execution nicely,
by adopting the same standards that many other tools use.
Use ctrl c for copy and ctrl v for paste.
Use a diskette icon for save even though no one actually uses floppy disks anymore.
This makes it easy for users to figure out what to do in your interface.
Number four, know your user.
The Gulf of Execution has a number of components: Identifying intentions,
identifying the actions to take,
and taking the actions.
For novice users, identifying their intentions and actions are most valuable.
So, making commands discoverable through things like menus is preferable.
For experts though, actually doing the action is more valuable.
That's why many experts prefer the command line,
although it lacks many usability principles targeted at novices, it's very efficient.
Number five, feedforward.
We've talked about feedback,
which is a response to something that the user did.
Feedforward is more like feedback on what the user might want to do.
It helps the user predict what the result of an action will be.
For example, when you pull down the Facebook news feed on your phone,
it starts to show the little refresh icon.
If you don't finish pulling down, it doesn't refresh.
That's feedforward. Information on what will happen if you keep doing what you're doing.
Many of these tips are derived from some of the fundamental principles of design,
pioneered by people like Don Norman and Jacob Nielsen,
and we'll cover them more in another lesson.