The second challenge is for the task to express to the user through the interface,
the output of the actions that the user took.
This is called the Gulf of Evaluation because the user needs to
evaluate the new state of the system in response to the actions they took.
Like the Gulf of Execution,
we can think of this in terms of three parts.
There's the actual physical form of the output from the interface,
what did it actually do in response?
There might be something visual,
there might be a sound, a vibration,
some kind of output.
The second is interpretation.
Can the user interpret the real meaning of that output.
You might think of this in terms of a smartphone.
If a smart phone vibrates in your pocket,
can you interpret what the meaning of that output
was or do you have to pull the phone out and actually see?
Then the third phase is evaluation.
Can the user use that interpretation to
evaluate whether or not their goals were accomplished?
You can imagine submitting a form online.
It might give you output that you interpret to mean that the form was
received but you might not be able to
evaluate whether or not the form was actually accepted.
Once they've received and interpreted that output,
the final step is to evaluate whether or not
that interpretation means that their goals were actually realized within the system.
Take our on-demand video service example again.
Imagine that the user has gotten all the way to finding the program that they
want to watch and they've press the play button on the remote.
Imagine the interface responds by hiding
the menus that they were using to navigate amongst the service.
Can they interpret the meaning of that output?
Can they evaluate whether or not
that interpretation means that their goals were realized?
If they're a novice user maybe not,
an expert might correctly interpreted the screen
blacking out is because the service is trying to load the video,
they then evaluate that interpretation
and determined that their goals have been realized,
but the service is trying to play the show they want to watch.
But a novice user might interpret
that output to mean that the service has stopped working at all,
like when your computer just shuts down and the screen goes black.
They then incorrectly evaluate that their goals were not actually realized in the system.
We might get over this by showing some kind of buffering icon.
That's a different kind of output from the system that helps the user correctly
interpret that the system is still working on the actions that they put in.
They then can evaluate that maybe their goals were correctly realized after all,
because the system is still working to bring up their show.
So, as you can see, each of these three stages presents some unique challenges.