Let's take a thermostat, for example.
I have a goal to make the room warmer,
so
I do something to my thermostat with
the intention of making the room warmer.
What does the system do as a result?
Well, it turns the heat on, that would
be the successful result of my action.
But how do I know that
the heat was turned on?
Well, maybe I can hear it,
I might hear it click on.
But that's a one time kind of thing and
it might be quiet.
And if I'm mishearing it,
I have no way of double checking it.
So I'm not sure if I heard it,
and I have to go find a vent and
put my hand on it and
try to feel the heat coming out.
And there's more going on in a heater,
it might have worked,
but the heater doesn't immediately
turn on for one reason or the other.
These are signs of a large
gulf of evaluation.
Neither the sound or the vent are
optimal displays because they're either
hard to reach or possible to miss.
Feeling the heat might be
easy to interpret, but
hearing the heater turn on might not.
So either way, I have to do
a lot to evaluate whether or
not my action was successful.
And this is all for
a very small piece of feedback.
Ideally if I wasn't successful, we want
the system to also tell me why I wasn't
successful so I can evaluate what I
did wrong and respond accordingly.
There's a very large gulf of evaluation
if there's no indicator on the actual
thermostat.
So how can we resolve that?
Well, simple.
We just mark on the thermostat
that the heat is on.
That sounds trivial, but
nothing in the fundamental design of
this system demanded a note like this.
It's only in thinking about the system
from the perspective of the user
that we find that need.
I can let you know as well,
this system still isn't very ideal.
For various reasons,
it'll turn the heater on or
the air conditioning off even when it
hasn't reached the temperature I put in.
And it gives me no indication of why.
I can look at the system and evaluate
that the temperature is set to lower
than the current
temperature in the room.
But at the same time,
I can see that the heater isn't on.
Under those circumstances,
I have no way of knowing if the heater's
malfunctioning, if the switch is wrong,
or I don't even know.
In this case, it might just be
that it's set to the wrong mode.
The mode is visible, but
after I remembered to check it,
it appears to be malfunctioning.
We can imagine an alternative message
on the screen indicating the direction
of the relationship or something similar
that would give some sign that it's
currently set incorrectly.