Here are five quick tips for bridging gulfs of evaluation.
Number one; give feedback constantly.
Don't automatically wait for whatever the user did to be
processed in the system before giving feedback.
Give them feedback that the input was received.
Give them feedback on what input was received.
Help the user understand where the system is in executing
their action by giving feedback at every step of the process.
Number two; give feedback immediately.
Let the user know they've been heard even when you're
not ready to give them a four response yet.
If they tap an icon to open an app,
there should be immediate feedback just on that tap.
That way even if the app takes a while to open,
the user knows that the phone recognize their input.
That's why icons briefly gray out when you tap them on your phone.
Number three; match the feedback to the action.
It might seem like this amount of constant immediate feedback would get
annoying and if executed poorly, it really would.
Subtle actions should have subtle feedback.
Significant actions should have significant feedback.
Number four; vary your feedback.
It's often tempting to view our designs as existing solely on a screen,
and so we want to give the feedback on the screen.
But the screen is where the interaction is taking place,
so visual feedback can actually get in the way.
Think about how auditory or haptic feedback can
be used instead of relying just on visual feedback.
Number five; leverage direct manipulation.
We talked about this a lot more, but whenever possible,
let the user feel like they're directly manipulating things in the system.
Things like dragging stuff around or pulling something to make it larger or smaller,
are very intuitive actions because they feel like they're
interacting directly with the content. Use that.
Again, we talk far more about this in another lesson,
but it's worth mentioning here as well.
By loading these things into your short-term memory several times,
we hope to help solidify them in your long-term memory.
That relationship is actually something we also talk about elsewhere in this unit.