What time is it?
You can go ahead and go to lunch.
Did that exchange make any sense?
I asked Amanda for the time and she replied by saying I can go ahead and go get lunch.
The text seems completely nonsensical and yet hearing that,
you may have filled in the context that makes this conversation logical.
You might think that I asked a while ago what time we were breaking for
lunch or maybe I mentioned that I forgot to eat breakfast.
Amanda would have that context and she'd use it to
understand why I'm probably asking for the time.
Context is a fundamental part of the way humans interact with other humans.
Some lessons we'll talk about even suggests that we are
completely incapable of interacting without context.
If context is such a pervasive part of the way humans communicate,
then to build good interfaces between humans and computers,
we must equip computers with some understanding of context.
That's where context-sensitive computing comes in.
Context-sensitive computing attempts to give computer interfaces
the contextual knowledge that humans have in their everyday lives.
For example, I use my mobile phone differently
depending on whether I'm sitting on the couch at home,
or using it in my car,
or walking around on the sidewalk.
Imagine I didn't have to deliberately inform my phone of what mode I was in though.
Imagine if it just detected that I was in my car and
automatically brought up Google Maps and audible for me.
Services have started to emerge to
provide this but there's an enormous amount of research to be
done on context-sensitive computing especially as it relates to things like wearables,
augmented reality, and ubiquitous computing.