I always find it interesting how
certain technologies seem to come
around full circle.
For centuries we only interacted
directly with the things that we built
and then computers came along.
And suddenly we needed interfaces
between us and our tasks.
Now, computers are trying to actively
capture natural ways we've always
interacted.
Almost every computer I encounter
now days has a touch screen.
That's a powerful technique for creating
simple user interfaces because it
shortens the distance
between the user and
the tasks they’re trying to accomplish.
Think about someone using a mouse for
the first time.
He might need to look back and
forth from the screen to the mouse,
to see how interacting down here,
change things he sees up here.
With a touch based interface,
he interacts the same way he uses
things in the real world around him.
A challenge can sometimes be a lack
of precision, but to make up for
that we've also create
pen based interaction.
Just like a person can
use a pen on paper,
they can also use a pen
on a touch screen.
And in fact,
you might be quite familiar with that,
because most Udacity courses
use exactly that technology.
They record someone writing on a screen.
That gives us the precision necessary
to interact very delicately and
specifically with our task.
And as a result tablet based interaction
methods have been used in fields like
art and music.
Most comics you find on the internet
are actually drawn exactly like this,
combining the precision of human
fingers with the power of computation.