There's one final thing you must understand about
the guidelines and heuristics and principles we've talked about.
They're only half the picture.
They're necessary for good design, but they aren't sufficient.
You can't just grab these guidelines off the shelf,
throw them at a new task,
and expect to have a perfect interface the first time.
These principles give you a solid foundation.
But every domain, every task,
every audience has its own unique requirements and criteria.
To design usable interfaces,
you have to understand your specific user.
Remember, that isn't you.
What that means is that you have to go out and find what your users need.
You have to get inside their head and understand the task.
You have to prepare multiple different ideas for them to try out.
You have to evaluate those ideas with real users.
You have to take that experience and use it to improve your design,
and start the process all over again.
These guidelines and principles are useful in
making that process as efficient as possible,
but they aren't sufficient on their own.
These principles are only half the picture.
The other half are the methods.