One way of knitting together
the different ideas of HCI
is to start very close and zoom out.
At the narrowest level,
we might view HCI as the interaction
between a person and an interface.
This is the processor model of
the role to human knit system.
This too looks almost like
an interaction between two computers,
one just happens to be a human.
But humans' actions are approached
almost computationally.
If you're going to take this model,
we need to understand a lot about what
the human can sense,
remember, and physically do.
The model approaches HCI
in this manner as well.
It distills the human's role into goals,
operators, methods and
selection of rules,
all of which can be externalized.
But this is a pretty narrow view of HCI.