When we started that conversations I
commented that when you do HCI right,
users won't actually know
you've done anything at all.
Good HCI disappears between the user and
the tasks that they're completing.
As a result, people can underestimate
how complex good HCI can be to leverage.
In this unit, one of my goals has
been to help pull back the curtain
on all the theories that
go on behind the scenes
of the designs of some of
the interfaces that you use everyday.
So as we close this unit, take a second
to reflect on the interfaces you use
that have disappeared between you and
the task.
Focus especially on interfaces that
were never visible in the first place,
not interfaces that became
invisible by learning.
Which of the principles that we've
discussed do you now see at play
in the design of some
of those interfaces?