For me, I'm actually using an example
of one of these interfaces right now.
I have a teleprompter in front of me.
I didn't always use a teleprompter, but
as soon as I tried one, I was hooked.
And part of that is because of how
well designed the interface is.
The very first time I used it,
it made things immediately easier,
instead of introducing
a new learning curve.
First, it uses very simple interactions,
quick presses that accomplish anything I
could need during the actual
recording process.
Second, it builds on a good mental
model of the task that I'm performing.
It understands, that while recording,
the only things I need to do regularly
are pause, play, scroll back,
and scroll forward.
There are a lot of other
options that it has but
it keeps those out of the way during
the actual recording process,
because they're not
necessary at the time.
Personally though, I think the
teleprompter is great to analyze from
the prospective of
distributed cognition.
I struggle when recording
with talking too fast.
Without the teleprompter,
I have to remind myself to slow down,
while also remembering what to say.
That's a lot to keep in
memory at the same time.
The teleprompter lowers the cognitive
load involved in remembering what to
say, but
it also controls my speed because I
can't read what hasn't yet appeared.
So the teleprompter takes care
of two cognitive processes.
Remembering what I have to say, and
monitoring the speed at
which I am presenting.
So the system comprised
of the teleprompter and
me is better at recording
than I am alone.