Here are five quick tips for using HCI and Agile development together,
especially for mitigating the risks to
the user experience presented by this more Agile development process.
Number one, start more traditional.
Start with a more traditional need-finding and prototyping process
and shift to more Agile development once you have something up and running.
Jacob Nielsen describes this as doing some foundational user-research.
Once you have something up and running,
you have a way of probing the user experience further,
but you need something solid to begin with,
and that comes from the more traditional process.
Number two, focus on small changes.
Notice that when I was doing live prototyping in AB testing,
I was making a small change to an existing interface,
not building an entire new site from scratch.
Number three, adopt a parallel track method.
Agile development often uses short two-week sprints and development.
Under that setup, have the HCI research one sprint ahead of the implementation.
The HCI team can do two weeks sprints of
need-finding prototyping and low-fidelity evaluation.
Then, hand the results to the development team for their next sprint.
Number four, be careful with consistency.
One of our design principles was consistency both
within our interfaces and across interface design as a whole.
If your interface caters to frequent visitors or users,
you'll want to be conservative in how often you mess with their expectations.
If you're designing for something like a museum kiosk though,
you can be more liberal in your frequent changes.
Number five, nest your design cycles in Agile development,
you go through many small design cycles rapidly,
and each cycle gives you a tiny bit of new information.
Take all that new information you gather,
and use it in the context of
a broader more traditional design cycle aimed at long-term substantive improvements,
instead of small optimizations.