Where did these changes come from?
We can think of them in terms of some of the costs
associated with elements of the design lifecycle.
Think back to before the age of the Internet,
developing software was very expensive.
It required a very specialized skill set.
Software distribution was done the same way we sold coffee mugs or bananas,
you'd go to the store and you'd physically buy the software.
That distribution method was expensive as well.
If you ship software that was hard to use,
the cost of fixing it was enormous.
You had to mail each individual person an update disk,
and really the only way to get user feedback or even to find out if it was usable,
was the same way you would do it before distribution,
by having users come in for testing.
All of this meant, there was an enormous need to get it right the first time.
If you didn't, it would be difficult to fix the actual software,
difficult to get the fix to users,
and difficult to find out that a fix was even needed.
Shigeru Miyamoto, the creator of Nintendo's best video game franchises,
describe this in terms of video games by saying,
"A delayed game is eventually good but a rushed game is forever bad".
The same applied to software.
Fast-forward to now though, is that still true?
Development isn't cheap now but it is cheaper than it used to be.
A single person can develop in a day what would have
taken a team of people months to do, 20 years ago.
Thanks to advances in hardware,
programming languages, and the available libraries.
You can look at all the imitators of
popular games on either the Android or the iPhone app store,
to quickly see how much development costs have come down.
It's certainly feasible to churn out
a really quick imitator when something becomes popular.
But more importantly, distribution for software is
now essentially free and updating software is essentially free as well.
Every day you can download new apps and have them update automatically in the background.
If you release something that has a bug in it,
you can fix it and roll out the fixed immediately.
Miyamoto's quote is no longer really accurate,
because it is possible to fix games after they're released.
Tesla for example, regularly pushes software updates to its cars via the Internet.
In the video game industry,
day one patches that fixed glitches on the very first day of release,
has pretty much become the standard.
Perhaps most importantly, we can gather usage data from
live users automatically and essentially for free as well.
It isn't just usage data,
it's product reviews, error reports, buzz on the Internet.
Lots of feedback about our applications now comes naturally,
without us having to spend any money to gather it.
What all this means is,
there is now more incentive to build something
fast and get it to users to start getting real feedback,
as early as possible.
Now make no mistake, this isn't
justification to just throw out the entire design lifecycle.
The majority of HCI design and research still goes through with a longer process.
You need several iterations through
the full design lifecycle for big websites, complex apps,
anything involving designing hardware,
anything involving a high-profile first impression
and really anything involving anything,
even somewhat high in stakes.
But that said, there exists a new niche for rapid development.
Maybe you came up with an idea for a simple Android game,
in the time it would take you to go through this longer process,
you could probably implement the game and get it in front of a real users,
and get a lot more feedback.
That's what we're discussing here.
How do you take the principles we've covered so far and
apply them to a rapid, agile development process?