Before I describe the current ideas behind when to go for an agile development process,
let's see what you think.
Here are five possible applications we might develop.
Which of these would lend itself to an agile development process?
So, feel free to skip ahead to the quiz if you don't want to listen to me, read them out.
A camera interface for aiding MOOC recording.
A tool for helping doctors visualize patient info in surgery.
A smartwatch game to play in short five-minute sessions.
A wearable device for mobile keyboard entry.
A mobile app for aggregating newsfeeds across networks.
A navigation app for the console of an electric car.