One application of Agile development
in HCI is the kind of new idea of
live prototyping.
Live prototyping is a bit of
an oxymoron, and the fact
that it's an oxymoron speaks to how
far along prototyping tools have come.
We've gotten to the point in some areas
of development where constructing actual
working interfaces is just as
easy as constructing prototypes.
So here's one example of this,
it's a tool we use at
Udacity called Optimizely.
It allows for drag and
drop creation of real working webpages.
The interface is very similar to many of
the wire-frame tools out there, and yet
this website is actually live.
I can just click a button and
this site goes public.
Why bother constructing prototypes
before constructing my final interface,
when constructing the final interface
is as easy as constructing prototypes?
Of course, this only addresses one of
the reasons we construct prototypes.
We don't just construct them because
they're usually easier, we also
construct them to get feedback before
we roll out a bad design to everyone.
But when we get to the point of making
small little tweaks or small revisions,
or if we have a lot of experience with
designing interfaces in the first place,
this might not be a bad place to start.
It's especially true if the cost
of failure is relatively low, and
if the possible benefit of
success is particularly high.
I would argue that's definitely the case
for any kind of e-commerce site.
The cost of failure is maybe
losing a few sales but
the possible benefit is gaining more
sales for a much longer time period.
I'm sure anyone would risk having
fewer sales on one day for
the possible reward of having
more sales every subsequent day.