Agile development techniques don't replace the design life cycle,
they just caffeinate it.
We're still doing need-finding but we're probably just doing it a little bit more
tacitly by reading user feedback or checking out interaction logs.
We're still brainstorming design alternatives,
but we're really just coming up with them in our head
because we then immediately move them on to prototyping.
Our prototypes are still just prototypes.
They just happen to work.
We're still doing evaluation by rolling our changes out to
only certain participants first to make sure the respons is good.
The results of that evaluation then feed the same process over and over again.
So, taking an agile approach to the design lifecycle really doesn't change cycle itself,
it just changes the rate at which we go through it and
the types of prototypes and the types of evaluation that we actually do.
Remember also, the Chamberlain sharpen maiden
advocated still doing the initial need-finding step.
Rarely, will we go from no interface at all to
a working prototype quite as quickly as we go
through revisions of those working prototypes.
So, it's useful to do an initial need-finding phase the way we normally would do it.
Then, proceeding to a more agile revision process
once we have a working prototype to actually tweak and modify.