In this unit, we've discussed the HCI research methods that formed the design life cycle,
an iterative process between need-finding,
brainstorming design alternatives, prototyping,
and evaluation with real users.
We've also discussed the ethics behind this kind of research and how
it applies to some more modern agile software development methodologies.
Now, in this wrap-up lesson,
we want to explore a couple of examples of the full design life cycle in action.
We also want to tie into the design principles unit and
explore how we can use
the design principles and research methods in conjunction with one another.