At the end of the last iteration through the design cycle,
we had two interface prototypes,
each with significant weaknesses.
Our voice command interface struggled in loud areas,
where exercisers are often exercising.
Our screen-based interface presented too high a gulf of execution.
But notice how far we've come at this point.
We now have a pretty complete and nuanced view of the task and our possible solutions.
So, now let's go through one more iteration to get
something we can actually implement and deploy.
Our needfinding has come along with the point of understanding
the completely hands-free interfaces are more usable,
but we also know that gesture-based interaction is
still technologically not totally feasible,
and voice space isn't perfectly reliable.
So, now we might come up with a new alternative, a hybrid system.
The voice interaction and on-screen touch interaction
aren't incompatible with one another.
So, our new alternative is to develop a system that supports both,
allowing users to use voice commands most of the time and
default to touch commands in situations where the voice commands won't work.
So, they always have full functionality,
but usability is still maximized.
So, we create a new prototype,
basically merging our two prototypes from the previous iteration.
There is still pretty low fidelity because we
haven't tested this particular combination yet,
and the next stages of sophistication is going to be pretty expensive to develop.
So, we want to make sure that it's worth pursuing.
Then, we evaluate that,
and we find it's good enough to go ahead and move forward with producing it.