The design principles we describe in our other unit are deeply
integrated throughout the design life cycle. They don't supplant it.
You won't be making any great designs just by applying those principles,
but they streamline things.
In many ways, design principles capture the takeaways and
the conclusions found by this design life cycle in the past,
in ways that can be transferred to new tasks and new interfaces.
In uncovering needs, many of our needs are
driven by current understanding of user abilities.
Task analysis allows us to describe those needs,
those tasks in formal ways to equip the interface design process,
and cognitive load lets us keep in mind how much users are asked to do at a time.
Direct manipulation gives us a family of techniques that we
want to emphasize in coming up with our design alternatives.
Mental models provide us an understanding of how
the design alternatives might mesh with the user's understanding of the task.
Distributed cognition gives us a view on
interface design that lends itself to design at a larger level of granularity.
Here we're designing systems not just interfaces.
Design principles in general give us some great rules of
thumb to use when creating our initial prototypes and designs.
Our understanding of representations ensures that the prototypes we
create match with users mental models that we uncovered before.
Visible interfaces help us remember that
the interface should be the conduit between the user and the task,
not the focus of attention itself.
Then the vocabulary of feedback cycles,
the gulf of execution and evaluation give us ways to
evaluate and describe our evaluations of the interfaces that we design.
The notion of politics and values in interfaces allow us
to evaluate the interface not just in terms of it's usable interactions,
but in the types of society it creates or preserves.
Those usability heuristics that we apply to our prototyping are also a way of evaluating
our interface and mentally simulating what
a user will be thinking while using our creations.
These principles of HCI were all
found through many years of going through the design lifecycle,
creating different interfaces, and exploring and evaluating their impact.
By leveraging those lessons,
we can speed to usable interfaces much faster.
But applying those lessons doesn't remove the need to go talk to real users.