Over the past several lessons,
you've been exploring how the design life cycle applies to
the area of HCI that you chose to explore.
Now that we've reached the end of the unit,
take a moment and reflect on the life cycle that you've developed.
How feasible would it be to actually execute, what would you need?
What users do you need?
How many? When do you need them?
There are right answers here, of course.
Ideally you'll need users early and often.
That's what user-centered design is all about.
In educational technology, that might mean having some teachers,
and students, and parents that you can contact frequently.
In computer-supported cooperative work,
that might mean having a community you can visit often to see the new developments.
In ubiquitous computing, that might mean going as far as having someone who specializes
in low fidelity 3D prototypes to quickly spin up new ideas for testing.
Now that you understand the various phases of the design life cycle,
take a moment and reflect on how you use them iteratively
and as a whole in your chosen area of HCI.