If research really is your calling though,
then you might want to move on to a PhD which can have a specialization in HCI as well.
Now, a PhD isn't for everyone.
There's a tendency to view it as the next logical step after a master's degree,
but a PhD program is far more of an apprenticeship program.
At Georgia Tech, at least, a PhD actually
requires fewer classes to complete than a master's,
but that's because 90 percent of your time is spent
working closely with a faculty research adviser.
But if you're very interested in research,
the PhD may very well be the way to go.
So, as a reminder, here were some of the project areas that
have ongoing research in HCI going on here at Georgia Tech.
A PhD program is a huge commitment.
It's your full-time job for typically five years.
It's absolutely not for everyone,
but it absolutely is for some people.
So, if you're really passionate about what you've learned here,
a PhD focusing on HCI maybe the way to go.