The research side of HCI connects to the
relationship between HCI and psychology.
And if we zoom out even further
on this hierarchy of disciplines,
we might say that human
factors engineering itself
is in many ways the merger of
engineering and psychology.
As well as other fields of design and
cognitive science.
In HCI, the engineering side takes
the form of software engineering, but
this connection to psychology remains,
and in fact, it's symbiotic.
We use our understanding of psychology,
of human perception,
of cognition to inform
the way we design interfaces.
We then use our evaluations of
those interfaces to reflect
on our understanding
of psychology itself.
In fact, at Georgia Tech, the Human
Computer Interaction class is cross
listed as a Computer Science and
Psychology class.
So let's take an example of this.
In 1992, psychologists working
at Apple wanted to study
how people organized the rapid flow
of information in their work spaces.
They observed that people tended
to form piles of related material,
kind of like a less formal
filing system, and so
they then designed a computer interface,
that would mimic that ability.
Finally, they used the results of that
development to reflect on how people
were managing their work
spaces in the first place.
So in the end, they had a better
understanding of the thought processes
of their users as well as an interface
that actually helped users.
So in the end,
their design of an interface with an HCI
informed their understanding
of psychology more generally.
We came away with a better understanding
of the way humans think about their work
spaces because of our
experience designing something
that was supposed to help them
think about their work spaces.