Now that we've talked at length about what HCI isn't,
let's talk a little bit about what HCI actually is.
On the one hand, HCI is about research.
Many of the methods we'll discuss are about researching the user,
understanding their needs and evaluating
their interactions with designs that we prototype for them.
But on the other hand, HCI is about design.
After all, design is that prototyping phase,
even though we're prototyping with research in mind.
HCI is about designing interactions to help humans interact with computers,
oftentimes using some known principles for good interaction,
things like designing with distributed cognition in mind or making sure
the user develops good mental models of the way the interface works,
or making sure to design with universal design in mind.
We'll talk about all these topics later in our conversations.
You don't need to worry about understanding any of these right now.
What is important to understand right now,
is that these aren't two isolated sides.
The results of our user research inform the designs we
construct and the results of our designs inform our ongoing research.
Again, you might notice this is very similar to
the feedback cycles we're designing for our users.
They use what they know to participate in the task,
and then use the feedback from that participation to inform what they know.
We use what we know to design good interfaces,
and then use the results of those interfaces to inform our ongoing research.
This is the heart of what HCI is for the purpose of our conversations;
using research to inform our designs and using
the results of those designs to inform our ongoing research.
In this cycle, appears anywhere that humans are using computers to participate in tasks.
That can be sitting at a desk using a screen.
That could be using a smartphone or a smartwatch.
That can be participating with some kind of touch or gesture-based system,
or it could be some interesting emerging technologies like virtual and augmented reality.
In HCI, we're interested in the general principles and
methods for designing and researching all of these things.