This is a computer.
Or at least,
this is probably what you think of
when you think of the term computer.
But this is also a computer.
And so is this.
>> Hey!
>> This is Amanda, my video producer.
>> Go on, I'm rolling.
>> Right, and so is this.
And so is this, and this, and
this, and this, and even this.
And so is this.
[SOUND] And so is this.
Hey David?
>> One second,
trying to get to Squirtle.
There we go.
With mobile devices and
augmented reality,
HCI is quite literally everything.
Pokemon Go was released a few
days before I recorded this and
augmented reality games like this
turn effectively the entire world
into an instance of HCI.
Even out here in the middle of nowhere,
I'm still doing
something with computers.