We have humans and we have computers and
we're interested in
the interaction between them.
That interaction can take
different forms though.
The most obvious seems to be the human
interacts with the computer and
the computer interacts with
the human in response.
They go back and forth interacting,
and that's a valid view.
But it perhaps misses the more
interesting part of HCI.
We can also think of the human
interacting with the task,
through the computer.
The interaction is really between
the human and the task and
the computer in the middle just
mediates that interaction.
Or to put this differently,
the human and
the computer together,
interact with the task.
Ideally in this case, we're
interested in making the interface as
invisible as possible, so the user
can spend as little time focusing on
the interface and instead focus on the
tasks that they're trying to accomplish.
Realistically, our interfaces
are likely to stay somewhat visible.
But our goal is to let the user spend
as much time as possible thinking about
the task,
instead of thinking about our interface.
We can all probably remember times
when we've interacted with a piece of
software and
we felt like we spent all our time
thinking about how to work the software.
As opposed to accomplishing what we
were using the software to do in
the first place and that's frustrating.
So our goal as designers,
is to help the human feel like they're
interacting directly with that task.
While our interface, kind of vanishes,
in the middle of that interaction.