Video games actually give us some
great examples of interfaces
becoming invisible.
A good video game is really
characterized by the player feeling like
they're actually inside the game world,
as opposed to controlling it by
pressing some buttons on a controller.
We can do that through some
intuitive controller design like
pressing forward moves forward, and
pressing backward moves backwards.
But a lot of times we'll rely on
the user to also learn how to control
the game over time.
But as they learn, it becomes invisible
between them and their interaction.
A classic example of a place where
interaction is more visible,
is the idea of having more than one
remote control that controls what
feels like the same system.
So I have these two controllers that
control my TV and my cable box together.
And for me it feels like this
is just one task, watching TV.
But technologically,
it's actually different tasks.
So I have to think about am I using
the number pad on this controller or
this controller, depending on what
I'm trying to do at a given time.
So I spend a lot of time
thinking about the interface and
not as much thinking about the task.