Now, what we've described so
far is a huge field,
far too big to cover in any one class.
In fact there are lots of places where
you can get an entire masters degree or
PhD in human computer interaction.
Here are some of the schools
that offer programs like that.
And these are just the school that
offer actual degree programs in HCI,
not computer science degrees
with specializations in HCI,
which would be almost any
computer science program.
So let's look more closely at
what we're interested in for
the purpose of the next several weeks.
To do that, let's look at where HCI
sits in a broader hierarchy of fields.
We can think of HCI as a subset of
a broader field of human factors
engineering.
Human factors engineering is interested
in a lot of the same ideas that
we're interested in.
But they aren't just
interested in computers.
Then there are also sub
disciplines within HCI.
This is just one way to represent this.
Some people, for example, would put UI
design under UX design, or put UX design
on the same level as HCI, but
this is the way I choose to present it.
Generally, these use many of the same
principles that we use in HCI,
but they might apply them
to a more narrow domain, or
they might have their own principles and
methods that they use in addition to
what we talk about in HCI in general.
So to get a feel for what we're
talking about when we discuss HCI,
let's compare it to these
other different fields.