The first common method we can use to
flush out design alternatives is called
personas.
With personas we create actual
characters to represent our users.
So let's create a persona for
the problem of helping exercisers
take notes while reading books.
We'll start by giving her a name and
a face,
and then we'll fill out some details.
We want to understand
who this persona is.
We want to be able to
mentally simulate her.
We want to be able to say,
what would Anika do in this situation?
What is she thinking when
she's about to go exercise?
What kind of things might interrupt her?
We might want to put in some more
domain specific information as well.
Like, why does this person exercise?
When do they exercise?
What kind of books do they like?
How are they feeling
when they're exercising?
Where do they usually exercise?
We want to create at least three or four
of these different personas, and perhaps
more depending on how many different
stakeholders we have for our problem.
The important thing is that these
should be pretty different people,
representing different
elements of our designs,
different elements of our task, so
we can explore its entire range.
We don't want to design just for
Anika, but we do want to design for
real people.
And so we should define personas that
represent the range of real people that
we care about.
That way we can ask our questions like,
how would Janet feel about
this design alternative?
Using this,
we can start to extort the space and
find the options that
has the most appeal.