Personas are meant to give us a small
number of characters that we can reason
about empatheticly.
However, it can sometimes also be
useful to formulaicly generate
a large number of user profiles
to explore the full design space.
We can do this by defining a number of
different variable about our users and
the possibilities within each.
So here our few examples,
we can ask ourselves,
do we care about novice users or
expert users or both?
Do we care about users that read
casually, that read seriously, or
both kinds of users?
Do we only want to cater to users that
are highly motivated to use our app,
which can make things
a little bit easier on us?
Or do we want to assume that it
won't take much to stop them
from using our app?
Can we assume a pretty high-level
of technological literacy, or
are we trying to cater to
more casual users as well?
And are we interested in users that are
going to use our app all the time, or
in users who are going to use our
app only occasionally, or both?
All of these decisions present some
interesting design considerations that
we need to keep in mind.
For example, for users that are going
to use our tool very often,
our major consideration is efficiency.
We want to make sure they can do what
they need to do as quickly as possible.
And oftentimes,
that might be relying on them to
know more about how to use the app.
But if we're designing for
users that use our app pretty rarely,
we need to make sure to keep all the
interactions discoverable and visible.
That way every time they
come back to the app,
it's like the first time
they came back to it.
They don't need to remember anything
from the previous time because
we don't know how long it's been
since the last time they've used it.
If we want to design for both,
then we have our work cut out for us.
We need to either design very efficient
interaction methods that nonetheless
are discoverable and
visible, or we need to design
two sets of interaction methods.
One way that's very discoverable and
visible, and
one way that's very efficient.
We see this with our example of
the hotkeys for copy and paste.
If you don't know how to use them,
you have a way of finding them.
So it caters to either novice users or
users who haven't used
the program in awhile.
But because you can also
do it with simple hotkeys,
it caters to those users who
use it more frequently and
makes it more efficient for those
who are going to be doing it a lot.
In deciding what to design,
we need to understand what groups,
what profiles we're designing for, and
use that to inform our design decisions.
Inexperienced designers often
make big mistakes here.
They either try to design for
everybody, which rarely works, or
they design with no one
in particular in mind.
And so, certain areas of program are
good for some users, others are good for
other types of users.
An entire program as a whole is not
good for any particular type of user.
So it's very important that we
understand the range of users that we're
designing for, and that we make sure
the range is actually something that we
feasibly can design for.