Building on the idea of a persona we can
take that person and stretch her out
over time and see what is she thinking,
what is she doing at various stages of
interacting with our interface or
interacting with the task at hand.
I've also heard this called
journey maps although
journey maps usually cover
much longer periods of time.
They cover the entire
expanse of the persons life,
why they are interested in something and
where they are going from here.
Timelines can be more narrowed
to the specific time which
users are interacting with the task or
with the program.
So our goal is to take that persona and
stretched it out overtime.
So for our example, what sparks Anika to
decide to exercise in the first place?
That might be really useful
information to know.
After she decided to exercise,
what did she do next?
In theory she doesn't
just start right there.
She goes exercise somewhere
she has kind of setup process.
Then what does she do?
In this case, maybe she set ups her
audiobooks as she actually pushes play,
puts her headphones in, and so on.
And then there's probably a period
of actual exercise in our example,
and then at the end,
she turns off the audiobook.
The usefulness of drawing this as
a timeline is it starts to let
us ask some pretty
interesting questions.
What prompts this person to actually
engage in the task in the first place?
What actions lead up to the task?
How are they feeling at
every stage of the task?
And can we use that?
How would each design alternative
impact their experience throughout this
process?
For example, if our persona for
Anika was that she really doesn't like
to exercise but she knows she really
needs to, then we know her mood during
this phase might be kind of glum.
We need to design our app with
the understanding that she might have
kind of low motivation to
engage in this at all.
If our app is a little
bit frustrating to use,
then it might turn her off
of exercising all together.
On the other hand,
if Anika really likes to exercise,
then maybe she's in a very
good mood during this phase.
And if she likes exercising on its own,
maybe she forgets to even set
up the audio book at all.
So then we need to design
our app with that in mind.
We need to design it such that there's
something built into it that could maybe
remind her that when she
gets to a certain location,
she meant to start her audio book.
So stretching this out as
a timeline lets us explore not only
who the user is, but also what they're
thinking and what they're feeling.
And how what we design can
integrate with a task that they're
participating in.
Exploring our different design
alternatives in this way
allows us to start to gauge which
designs might have the greatest
potential to positively
impact the user's experience.
And they also let us explore what might
be different between different users.
Our design might need to be different
for Anika who loves to exercise, and
Paul who hates exercising.
This timeline let's us start to
explore those more personal elements.