We can create general timelines for routine interactions with our design alternatives,
but it's often even more interesting to examine
the specific scenarios users will encounter while using our interfaces.
Rather than outlining the whole course of interaction,
scenarios let us discuss specific kinds of
interactions and events that we want to be able to handle.
This is sometimes also referred to as storyboards,
sequences of diagrams or drawings to outline what happens in a particular scenario.
The difference between timelines,
and storyboards, and scenarios,
is that timelines, in my experience at least,
tend to be pretty general.
They're how a routine interaction with the interface or
routine interaction with the design alternative goes.
Scenarios and storyboards are more specific.
They are about a particular person interacting in
a particular way with particular events coming up.
So, let's build one of these scenarios.
Morgan is out jogging when a fire engine goes by.
It's so loud that she misses about 30 seconds of the book.
How did she recover from this?
What we want to go through that question with each of our different design alternatives?
For our touch interface,
she would need to stop,
pull out her phone, turn on the screen, and pause the book.
For our voice interface,
she would have to wait for the fire engine to finish passing and then say, "Rewind."
Because chances are, if it's too loud for her to hear her book,
it's probably too loud for her phone to hear her voice command.
But for a gestural interface,
she could simply make the gesture that will allow her to pause the book,
and then play again when the fire engine has finished passing.
Ideally, we'd like to outline several such scenarios and
explore them for various personas and design alternatives.
Of course, now, we're reaching three degrees of freedom,
so it's not crucial that we explore every possible combination of persona,
scenario, and design alternative.
This is a more fluid process of exploring,
what ideas have potential,
and what ideas are worth exploring further?
We might find there are certain combinations of
scenarios and personas that we really care about,
that completely rule out certain design alternatives.
If we really care about allowing her to exercise in a loud area,
that goes ahead and tells us that
a voice interface might not be the direction that we want to go in.
Or, for another example,
if our earlier need-finding exercises revealed
a significant number of exercisers carry weights or other things in their hands,
then gestural interfaces start to look a lot less promising.
Now, as video technology has gotten more and more ubiquitous,
storyboards have also taken on a different form in a lot of prototypes that I have seen.
There's been an emergence of what is called video prototyping, which is basically,
doing a video mockup of what someone would actually look like
interacting with a certain interface to show to people so that they can see,
whether or not, that would actually be something that
would help them in their everyday life.
So, storyboards taken into an extreme,
could actually be a video mockup of what it would be like to use the finished product.