In our unit on principles, we talk about
task analysis, including things like
cognitive task analysis or
human information processor models.
Performing those analysis
as part of our need finding
also gives us a nice tool for
exploring our design alternatives.
Using this, we can start to look at how
exactly the goals, operators, methods,
and selection rules of the Gomes model
map up to the ideas of our design
alternatives.
How does the user achieve each of
their goals in each interface?
How relatively easy are the goals to
achieve between the different design
alternatives?
With the results of our cognitive
task analysis, we can start to
ask some deeper questions about what
the user is keeping in mind as well.
Given what we know about things
competing for our user's attention,
what are the likelihoods that
each interface will work?
In some ways, this is a similar process
to using personas we outlined earlier,
but with a subtle difference.
Personas are personal and
meant to give us an empathetic
view of the user experience.
User models are more objective and
meant to give us a measurable and
comparable view of the user experience.
So ideally, the result of this kind of
analysis is we would be able to say that
the different alternatives have these
different phases and these different
phases have different efficiencies or
different speeds associated with them.
So, we could start to say exactly
how efficient one design is compared
to another.