So personally here's my answer.
For me scenarios are really the only
ones that include the entire
task context.
You can make the case that personas and
timelines do as well, but I tend to
think that these are a little bit too
separated from the task to
really include the context.
Personas and user profiles, on the other
hand, do include the users context.
They include plenty of information
about who the user is,
why they're doing this task,
and what their motivations are.
You could make the argument as well,
that scenarios and
timelines include the user's context.
Because the way we describe them,
they're instances
of the personas being stretched
out over a scenario or over time.
User profile probably do the cleanest
job of delineating the target audience.
With our personas we have kind of
a fuzzy idea of who are different
users are.
But our user profiles really formally
articulate the space of your users in
which we're interested.
As far as general workflows that's
what user modeling is really good at.
It really outlines the phases or
steps or operators that users
use in a general sense.
You could say the same thing about
timelines to a certain extent although
timelines are more focused on what
the user is thinking and feeling and
less on their actual workflow
with regard to the task.
As far as capturing activity over time,
scenarios, timelines, and
user modeling all have an element
of time in what they analyze.
And possibly one of the bigger
benefits of using scenarios
is they allow us to capture
potential edge cases more easily.
Timelines, user models,
user profiles and personas are all about
the general user or the general
routine interaction with the task.
But scenarios let us pose
interesting and novel situations so
that we can kind of mentally simulate
how our different design alternatives
will work with that scenario.
For example, we wouldn't say that
a fire engine going by Morgan,
which is listening to an audiobook,
is a routine thing, so
it probably wouldn't come up in our
timeline or in our user modeling.
But we can develop a scenario that
explores how is she going to deal with
that particular event.
And while it might seem
a little silly to focus so
much on edge cases,
as we do more and more design,
we start to discover that
there are a lot of edge cases.
They're all different.
But a lot of our time is spent dealing
with those unique circumstances that
fall pretty far outside the routine
interaction with the program.