So let's apply these techniques to
some of the ideas that I came up with
earlier.
The first thing I might
do is go ahead and
rule out any of the ideas that
are just technologically unfeasible.
Coming up with those wasn't a waste of
time because they're part of a nice
broad free flow brainstorming process.
But skin based interfaces and
augmented reality, probably are not on
the table for the immediate future.
I might also rule out the options
that are unfeasible for
some more practical reasons.
We might a small team of developers,
for example.
So, a dedicated wearable device
isn't really our expertise.
Now the one I might do next is create
some timelines, covering a sequence of
events in exercising to use to
explore these alternatives further.
I might notice that the users
I observed and talked with,
valued efficiency in getting started.
They don't want to have to walk through
a complex set up process every time they
start to exercise.
I might also use my user persona's to
explore the cognitive load of the users
in these different alternatives.
They have a lot going on, between
monitoring their exercise progress,
observing their environment,
and listening to the book.
So, I'm going to want to keep
cognitive load very low.
Now granted, we always want to keep
cognitive load pretty low, but
in this case, the competing
tasks are significant enough,
that I want to sacrifice features for
simplicity, if it keeps that
cognitive load pretty manageable.
Now based on these timelines and
these personas, I would probably
end up here with three design
alternatives that I want to explore.
One is a traditional touch interface,
a smartphone app.
Then unfortunately it means the user is
going to have to pull out their phone
whenever they want to take a note.
But if I can design it well enough
that might not be an issue.
I also know that approach gets
me a lot of flexibility so
it's good to at least explore it.
A second approach is
gestural interfaces.
I know that people aren't usually
holding their device while exercising.
So it would be great if they had
someway of interacting without pulling
out their phone.
Gestures might let us do that.
Now in our gesture recognition
is in its infancy, but
we might be able delivered
smart watched technology or
something like a Fitbit to
support interaction via gestures.
A third approach is a voice interface,
I know people generally aren't
communicating verbally while exercising,
so why not a voice interface?
That can even double as
the note taking interface.
So now that I have three
design alternatives that I'm
interested in exploring, I would move
on to the prototyping stage which is
building some version of these
that I can test with real users.