The biggest mistake that a designer can
make is jumping straight to designing
an interface without understanding
the users or understanding the task.
The second biggest mistake though is
settling on a single design idea or
a single genre of
design ideas too early.
This can take on multiple forms.
One form is staying too allegiant
to existing designs or products.
Take the thermostat, for example, again.
If you settled on tweaking
the existing design of a thermostat
you would never invent the Nest.
So if you're working on
improving an existing interface,
try to actually distance yourself
from the existing solutions,
at least initially during
the brainstorming session.
But this is also a problem if
you're designing interfaces for
new tasks as well.
Imagine for instance, that while you
were observing people exercising, you
started sketching interface ideas like
how to make the buttons big enough or
what buttons need to be
featured prominently.
In doing so, you're getting tunnel
vision and missing out on any design
alternatives that might involve voice or
gesture control.
So the second biggest mistake
you can make is focusing
too strongly on one alternative
from the very beginning,
instead of exploring the entire range
of possible design alternatives.
The reason why this is
such a common mistake,
is that there's this natural tendency
to think of it as a waste of
time to develop interfaces you're
not going to end up using.
You think you can get it done faster
just by picking one early on and
sticking to it.
But flushing out ideas for interfaces
you don't end up using isn't a waste of
time, because by doing so you continue
to learn more about the problem.
The experience of exploring those ideas
that you leave behind will make you
a better designer for
the ideas that you do choose to pursue.
In all likelihood your ultimate
design will be some combination of
the design alternatives
that you explored earlier.
So, take my security system for
an example.
There are two ways of interacting with
it, the key pad and the key chain.
Two different designs that,
in this particular instance,
integrated just fine.
Different alternatives won't always
integrate side by side this easily,
but the design process as a whole is
an iterative process of brainstorming,
combining, abandoning, revising and
improving your ideas, and
that requires you start with
several ideas in the first place.