The goal of the design alternative stage of the design life cycle is to generate
lots of ideas and then synthesize those ideas into a handful worth exploring further.
So, we started with some heuristics for generating lots and lots of
ideas through both individual and group brainstorming.
Then, we proposed some methods for exploring
those ideas and deciding which ones to pursue.
Now, these were all thought experiments.
We haven't actually gotten to the point of designing any of these interfaces yet.
That'll be the next stage.
At the end of the design alternative stage,
we want to select a handful of designs that are worth carrying forward
and prototyping to then give to users for actual feedback.