When you first start brainstorming,
your goal is to generate a lot of ideas.
These ideas can be very short,
very high level, and very general.
Your goal is just to generate an expanse of them.
They don't even have to be ideas for interfaces,
just any idea for solving the problem.
If you look online, you'll find lots of great guides to how to brainstorm ideas.
One of the most interesting takeaways is that research generally indicates it's
better to start with individual brainstorming. That's not intuitive though.
We often hold meetings for brainstorming,
but it should start out individually.
That's because brainstorming is most effective
when it initially generates a lot of ideas.
But groups tend to coalesce around ideas pretty early.
So, start out individually.
Generate a lot of ideas.
Each idea needs only be a few words or a sentence.
Don't worry right now if they're good or bad. Write down everything.
Think about how you design with different types of
interactions like gestures and voice and touch.
Think about how you design for different interfaces like smartwatches,
or tablets, or augmented reality.
Think about how you designed for different audiences,
novices, and experts or kids and adults.
Get silly with it. Some of the best ideas start as silly ideas.
How would you design this for your dog or for your cat?
How would you design this for someone with three arms or three legs? Go nuts.
Your goal is to generate a lot of ideas.
These are going to get loaded into your mind,
and they'll crop up in interesting ways throughout the rest of the design process.
That's why it's important to generate a lot of ideas.
You never know when they'll come up.