Here are five quick tips for
effective individual brain storming.
Number one, write down the core problem.
Keep this visible.
You want to let your mind enter
a divergent thinking mode but
you also want to remain
grounded in the problem.
Writing down the problem and
keeping it available will help you
remain focused while remaining creative.
Number two.
Constrain yourself.
Decide you want at least on idea in
a number of different categories.
Personally, I try to make sure I
have at least three ideas that use
nontraditional interaction methods,
like touch and voice.
You can constrain yourself
in strange ways too.
Force yourself to think of
solutions that are too expensive or
not physically possible.
The act of thinking in these
directions will help you out later.
Number three.
Aim for 20.
Don't stop until you have twenty ideas.
These ideas don't have to be very
well-formed or complex, they can be
simply one sentence descriptions
of designs you might pursue.
This forces you to think
through the problem,
rather than getting tunnel
vision on an early idea.
Number 4.
Take a break.
You don't need to come up with all
of these at once and, in fact,
you'll probably find it's easier
if you leave and come back.
I'm not just talking about
a ten minute break either.
Stop brainstorming and decide to
continue a couple days later but
be ready to write down new
ideas that come to you.
Number 5.
Divide and conquer.
If you're dealing with a problem like
helping kids lead healthier lifestyles,
divide it into smaller problems and
brainstorm solutions to those.
If we're designing audio books for
exercises, for
example, we might divide it into
things like the ability to take and
review notes, or the ability to
control playback hands-free.
Divide it like that and
brainstorm solutions to each
individual little problem.