Group brain storming presents
some significant issues.
Thompson in 2008 laid out four behaviors
in group brainstorming that can block
progress.
The first is social loafing.
People often don't tend to work as hard
in groups as they would individually.
It's easy to feel like
the responsibility for
unproductive brainstorming is shared and
deflected.
In individual brainstorming,
it's clearly on the individual.
The second blocker is conformity,
people in groups tend to want to agree.
Studies have shown that
group brainstorming leads
to convergent thinking.
The conversation the group has tends to
force participants down the same line of
thinking, generating fewer and
less varied ideas than
the individuals acting alone.
During brainstorming,
though, the goal is diversion thinking,
lots of ideas, lots of creativity.
The third blocker is
production blocking.
In group brainstorming,
there are often individuals who dominate
the conversation and make it difficult
for others to actually be heard.
Their ideas can thus command more
weight, not because of the strength of
the ideas, but because of
the volume of the description.
The fourth blocker is
performance matching.
People tend to converge in terms
of passion and performance,
which can lead to a loss
of momentum over time.
That might be able to get people excited
if they're around other excited people
initially, but
more often than not, it saps the energy
of those who enter with enthusiasm.
In addition to these four challenges,
I would add a fifth.
Group brainstorming may also be
prone to power dynamics, or biases.
No matter how supportive and
collaborative a boss might be,
there'll likely always exist a tacit
pressure to build on her suggestions,
which dampens creative brainstorming.
There also exists considerable
literature stating that other biases
based on gender, age, race, complain
to these group sessions as well.
Now note that this doesn't mean group
brainstorming should be avoided
altogether.
What it means is that we should enter
into group brainstorming with strong
ideas of how to address these issues,
ideally,
after a phase of individual
brainstorming has already occurred.