To have an effective group brainstorming
session, we need to have some rules to
govern the individual's behavior to
address those common challenges.
In 1957,
Osbourne outline four such rules.
Number one, Expressiveness.
Any idea that comes to mind, share
it out loud, no matter how strange.
Number two, nonevaluation.
No criticizing ideas,
no evaluating the ideas themselves yet.
Number three, quantity.
Brainstorming as many as possible.
The more you have, the greater
your idea of finding a novel idea.
Number four, building.
While you shouldn't
criticize other's ideas,
you should absolutely
try to build on them.
Then, in 1996, Oxley, Dzindolet and
Paulus presented four additional rules.
Number one, stay focused.
Keep the goal in mind at all times.
Number two, no explaining ideas.
Say the idea and move on.
No justifying ideas.
Number three, when you hit a roadblock,
revisit the problem.
Say it again out loud.
Number four, encourage others.
If someone isn't speaking up,
encourage them to do so.
Note that all eight of these rules
prescribe what individuals should do,
but they're only effective if
every individual does them.
So it's good to cover these rules,
post them publicly, and
call one another on breaking from them.