The rules given by Osborn, Oxley,
Dzindolet and Paulus are about helping
individuals understand how they should act in group brainstorming.
Here are a few additional tips though that apply less to
the individual participants and more to the design of the activity as a whole.
Number one, go through every individual idea.
Have participants perform individual brainstorming ahead of
time and bring ideas to the group brainstorming session,
and explicitly make sure to go through each one.
That will help avoid converging around an idea too early and make sure everyone is heard.
Number two, find the optimal size.
Social loafing occurs when there's a lack of individual responsibility.
When you have so many people that not everyone will get to talk anyway,
it's easy for disengagement to occur.
I would say group brainstorming session should generally
not involve more than five people.
If more people need to give perspectives than that,
then you can have intermediate groups that then send ideas along to a later group.
Number three, set clear rules for communication.
Get a 20-second timer and when someone starts talking, start it.
Once the timer is up,
someone else gets to speak.
The goal is to ensure that no one can block others ideas
by talking too much whether intentionally or accidentally.
Number four, set clear expectations.
Enthusiasm starts to wane when people are
unsure how long a session will go or what will mark its end.
You might set the session to go a certain amount of time or
dictate that a certain number of ideas must get generated.
No matter how you do it,
make sure that people participating can
assess where in the brainstorming session they are.
Number five, end with ideas, not decisions.
It's tempting to want to leave a brainstorming session with
a single idea on which to move forward, but that's not the goal.
Your brainstorming session should end with several ideas,
then let them percolate in everyone's mind
before coming back and choosing the ideas to pursue later.