The relationship between HCI and user experience design is a little bit closer.
In fact, if you ask a dozen people working in the field,
you'll likely get a dozen different answers about the difference.
For the purposes of our conversations,
we'll think about the difference like this.
HCI is largely about understanding the interactions between humans and computers.
User experience design is about dictating the interactions between users and computers.
In order to design user experiences very well,
you need to understand the user.
You need to understand their interactions with interfaces.
That's why I personally consider user experience design to be
a subfield of the broader area of HCI.
In our conversations, we'll use the principles and methods from
HCI to inform how we design user experiences.
But it's important to note that this relationship is deeply symbiotic.
We might use that understanding to inform how we design
user experiences but then we evaluate
those designs and based on their success or failures,
we'll use that to inform our increasing knowledge of human computer interaction itself.
If our understanding leads us to create good designs,
that provides evidence that our understanding is correct.
If we create a design with some understanding and that design doesn't work,
then maybe our understanding was flawed, and now,
our understanding of human computer interaction as a whole will increase.
This is similar to something called design-based research which we'll talk about later.
Using the results of our designs to conduct
research and you might also notice
this is very related to our concept of feedback cycles.
Just as a user uses an interface to participate in
some task and then evaluates the result of their interaction,
so also, we design interfaces and evaluate their success.
You'll find the feedback cycles are really all over
this course and all over the world in general.