Depending on the area of HCI that you chose to explore,
direct manipulation might be a big open question.
So, for gesture-based interaction for example,
you generally not actually touching anything.
Direct manipulation is contingent on
immediate feedback that maps directly to the interaction.
So how do you create that in a gesture-based interface?
This is a big challenge for virtual reality as well.
Virtual reality thrives on making you feel
like you're somewhere else both visually and auditorily,
but it has a long way to go can aesthetically.
How do you create the feeling of direct manipulation based on physical action,
where you can only give feedback visually or auditorily?
So, take a second, and reflect on how these principles of
direct manipulation apply to your chosen area of HCI.