Whether through using
direct manipulation,
through innovative approaches
to shrinking these gulfs or
through the user's patience and
learning, our ultimate goal is for
the interface between the user and
the task to become invisible.
What this means is that even though
there is an interface in the middle,
the user spends no
time thinking about it.
Instead, they feel like they're
interacting directly with the task
rather than with some interface.
So for example, I have a stylus and I'm
going to write on this tablet computer.
I'm interacting with an interface
just translating my drawing
into data in the system.
But for me, this feels just like
I'm writing on a normal page.
That feels just like writing on paper.
This interface between me and
the data representation of my drawing
underneath is pretty much invisible.
I feel like I'm writing on paper.
Contrast that with trying
to draw with a mouse.
That feels extremely unnatural.
I'm very well aware of the mouse as
the interface between myself and
this drawing task.
So the direct manipulation facilitated
by the stylus gets me much closer to my
task and helps the interface
disappear between me and
what I'm trying to accomplish.