We shouldn't fall into the trap of
assuming that just because an interface
has become invisible,
the design is great.
Interfaces become invisible not
just through great design, but
also because users learn to use them.
With enough practice and experience,
many users will become sufficiently
comfortable with many interfaces
to feel invisibly
integrated in the task.
So take driving for example.
Lets say I'm driving a car and
I discover I'm headed right for someone.
What's my reaction?
Well I turn the wheel to the side and
I press my brake.
It's instinctive.
I do it immediately, but
think about that action.
If I was just running
down the street and
suddenly I saw someone in front
of me would it be natural for
me to go like that?
Of course not.
The steering wheel was an interface
I used to turn to the left.
But it's become invisible during
the task of driving because of all my
practice with it.
But just because the interface has
become invisible doesn't mean it's great
interface.
People spend months learning to drive,
they pay hundreds of dollars for
classes.
And they have to pass
a complicated test.
Driving is important enough that it
can have that kind of learning curve.
But for the interfaces that we design,
we generally can't expect users to
give us an entire year
just to learn to use them.
We'll be lucky if they give us
an entire minute to learn to use them.
So our goal is to make our
interfaces invisible by design.