Our goal is to create interfaces that
are invisible from the moment the user
starts using them.
They should feel immediately as if
they're interacting with the task
underlying the interface.
Now this is an extremely tall order and
one we honestly probably won't meet
very often, but it's the goal.
In fact, in my opinion,
this is why people tend to
underestimate the complexity of HCI.
When you do things right,
people won't be aware that
you've done anything at all.
So how do we create interfaces that
are invisible from the very first moment
the user starts using them?
That's precisely what we'll discuss in
a lot of our conversations about HCI.
We'll talk about principles for
creating interfaces that disappear like
leveraging prior expectations and
providing quick feedback.
We'll also talk a lot about how
to get inside the user's head and
understand what they're seeing when they
look at an interface that we can make
sure that they're internal
mental model matches the system.
In fact, if we consider invisibility
to be a hallmark of usable design,
then this entire course could be
retitled Creating Invisible Interfaces.