Here are five tips for designing invisible interfaces.
Number one, use affordances.
We talked more about affordances when we discuss design principles in heuristics,
but affordances are places where
the visual design of the interface is just how it's supposed to be used.
Buttons are for pressing,
dials are for turning,
switches are for flicking.
Use these expectations to make your interface more useable.
Number two, know your user.
In visibility means different things to different people.
Invisibility to a novice means the interactions are all natural,
but invisibility to an expert means maximizing efficiency.
Know for whom you're trying to design.
Number three, differentiate your user.
Maybe you're designing something for both novices and experts.
If that's the case,
provide multiple ways of accomplishing tasks.
For example, having Copy and Paste under the Edit menu,
keeps those options discoverable.
But providing control c and control v as shortcuts keep those actions efficient.
Number four, let your interface teach.
When we think of teaching users how to use our software,
we usually think of tutorials or manuals.
But ideally the interface itself will do the teaching.
For example, when users select Copy and Paste from the Edit menu,
they see the hotkey that corresponds to that function.
The goal is to teach them more efficient way of performing the actions
without requiring them to already know that in order to do their work.
Number five, talk to your user.
We'll say this over and over again,
but the best thing you can do is talk to the user.
Ask them what they're thinking while you use an interface.
Note especially whether they're talking about the task or the interface.
If they're talking about the interface,
then it's pretty visible.