One of my favorite examples of
an interface that is invisible by design
comes from a video game called Portal 2.
In lots of video games, you use
a control stick to control the camera in
game, but different people
have different preferences for
how the camera should behave.
Some feel if you press up,
you should look up.
Others like myself, feel if you
press down you should look up,
more like you're controlling
an airplane with a joystick.
In most games you have to set this
manually by going to options,
selecting camera controls,
and enabling or
disabling a y axis and
it's just a chore.
But in portal two, watch what happens.
>> You will here a buzzer.
When you hear the buzzer,
look up at the ceiling.
[SOUND] Good.
You will hear a buzzer.
When you hear the buzzer,
look down at the floor.
[SOUND] Good.
This completes the gymnastic portion
of your mandatory physical and
mental wellness exercise.
>> Did you see that?
It was so subtle you might
not have even noticed it.
A character in the game
asked me to look up.
The game assumed whichever
direction I pressed
was the way I would want to
press when I want to look up.
And set my preference accordingly.
No option screen, no changing settings.
The game automatically and
invisibly had me complete my goal of
correctly setting my camera preference.