For this design challenge, let's
tackle one of the most common problems
addressed in undergraduate HCI classes,
designing a better remote control.
Now, these probably aren't
very good interfaces.
And that's not to say that
they're poorly designed, but
the constraints on how many
different things they have to do and
how limiting the physical structure
can be, make these difficult to use.
You might have seen humorous
images online of people putting
tape over certain buttons on the
controls to make them easier to use for
their parents or their kids.
How would we design an invisible
interface for universal remote control,
one that doesn't have the learning
curves that these have?