Personally I think this is a great
candidate for a voice interface.
And in fact, Comcast,
Amazon and others have
already started experimenting with
voice interfaces for remote controls.
One of the challenges with voice
interfaces is that generally
the commands aren't very discoverable.
Generally, if you don't know what you
can say, you have no way of finding out.
But watching TV and movies is such a
normal part of our conversations that we
already have a vocabulary of
how to say what we want to do.
The challenge is for
us designers to make a system that
can understand that vocabulary.
That way when I say, watch Community, it
understands that Community is a TV show
and it tries to figure out,
do I grab it from the DVR,
do I grab it from On Demand,
do I see if it's on live?
The vocabulary for
the user was very natural.
So for example, watch Conan.
>> Well tonight, a fan named
David Joiner thinks he caught a mistake.
He says it happened when I was telling
a joke recently about Rand Paul.
>> Hey Conan, I was watching
your episode on April 17th, and
you said that Rand Paul
wanted to run for president.
>> I had to put that in there somewhere.