Today, we've talked about
two applications of effective feedback cycles:
direct manipulation and invisible interfaces.
We talked about how interfaces are most effective when the user has
a sense that they're directly manipulating the object and their tasks.
We talked about how modern technology like touchscreens and
virtual reality are making it possible for manipulation to feel more and more direct.
We talked about how the most effective interfaces
become invisible between the user and their task.
Since the user it spends no time at all thinking about the interface.
We talked about interfaces can become invisible via either learning,
or design and are most interested in designing them to become invisible.
To a large extent, that's the definition of usable design,
designing interfaces that disappear between the user and their task.