[MUSIC]
Human computer interaction
starts with human.
So it's important that we
understand who the human is, and
what they're capable of doing.
In this lesson, we're going to bring up
some psychology of what humans can do.
We'll look at three systems.
Input, processing, and output.
Input is how stimuli are sent from the
world, and perceived inside the mind.
Processing is cognition,
how the brain stores, and
reasons over the input it's received.
Output is how the brain then
controls the individual's actions
out in the world.
Now, we're going to cover a lot
of material at a very high level.
If you're interested in hearing more,
I recommend taking a psychology class,
especially one focusing on sensation and
perception.
We'll put some recommended
courses in the notes.