In discussing human abilities,
we're going to adopt something similar
to the processor view of the human.
For now we're interested
in what they can do,
physically, cognitively, and so on.
So we're going to focus exclusively
on what's going on over here.
We're going to look at how
the person makes sense of input, and
how they then act in the world.
And right now, we're not going to worry
too much about where that input came
from, or what their actions
in the world actually do.
Notice that in this lesson we're
discussing the human, almost the same
way we discuss the computer, or
the interface, in most lessons.
The human is something
that produces output and
consumes input,
just like a computer might be otherwise.
But for now, we're only interested
in how the human does this.