Let's start by talking a bit about
what the average person can sense and
perceive.
So, here we have Morgan again.
Morgan has eyes.
Morgan's eyes are useful for
a lot of things.
The center of Morgan's eye is most
useful for focusing closely on color or
tracking movement.
So, we can assume that the most
important details should be placed in
the center of her view.
Morgan's peripheral vision is good for
detecting motion, but
it isn't as good for
detecting color or detail.
So while we might use her periphery for
some alerts,
we shouldn't require her to focus
closely on anything out there.
As a woman,
Morgan is unlikely to be colorblind,
she has about a 1 in 200 chance.
Men have a much greater prevalence
of color blindness at about 1 in 12.
Either way,
that's a significant body of people.
So we want to avoid relying on
color to understand the interface.
We can use it to emphasize knowledge
that it's already present in the system,
but using the system shouldn't
rely on perceiving color.
Sight is directional.
If Morgan's looking the wrong way or
has her eyes closed,
she'll miss visual feedback.
As Morgan gets older,
her visual acuity will decrease.
So if we're designing something
with older audiences in mind,
we want to be careful of
things like font size.
Ideally, these would be adjustable to
meet the needs of multiple audiences.
All together though,
Morgan's visual system is hugely
important to her cognition.
The majority of concepts we cover in
HCI are likely connected to visual
perception.
[SOUND]