Morgan also has ears.
Morgan can discern noises based on
both their pitch and their loudness.
Her ears are remarkably good
at localizing sound as well.
In fact, she can tell the difference
between a nearby quiet sound and
a far away loud sound.
Even if their relative pitches and
loudnesses are the same
when they reach her ear.
Unlike vision,
hearing isn't directional.
Morgan can't close her ears or
point her ears the wrong direction so
she can't as easily filter
out auditory information.
That might be useful for designing
alerts, but it's problematic for
overwhelming her or sharing too much
information with the people around her.