Morgan's skin can feel things.
It can't feel at a distance but
it can feel when things
are touching right up against it.
It can feel a variety of different
types of input, like pressure,
vibration and temperature.
Like listening, Morgan can't
easily filter out touch feedback.
But unlike listening, touch feedback is
generally only available to the person
it's touching, so it can be used
to create more personal feedback.
Traditionally, touch feedback, or
haptic feedback, has been very natural.
Morgan feels the keys go down
as she presses them on keyboard.
But with touchscreens, motion controls
and virtual reality, touch needs to
be more and more designed explicitly
into the system if we're to use it.