Here's one possible design.
We know that smartphones have
cameras and light sensors on them.
We can use that to determine
where the phone is,
and what kind of alert
it should trigger.
If the sensor detects light, that means
the screen is visible, so it might alert
her simply by flashing its flashlight or
illuminating the screen.
If the sensor does not detect light,
it would infer that the phone is in her
pocket and thus, would vibrate instead.
Now, of course, this isn't perfect.
It could be in her purse, or
she could have put it face down.
That's why we iterate
on a design like this,
to improve it based on
the user's experiences.