After the perception portion of this
model comes the cognition portion,
starting with memory.
There are lots of different
models of memory out there.
For our purposes we're going to talk
about three different kinds of memory,
the perceptual store or working memory,
the short-term memory, and
the long term memory.
Some scientists argue that there
are other types of memory as well,
like an intermediate sort
of back of the mind memory.
But the greatest consensus is around the
existence of at least these three kinds.
So let's start with the first, the
perceptual store or the working memory.
The perceptual store is a very short
term memory lasting less than a second.
One of the most common models of
working memory came from Baddeley and
Hitch in 1974.
They described it as having three parts.
First, there's the visuospatial
sketchpad which holds visual information
for active manipulation.
So for example, picture a pencil.
The visuospatial sketchpad is where
you're currently seeing that pencil.
A second part is the phonological loop.
The phonological loop is similar, but
for verbal or auditory information.
It stores the sounds or
speech you've heard recently,
such as the sound of me
talking to you right now.
A third part is the episodic buffer.
The episodic buffer takes care of
integrating information from the other
systems as well as chronological
ordering to put things in place.
Finally all three of these
are coordinated by a central executive.
So let's try an example of this.
I'm going to very quickly show you a
picture and ask you a question about it.
Don't focus on any particular portion of
the picture, try to view it as a whole.
What was the score on the scoreboard?