As you can now see,
the score was 0 to 0.
Now, as you tried to reason over that,
what you probably did was
picture the image in your mind.
That was trying to reason over what was
stored in the perceptual buffer, and
it decayed very quickly.
However, if you're a fan of baseball,
you probably had a better
chance of getting that right.
That's because you have
some domain expertise.
You're better able to process images
about that domain more quickly.
You might, for example, have recognized
that most of the innings weren't marked.
So that increases the odds that
the score of the game was pretty low.
This idea is actually the foundation of
a fascinating study about chess experts
versus novices and recognizing
the configuration of chess boards.
The study found that experts were far
better than novices at remembering
realistic chess boards that were only
flashed for a short period of time,
like the one on the left.
But experts were no better than novices
at remembering random chessboards.
So expertise, or rehearsal, delays
the decay of the perceptual buffer.