When we're designing interfaces,
short-term memory is one
of our biggest concerns.
It's important we avoid requiring
the user to keep too much stored in
short-term memory at a time.
Current research shows that users can
really only store four to five chunks
of information at a time.
For a long time, there was a popular
idea that people could store seven,
plus or minus two,
items in memory at a time.
But more recent research suggests that
the number is really four to five
chunks.
There are two principals we need
to keep in mind here though.
The first, is the idea of chunking.
Chunking is grouping together
several bits of information into
one chunk to remember.
So to illustrate this, let's try it out.
I'm about to show you six
combinations of letters.
Try to memorize them and then enter
them into the exercise that pops up.
Are you ready?
Now to keep you from just rehearsing it
in your perceptual store until you can
reenter it, I'm going to stall and
show you some pictures of my cats.
There's one.
There's both of them,
and here's my daughter.
Okay, now fill in the words.