So what happened?
Well, what likely happened is
that you maybe had only a little
bit of trouble remembering the two real
words that were listed on the right.
You might have had some more trouble
remembering the two words that were
listed in the middle
that were fake words, but
did nonetheless look like real words.
And you probably had a lot of trouble
remembering the two series of letters
over on the left.
Why is all of that?
Well, when it came to
memorizing these two words,
you were just calling up a chunk
that you've already had.
You didn't see these as arbitrary
collections of letters,
you just saw them as words.
For the ones in the middle, you've never
seen those combinations of letters
before, but you could pronounce
them as if they were words.
So you likely saw them as
fake words rather than just
random collection of letters.
For these over the left though, you had
to memorize five individual characters.
So that's means that while these four
were able to jump in the words or
pseudo words.
These likely had to be
remembered as five chunks each.
That's makes this much more
difficult to remember than these.