So what are the implications
of short term memory for HCI?
We don't want to ask the user to
hold too much in memory at a time,
four to five chunks is all.
Asking the user to hold ten numbers
in short term memory, for example,
would probably be too much.
But we can increase the user's effective
short term memory capacity by helping
them chunk things.
For example, this is probably
by far easier to remember,
even though it's the same content.
We've shrunk ten items into three.
And we've used a format for
phone numbers with which you're probably
familiar if you're in the United States.
If you're from outside the U.S.,
you might be familiar with
a different grouping.
But the same principle applies.
And finally, when possible, we should
leverage recognition over recall.
For example, if I ask you to recite
the number, maybe you could.
In fact, go ahead.
Try it.
Whether or not you could do that,
you almost certainly, though,
can pick it from this list.
This is one of the reasons why
menu bars and tool strips are so
ubiquitous in software design.
The user doesn't have to remember
the icon for a command or
the name of an option.
They just have to recognize
it when they see it.