Finally, we have long-term memory.
Long-term memory is a seemingly
unlimited store of memories, but
it's harder to put something
into long-term memory,
than to put it into short-term memory.
In fact,
to load something into long-term memory,
you generally need to put it into
short-term memory several times.
To demonstrate this,
I'm going to describe something
called lightner system.
The lightner system is a way
of memorizing key value pairs,
or in other words memorizing flashcards.
Those can be words and
their definitions, countries and
their capitals, laws and their formulas,
anything where you're given a key and
asked to return a value.
So I have some flashcards here that
have the capitals of the world.
What I do is go through each one,
read the country,
check to see if I remember the capital.
And if I do,
I'll put it in the pile on the right.
I read the country and
don't know the capital,
I'll put it in the pile on the left.
So let me do that real quick.
[MUSIC]
Now tomorrow, I will just go
through the pile on the left.
Any that I remember from
the pile on the left tomorrow,
I'll move to the pile on the right.
Any that I still don't remember,
will stay in the pile on the left.
So I'm focusing my attention on
those that I don't yet know.
In four days,
I'll go through the pile on the right.
And any that I don't remember then,
I'll move back to my pile on the left,
to remind me to go
through them each day.
So the things that I remember least,
are most often loaded in the short-term
memory, solidifying them
in my long-term memory.
Now in practice, you wouldn't just do
this with two piles, you'd do a three,
or four, or five.
And the long restoration pile you'd
might only go through yearly,
just to see if it's decayed yet.