Now let's talk a little bit about cognition.
One of the most important cognitive processes to consider is learning.
When we design interfaces,
we are in some ways hoping the user has to learn
as little as possible to find the interface useful.
However, our interfaces should also teach
the user over time how to use them most efficiently.
We can take PowerPoint as an example of this.
Let's pretend this is the first time I've ever used
PowerPoint and I want to copy something.
This application doesn't assume I know anything yet.
If I poke around, I'll find the Copy button under
the Edit menu which is off-screen above the slide.
When I bring up that menu,
it also shows the hotkey that will allow me to actually copy something.
That's helping me learn to interact with the application
more efficiently through hotkeys instead of through menus.
But yet it's also not assuming that I already knew
that because I was still able to find this under that menu.
There are two kinds of learning we're most interested in: procedural and declarative.
Procedural is how to do something.
That could be doing work on the computer,
playing sports, playing a musical instrument.
It's a task in which you're engaged or an activity you're performing.
It's something that you do.
Declarative learning is knowledge about something.
It's what you know in your head.
It's what you can answer when asked.
So, if I asked you,
what's the hotkey for paste?
I'm asking for a declarative knowledge.
If I asked you, paste your clipboard here,
I'm asking for procedural knowledge.
If you're an expert computer user,
you'd probably find it easier to just actually paste
your clipboard than to answer me when I say what's the hotkey for paste.
In all likelihood, when I ask you what's the hotkey for paste,
the way you remember it is you mentally simulate
doing it and then you look at what you simulated yourself doing.
What's interesting is that while a declarative knowledge is
how we generally communicate with one another,
procedural knowledge is generally what we do in HCI.
When you have strong procedural knowledge,
you may forget how you're doing what you're doing because it's so second nature.
You're unconsciously competent with what you're doing.
When you're in that state, it can be difficult to explain to someone who lacks
that competence because you aren't sure what makes you so good at it.
It's difficult to translate
your subconscious procedural knowledge into explicit declarative knowledge.
But declarative knowledge is how we communicate.
That's how we communicate with novice users.
This is important because as the designers of interfaces,
we're the experts in our domains.
That means we're prone to designing things that are easy for
us to use but hard for anyone else.