To talk about cognitive load,
let's think for
a moment of the brain
like it's a computer.
The community is actually
divided on whether or
not the brain actually
operates this way, but for
the purposes of this explanation,
it's a useful metaphor.
So your brain has a certain number of
resources available to it, the same way
your computer has a certain number of
processor resources available to it.
Each thing that the brain is working
on takes up some of those resources.
Let's say your at home in a quiet area,
working on a calculus problem that
requires 60% of your
cognitive resources.
In that setting, you have plenty of
resources to solve that problem.
However, then you go to
take a calculus test.
Now you have some stress in there.
Now you're stressing
about the impact this
test is going to have on your grade.
You're stressing about how well
other people seem to think they
are doing on it.
Whether or not other people seem to
be struggling while you struggle.
This is taking up a lot of
your cognitive resources.
Here we see the stress taking up 50%
of the cognitive resources you have.
Now you don't have sufficient resources
to complete the problem successfully.
I hypothesize that's why test taking
anxiety can have such a negative effect.
It takes resources away from
actually working on the test.
You can apply these same principles
to the presence of distractions,
anxiety disorders and more.
Cognitive load has two major
applications to our working design
interfaces.
One, we want to reduce the cognitive
load posed by the interface, so
that the user can focus on the task.
Second, we want to understand the
context of what else is going on while
users are using our interface.
We need to understand what
else is competing for
the cognitive resources users
need to use our interface.
If we're designing a GPS or
navigation system for
example, we want to be aware that
the user will have relatively
few cognitive resources because they're
focusing on so many things at once.