Computer programming is one task with
an incredibly high cognitive load.
At any given time, you're likely holding
in working memory your goals for
this line of code, your goals for this
function, your goals for this portion of
the program as a whole, the variables
you've created and a lot more.
That's why there's so many jokes about
how bad it is to interrupt a programmer,
because they have so
much in working memory that they lose
when they transition to another task.
But there are ways good IDEs
can help mitigate those issues.
For example, inline automated error
checking is one way to reduce
the cognitive load on programmers,
because it lets them focus more on
what they're trying to accomplish rather
than the low level syntax mistakes.
In that way, the IDE offloads some
of the responsibility from the user
to the interface.
Now we could phrase that
a little bit differently too.
We could describe this as distributing
the cognitive load more evenly between
the different components of the system,
myself and the computer.
That's a perspective we discuss when
we talk about distributed cognition.