So, now you know what we're going to cover in our exploration of HCI.
We're going to talk about some of the fundamental design principles
that HCI researchers have discovered over the years.
We're going to talk about performing user research whether it'll
be for new interfaces or exploring human cognition.
We're going to talk about the relationship between these two,
how our research informs what we design,
and how what we design helps us conducted research,
and we're going to talk about how these principles work,
in a lot of domains from technologies
like augmented reality to disciplines like healthcare.
I hope you're excited. I know I am.
I like to think of this not just as a course about human-computer interaction,
but also an example of human computer interaction.
Humans are using computers in new and engaging
ways to teach about human-computer interaction.
We hope this course exemplifies the principles,
as well as teaches them.