Here are five quick tips for reducing cognitive load in your interfaces.
Number one: Use multiple modalities.
Most often, that's going to be both visual and verbal,
but when only one system is engaged,
it's natural for it to become overloaded while the other one becomes
board so describe things verbally and also present them visually.
Number two: Let the modalities complement each other.
Some people will take that first step and use it as
justification to present different content in the two modalities.
That actually increases cognitive load because
the user has to try two process two things at once.
As you just noticed, when Amanda put something irrelevant up while I said that.
Instead, focus on letting each modality support,
Illustrate, or explain the other instead of competing with the other.
Number three: Give the user control of the pace.
That's more pertinent in educational applications of cognitive load, but oftentimes,
interfaces have built-in timers on things
like menus disappearing or selections needing to
be made that dictates the pace induce a stress and raises cognitive load.
Instead, let the user control the pace.
Number four: Emphasize essential content and minimize clutter.
The principle of discoverability says we want the user
to be able to find the functions available to them.
But that could also raise cognitive load if we
just give users a list of 500 different options.
To alleviate that we can design our interfaces in a way that emphasizes
the most common actions while still giving access to the full range of possible options.
Number five: Offload tasks.
Look closely at what the user has to do or remember at every stage of
the interfaces operation and ask if you can offload part of that task onto the interface.
For example, if a user needs to remember
something that they entered on a previous screen,
show them what they entered.
If there's a task that need to do manually,
see if you can trigger it automatically.