So our user has received some input.
It's entered her memory,
she cognitively processed it.
Now it's time to act in
the world in response.
In designing interfaces,
we're also interested in what is
physically possible for users to do.
This includes things like,
how fast they can move, or how precisely
they can click or tap on something.
For example, here are two versions of
the Spotify control widget that appears
on Android phones.
On the left is the version that's
available in the tray of the phone that
you can access at any given time by
swiping down on the phone screen.
And on the right is the version that
appears on the lock screen when you turn
on a locked phone while
it's playing music.
In each case, the X closes the app,
which is consistent with
a lot of other applications.
The forward,
back and pause buttons are similarly
consistent with their usual meanings.
I don't actually know what
the plus sign here does.
It's doesn't have a clear mapping
to some underlying function.
Now note on the left, we have the close
button, in the top right corner.
It's far away from anything
else in the widget.
On the right, the close button
is right beside the skip button.
I can speak from considerable
personal experience, and
say that the level of specificity or
the level of precision required to tap
that X, instead of tapping the skip
button, is pretty significant.
Especially if you're using this
while running or driving, or
anything besides just sitting there,
interacting directly with your phone.
The precision of the user's
ability to tap on a button is
significantly reduced
in those situations.
And in this case, that can lead to the
quick error of closing the application
when all you're trying to do is
skip forward to the next song.
This isn't an error in
the perception of the screen.
It's not an error in their
memory of the controls.
They're not thinking that the X
button actually is the skip button.
This is just an error in what they're
physically able to perform at
a given time.
The interface relies on more precision
than they would have in many
circumstances.
So this design doesn't take into
consideration the motor system
of the user or the full context
surrounding usage of this application.
This isn't as significant
in the design on the left,
because there's more room
around that close button.
If I aim for the forward button and
miss, the worst that's going to
happen is I might pause it.
I'm not going to close it by accident.
This is one example of how we need to be
aware of the constraints on the user's
motor system.
What they can physically do, how precise
or accurate they can be, and so on.
And we have to be aware of that in
the context where the application is
going to be used as well.
These buttons are no smaller than
the keys on a smart phone keyboard but
we expect more specificity when they're
sitting there typing with their thumbs,
as opposed to reaching over and
interacting real quick on
something on the lock screen.
Now of course, there might be
other constraints around this.
There might be a reason why
this button's placed there.
There might be some constraint in the
Android system that doesn't let them use
more than one row of the lock screen.
In that case, we would need to make
our interface more tolerant of errors.
Maybe require a double
tap to close the app, or
maybe we mute it when it's pressed and
then gives the user five seconds to
confirm that that's actually
what they want to do.
Those are ways of reducing
the penalty for errors.