We've talked a lot about different human abilities in this lesson.
Depending on the domain you chose,
the human abilities in which you're interested may vary dramatically.
If you're looking at gestural interfaces or wearable devices,
then the limitations of the human motor system might be very important.
On the other hand, if you're interested in educational technology,
you are likely more interested in some of
the cognitive issues surrounding designing technology.
For virtual reality, your main concern would likely be perception.
Although, there are interesting open questions about how we
physically interact with virtual reality as well.
So, take a few moments and reflect on what the limitations of
human ability are in the domain of HCI that you chose to explore.