Today we've gone through a crash course on human abilities and perception.
We started off by talking about the main ways people
perceive the world around them through sight, sound, and touch.
Then we discussed some of the components of cognition especially memory, and learning.
Then we discussed the motor system,
how the person then interacts with the world around them.
In this single lesson, we've only scratched the surface of human perception.
There are entire courses,
even entire degree programs that focus on these principles.
We'll give you some suggestions on some in the notes.
So, don't think we've given you a full view of the field.
Instead, we hope we've given you just enough to start to keep human abilities in mind,
and enough to know what to research as you start to learn to design interfaces.