In this lesson, we're going to talk about four sets of design principles.
These aren't the only four sets but are the ones that I see referenced most often,
and we'll talk about what some of the others might be at the end of the lesson.
In his book, "The Design of Everyday Things",
Don Norman outlined his famous six design principles.
This is probably the most famous set of design principles out there.
The more recent versions of the book actually have a seventh principle.
But that seventh principle was actually one of our entire lessons.
Jakob Nielsen outlines 10 design heuristics in his book, "Usability Inspection Methods".
Many of Norman's principles are similar to Nielsen's,
but there's some unique ones as well.
What's interesting is Norman and Nielsen went
into business together and form the Nielsen Norman Group,
which is for user experience, training,
consulting in HCI research.
In their books, "Software for Use",
Larry Constantine and Lucy Lockwood outline an additional six principles.
Again, many of them overlap with these two,
but some of them are unique.
Finally, Ronald Mace of
North Carolina State University proposed seven principles of universal design.
The Center for Excellence in universal design,
whose mobile site is presented here,
has continued research into this area.
These are a little bit different than
the heuristics and principles presented in the other three.
While these three are most concerned with usability in general,
universal design is specifically concerned with designing
interfaces and devices that can be used by everyone regardless of age,
disability, and so on.
To make this lesson a little easier to follow,
I've tried to merge these four sets of principles into one larger set,
capturing the overlap between many of them.
In this lesson, we'll go through these 15 principles.
These principles are intended to distill out
some of the overlap between those different sets.
This table shows those 15 principles.
My names for each of them,
and which sets that come from.
Note that my 15 principles are
just an abstraction or summary of these sets of principles,
and you should make sure to understand the sets themselves as well.
There are some subtle differences between
the principles I've grouped together from different sets,
and we'll talk about those as we go forward.
Again, note that these aren't the only four sets of design principles out there.
At the end of the lesson, we'll chat about a few more,
and we'll also mention when others apply within this lesson as well.