There often exists a tension between
discoverability and simplicity.
On the one hand, discoverability means
you need to be able to find things.
But how can you find them if
they're not accessible or visible?
That's how you get interfaces like
this with way too many things visible.
And ironically as a result, it actually
becomes harder to find what you're
looking for because there's so many
different things you have to look at.
This is where the principle
of simplicity comes in.
Simplicity is part of three
of our sets of principles,
Nielsen's, Constantine and Lockwood's,
and the universal design principles.
Nielsen writes specifically
about dialogues.
He says that the dialogues should not
contain information which is irrelevant
or rarely needed.
Every extra unit of information competes
with the relevant units of information,
and diminishes their
relative visibility,
which we see with all those
toolbars Constantine and
Lockwood establishes as
their simplicity principle.
They say the design should
make simple common tasks easy.
Communicating clearly and
simply in the user's own language and
providing good shortcuts.
Universal design is concerned
with simplicity as well.
Their principle of simple and intuitive
use advocates the use of design
easy to understand regardless
of the user's experience,
knowledge, language skills, or
current concentration level.
And in this principle you can see
universal design's special concern with
appealing to users of a variety of
different levels of expertise, ages,
disabilities, and so on.
Now in some ways, these principles
are about designing interfaces but
they cover other elements as well.
One example of this is
the infamous blue screen of death
from the Windows operating systems.
On the left we have the blue screen
of death as it appeared in older
versions of Windows.
And on the right we have how
it appears now on Windows 10.
There are a lot of changes here.
The blue is softer and more appealing.
The description of the error
is in plain language.
But the same information is still
provided, it's just de-emphasized.
This is a nice application
of Nielsen's heuristic.
The user should only be given as
much information as they need.
Here, the information that
most users would need,
which is just that
a problem occurred and
here's how close I am to recovering
from it, are presented more prominently
than the detailed information that
might only be useful to an expert.
Another interesting application of
simplicity in action came when New York
tried to create simpler signs to
represent its allowed parking schedule.
Navigating the sign on the left
is pretty much impossible.
But it's pretty easy to
interpret the one on the right.
The universal design principle
of simplicity is particularly
interested in whether or
not people of different experiences,
levels of knowledge, or
languages can figure out what to do.
Navigating this sign requires
a lot of cognitive attention and
some language skills.
Whereas I would hypothesize that even
someone who struggles with English
might be able to make sense
oft the sign on the right.
These two signs communicate
the same information, but
while the one on the left requires a lot
of cognitive load and language skills,
the one on the right can probably be
understood with little effort and
little experience.