[MUSIC]
Now that you understand a little bit
about what human-computer interaction
is, let's talk about what this
class is going to be like.
In this lesson, I am going to take
you through a high level overview
of this class.
What material we'll cover,
how it fits together, and
what you should expect to know
by the end of the course.
I'll also talk a little bit about the
assessments we'll use in the class, but
be aware, these assessments are only
applicable to students taking this class
through Georgia Tech.
If you're watching this course on your
own or taking it to complement other
courses you're taking, those
assessments won't apply to you, but
you'll get to hear a little bit about
what students in the actual course do.
If you are a student in the course,
you should know the assessments do tend
to change a bit semester to semester.
I'm going to try and stay as general as
possible to capture future changes, but
make sure to pay attention to the
specific materials you're provided for
your semester.