One way to keep design both simple and usable is to
design interfaces that by their very design tell you how to use them.
Don Norman described these as affordances.
The design of the thing affords or hints at the way it's supposed to be used.
This is also similar to the familiarity principle from Dix et al.
This is extremely common in the physical world because
the physical design of objects is connected to the physical function that they serve.
Buttons are meant to be pressed,
handles are meant to be pulled,
knobs are meant to be turned.
You can simply look at it and understand how you're supposed to use it.
Our next principle is the principle of affordances.
Norman writes, "An affordance is the relationship between the properties of an object and
the capabilities of the agent that determine just how the object could possibly be used.
In other words, an object with an affordance,
basically tells the user by its very design,
how it's meant to be used."
I use a door handle as the icon for this,
because the door handle is a great example of an affordance.
You can look at it and understand that you're
probably supposed to pull it down or push it up.
The very design of it,
tells you how you're supposed to use it.
Norman goes on to say that,
"The presence of an affordance is jointly determined by
the qualities of the object and the abilities of the agent that is interacting".
In other words, an affordance for one person isn't an affordance for everyone.
If you didn't grow up around door handles,
then maybe that door handle doesn't have an affordance
for you the way it would for someone who grew up around that.
Our affordances are defined by who the user is.
The challenge is that in the virtual computer world,
there's no such inherent connection between
the physical design and the function of an interface,
the way you might often find in the real world.
For example, when I mouse over a button in my interface,
the style that appears around it makes it look like it's elevated.
It makes it look like it's popping out of the interface.
That affords the action of then pushing it down,
and I know that I need to click it to push it down.
When I click it, it depresses. It gets darker.
It looks like it's sunk into the interface.
So, here we've manually created an affordance that would exist in the real world.
The design of this button hints at how it's supposed to be used.
It hints at the fact that it's supposed to be pressed.
So, we have to create that naturalness manually.
We can do that in a number of different ways.
We could, for example, visualize the space of options.
Here this color picture does a good job of this.
The horizontal line, it actually shows us the list of options available to us.
The placement of the dial suggest where we are now,
and there's this kind of implicit notion that I could
drag the style around to change my color.
We can also leverage metaphors or analogies of physical devices.
You can imagine that as this content was presented like a book,
I might scroll through it by flicking to the side, as if it's a page.
You may have seen interfaces that work exactly like that.
There's no computational reason why
that should mean go to the next page or that should mean go back a page,
except that it makes sense in the context of the physical interface it's meant to mimic.
We swipe in a book,
so let's swipe in a book like interface.
Of course, there are also actions in the virtual world that have no real-world analogy,
like pulling up a menu on a mobile site.
In that case, we might use signifiers.
Signifiers are a principle in Norman's more recent additions.
Signifiers are in-context instructions
like arrows to indicate which way to swipe for a particular action,
or in this case, a button labeled menu to indicate how to pull up a menu.
In this way, we can kind of create
our own affordances by creating an intuitive mapping between
controls and their effects in the world
being consistent with what others have done in the past.