It's important to note that the language with which we talk about
affordances is famously somewhat imprecise.
Norman's technical definitions of
affordances are a little different than what we've used here.
Affordances to Norman are actually inherent properties of the device.
For example, a door bar like this one has
the inherent property that the handle moves into the crossbar and opens a latch.
That's the affordance, it's something that inherently does.
A perceived affordance is a property attributed to the object by a human observer.
This could be a subtle difference.
Here, the perceived affordance would be pushability.
Pushing though is a human behavior.
So, pushability must be
a perceived affordance because it relies on someone to do the pushing.
What's important is that a perceived affordance can actually be inaccurate.
Norman famously complains when doors that are actually
meant to be pushed have a handle like this,
which looks like it's supposed to be pulled.
This is a place where a perceived affordance and an actual affordance are in conflict.
The user perceives that the store is meant to be pulled,
but the actual affordance is for it to be pushed,
or to be more precise,
the actual affordance is that the door opens inward based on these hinges.
A signifier then is anything that helps
the perceived affordance match the actual affordance.
For example, some doors like this will have
a block bar on the part that's supposed to be pushed.
That signifies to a user that this is a place they
should test out the interaction that they perceive to be possible.
On the store, we can put a sign that just says, Push.
That would be a signifier that tries to alleviate
the conflict between the actual affordance and the perceived affordance.
Now based on these definitions,
we can't add affordances.
Affordances are inherent in our system.
Instead, we can add signifiers that help
the perception of affordances match the actual affordances that are there.
With these technical definitions of these terms,
saying I added an affordance to the interface is like
saying I added tastiness to that dish or I added beauty to that painting.
Affordances, tastiness, beauty; these are
all things that arise as a result of adding signifiers,
or oregano, or some pretty shade of blue.
But in practice, these distinctions around this vocabulary are often disobeyed.
It's not uncommon to hear people say,
I added an affordance here,
so the user knows what they're supposed to do.
To me, there's really no harm in that.
The distinctions between these terms are very important when developing a theory of HCI.
But when you're doing day-to-day design,
we usually know what we're talking about when we misuse these terms.
So, I don't think there's any harm in being cavalier about how we use these terms,
but it is important to know
this distinction in case anyone ever brings up the difference.