A good example of the difference
between affordances and
mappings is a light switch.
A light switch very clearly affords
how you're supposed to use it.
You're supposed to flip it.
But these switches have no mapping to
what will happen when I switch them.
I can look at it and
clearly see what I'm supposed to do.
But I can't tell what the effect
is going to be in the real world.
Contrast with the dials on my stove.
There are four dials and
each is augmented with this little icon
that tells you which burner
is controlled by that dial.
So there's a mapping between
the controls and the effects.
So how would you redesign these light
switches to create not only affordances
but also mappings.
If relevant, this one turns
on the breakfast room light,
this one turns on the counter light and
this one turns on the kitchen light.