Consistency is a principle from Norman, Nielsen,
and Constantine and Lockwood that refers to using controls, using visualizations,
using layouts, using anything we use in our interface design consistently,
across both the interfaces that we design and what we design more broadly as a community.
Norman writes a consistency in design is virtuous.
It's a powerful word there.
It means that lessons learned with one system transfer readily to others.
If a new way of doing things is only slightly better than the old,
it's better to be consistent.
Of course, there'll be times when new ways of
doing things will be significantly better than the old,
and that's how we actually make progress. It's how we advance.
But if we're only making tiny little iterative improvements,
it might be better to stick with the old way of doing
things because users are used to it.
They're able to do it more efficiently.
Nielsen writes that users should not have to wonder whether different words,
situations or actions mean the same thing.
Follow platform conventions.
In other words, be consistent with what other people have done on the same platform,
in the same domain, and so on.
Constantine and Lockwood describe consistency as reuse.
They say the design should reuse internal and external components and behaviors,
maintaining consistency with purpose rather than merely arbitrary consistency.
Thus reducing the need for users to rethink and remember.
That means that we don't have to be consistent with things that don't
really impact what the user knows to do.
The color of the window, for example,
isn't going to change whether the user understand what
the word copy means in the context of an interface.
But changing the word copy to duplicate might force
users to actually rethink and remember what that term means.
In some cases, that might be a good thing if duplicate
actually does something slightly different than copy,
then changing that would force our users to
understand that they're doing something different.
But if we're doing the same thing,
it's important to maintain consistency so the user doesn't have to think as
much and can focus on the task at hand instead of on our interface.
The general idea across all of these is we should be consistent both within and across
interfaces to minimize the amount of
learning the user needs to do to learn our interface.
In this way, we create affordances on our own.
Unlike traditional physical affordances,
there's no physical reason for the interface to be designed a certain way.
But by convention, we create expectations for
users and then fulfill those expectations consistently.
One great example of following
these conventions are the links we use in text on most websites.
For whatever reason, an early convention on
the Internet was for links to be blue and underlined.
Now when we want to indicate to users that some text is clickable, what do we do?
Generally, we might make it blue and underline it.
Sometimes we change this as you can see here.
Underlining has actually fallen out of fashion in a lot of places and now we
just use the distinct text color to indicate a link that can be clicked.
On some other sites, the color itself might be different.
It might be red against blue text instead of blue against black.
But the convention of using a contrasting color to mark links has remained,
and the most fundamental convention is still blue underlines.
Again there's no physical reason why links need to be
blue or why they even need to be a different text color at all.
But that convention helps users understand how to use our interfaces.
If you've used the Internet before and then visit Wikipedia for the first time,
you understand that these are links without even thinking about it.
Most of the interfaces we designed will have
a number of functions in common with other interfaces.
So, by leveraging the way things have been done in the past,
we can help users understand our interfaces more quickly.
Other common examples of consistency and interface design would include
things like using consistent hotkeys for things like copy,
paste and select all.
Ordering the Menus, File, Edit, View,
etc, putting options like save and open under File.
We don't even begin to think about these things when we're using
an interface until we encounter one that defies our conventions,
and yet someone has to consciously decide to be consistent with established norms.
This is an example of design becoming invisible.
When people do it right,
we don't notice they did it at all.
When people put those options in the right places,
we don't even think about it, but when people put them in the wrong places,
it's pretty jarring and startling.