One of my favorite examples of how consistency matters
comes from Microsoft's Visual Studio development environment.
To be clear, I adore Visual Studio,
so I'm not just piling onto it.
As you can see here, in most interfaces,
Ctrl+Y is the redo hotkey.
If you hit undo one too many times,
you can press Ctrl+Y to redo the last undone action.
But in Visual Studio,
by default it's Shift+ Alt + Backspace.
What? And what's worse than this is that Ctrl+Y is the delete line function,
which is a function I never even heard of before Visual Studio.
So, if you're pressing Ctrl+Z a bunch of times to
maybe rewind the changes you've made lately,
and then you press Ctrl+Y out of habit because
it's what every other interface uses for redo,
the effect is that you delete the current line instead of redoing anything,
and that actually makes a new change which means
you lose that entire tree of redoable actions.
Anything you've undone can now not be recovered.
It's infuriating and yet it isn't without its reasons and the reason is consistency.
Ctrl+Y was the hotkey for the delete line function in WordStar,
one of the very first word processors.
Before Ctrl+Y was the hotkey for the more general redo function,
there wasn't even a redo function back then.
I've heard that Y in this context stood for yank but I don't know how true that is.
But Ctrl+Y had been used to delete a line from
WordStar all the way through Visual Basic Six,
which was the predecessor to Visual Studio.
So, in designing Visual Studio,
Microsoft had a choice,
be consistent with the convention from
Word Star and Visual Basic Six or be
consistent with the convention that we're using in their other interfaces.
They chose to be consistent with the predecessors to Visual Studio,
and they've stayed consistent with that ever since.
So, in trying to maintain the consistency principle in one way,
they actually violated it in another way.
So, if you try to leverage the consistency principle,
you're going to encounter some challenges.
There may be multiple conflicting things with which you want to be consistent,
there may be questions about whether a certain change is worth the dropping consistency.
These are things to test with users which we
talked about in the other unit of this course.