In designing user interfaces,
our goal is typically to make the interface usable,
and a big part of usability is accounting for user error.
Many design theorists argue that there's actually no such thing as user error.
If the user commits an error,
it was because the system was not structured in a way to prevent or recover from it,
and I happen to agree with that.
Now, one way we can avoid error is by
preventing the user from performing erroneously in the first place.
This is the idea of constraints.
Constraining the user to only perform the correct actions in the first place.
On constraints, Norman writes that constraints are
powerful clues limiting the set of possible actions.
The thoughtful use of constraints in design lets people
readily determine the proper course of action,
even in a novel situation.
Remember, designing so that users are immediately comfortable in
novel situations is one of the goals of good user interface design.
Nielsen notes that even better than good error messages is
a careful design which prevents a problem from occurring in the first place.
Either eliminate error-prone conditions or check for them and
present users with a confirmation option before they commit to the action.
For example, if our application was prone to
users accidentally closing it when they don't mean to,
ask them when it's about to close if that's actually what they meant to do.
Both of these approaches refer to the need to
stop faulty user input before it's even received.
This is a principle you might already encountered a lot.
Our password reset screen actually does this pretty well.
First, it shows us the constraints under which we're operating right there
visibly on the screen so we're not left guessing as to what we're supposed to be doing.
Then as we start to interact,
it tells us if we're violating any of those constraints.
So, if I were to just try to make my password the incredibly common 1234,
it immediately tells me that my password isn't long
enough and it doesn't represent enough character classes.
Now, obviously, it can't prevent me from entering 1234 in the first place,
since maybe that's along the way to a longer more valid password.
But it's visualizing those constraints so that instead of submitting and
getting frustrated when it didn't tell me I
was doing it wrong until I'd actually done it,
it actually tells me right in the context of doing it I'm not on the right track.
This is kind of a soft constraint.
It doesn't prevent me from doing something,
but it tells me while I'm doing it that I'm doing it wrong.
A harder constraint goes along with that last bullet: can
only contain characters printed on the computer's keyboard.
Right now, I'm trying to paste in a character that isn't on the computer keyboard,
and it's just not showing it all together.
It's a hard constraint against the inputting characters that aren't allowed.
So, it's preventing me from putting an invalid input in the first place.
So, in their simplest form,
constraints can be described as preventing the user
from putting an input that wasn't going to work anyway.