Norman takes us a step further though,
when he breaks down constraints
into four sub-categories.
These aren't just about
preventing wrong input.
They're also about
insuring correct input.
They're about making sure
the user knows what to do next.
Physical constraints are those that are
literally physically prevent you from
performing the wrong action.
A three-prong plug, for
example, can only physically be inserted
in one way, which prevents mistakes.
USB sticks can only be physically
inserted one way all the way.
But the constraint doesn't arise
until you've already tried to do it
incorrectly.
You can look at a wall outlet and
understand if you're trying
to put it incorrectly.
But it's harder to look at a USB and
know whether you're trying
to insert it the right way.
A second kind is a cultural constraint.
These are those rules that are generally
followed by different societies,
like facing forward on escalators,
or forming a line while waiting.
In designing we might rely on these, but
we should be careful of
intercultural differences.
A third kind of constraint
is a semantic constraint.
Those are constraints that are inherent
to the meaning of a situation.
They're similar to
affordances in that regard.
For example, the purpose of a rear
view mirror is to see behind you.
So therefore, the mirror must reflect
from behind, it's inherent to the idea
of a rear view mirror,
that it should reflect in a certain way.
In the future that meaning might change,
autonomous vehicles might not
need mirrors for passengers, so
the semantic constraints of today,
might be gone tomorrow.
And finally the fourth kind of
constraint is a logical constraint.
Logical constraints are things that
are self-evident based on a situation,
not just based on the design of
something like a semantic constraint,
but based on the situation at hand.
For example,
imagine building some furniture.
When you reach the end, there's only
one hole left, and only one screw.
Logically, the one screw
left is constrained to go in
the one remaining hole.
That's a logical constraint.