A lot of the principles we talk about
are cases where you might never even
notice if they've been done well.
There are principles
of invisible design,
where succeeding allows the user
to focus on the underlying tasks.
But constraints are different.
Constraints actively stand
in the user's way and
that means they've become more visible.
That's often a bad thing, but
in the case of constraints
it serves the greater good.
Constraints might prevent users
from entering invalid input or
force users to adopt certain safeguards.
So of all the principles
we've discussed,
this might be the one you've noticed.
So take a second, and think.
Can you think of any times you've
encountered interfaces that had
constraints in them?