I have kind of an interesting
example of this.
I can't demonstrate it well because
the car has to be in motion, but
on my Leaf there's an option screen,
and it lets you change the time and
the date, and
some other options on the car.
And you can use that option screen
until the car starts moving.
But at that point,
the menu blocks you from using it,
saying you can only use it
when the car is at rest.
That's for safety reasons.
They don't want people fiddling with
the option screen while driving.
What makes it interesting,
though, is it's a constraint that
isn't in the service of usability,
it's in the service of safety.
The car is made less usable
to make it more safe.