Finally, Nielsen has one last heuristic
regarding user error, documentation.
I put this last for a reason,
one goal of usable design is to avoid
the need for documentation altogether.
We want users to just interact
naturally with our interfaces.
In modern design, we probably can't rely
on users reading our documentation at
all unless they're being required
to use our interface altogether.
And Nielsen generally agrees.
He writes that even though it's better
if the system can be used without
documentation, it may be necessary
to provide help and documentation.
Any such information should be easy
to search, focused on user's task,
list concrete steps to be carried out,
and not be too large.
I feel modern design as a whole has made
great strides in this direction over
the past several years.
Nowadays, most often,
when you use documentation online or
wherever you might find it,
it's framed in terms of tasks.
You input what you want to do, and
it gives you a concrete list of
steps to actually carry it out.
That's a refreshing change
compared to older documentation,
which was more dedicated to just listing
out everything a given interface could
do without any consideration to what
you were actually trying to do.