So, I've attempted to distill the 29 combined principles from Norman,
Nielsen, Constantine, Lockwood, and the Center for Universal Design into just these 15.
Here you can see where each of these principles comes from.
I do recommend reading the original four lists to pick up on some
of the more subtle differences between these principles that I've grouped together,
especially perceptibility, tolerance, and feedback.
Note also that in more recent editions,
Norman has one more principle: conceptual models.
That's actually the subject of an entire lesson in this course.
These also certainly aren't the only four sets of
design principles. There are several more.
For example, Dix, Finlay, Abowd,
and Beale proposed three categories of principles:
learnability for how easily a new user can grasp an interface,
flexibility for how many ways an interface can be used,
and robustness for how well an interface gives feedback and recovers from errors.
We talk about their learnability principles when we discussed mental models.
Jill Gerhardt-Powals has a list of principles for cognitive engineering,
aimed especially at reducing cognitive load.
Her list is in particularly useful applications for data processing and visualization.
In "The Human Interface",
Jef Raskin outline some additional revolutionary design rules.
I wouldn't necessarily advocate following them,
but they're interesting to see a very different approach to things.
In "Computer Graphics Principles and Practice",
Jim Foley and others give some principles that apply
specifically to 2D and 3D computer graphics.
Finally, Susan Weinschenk and Dean Barker have a set of guidelines that
provide an even more holistic view of interface design,
including things like linguistic and cultural sensitivity,
tempo and pace, and domain clarity.
Even these are only some of the additional lists.
There are many more that I encourage you to look into.
We'll provide some on the notes.