In this lesson, I've tried to take the various different lists of
usability guidelines from different sources
and distill them down to a list you can really work with.
We combine the lists from Don Norman,
from Jakob Nielsen, Larry Constantine,
Lucy Lockwood, and the institute for Universal Design into 15 principles.
Now remember, these are just guidelines, principles, and heuristics.
None of them are unbreakable rules.
You'll often find yourself wrestling with the tensions between multiple principles.
There will be something cool you'll want to implement but
only most expert users will be able to understand it,
or there might be some new interaction method you want to test
but you aren't sure how to make it visible or learnable to the user.
These principles are things you should think about when designing.
But they only get you so far.
You still do need finding, prototyping,
and evaluation to find out what actually works in reality.