[MUSIC]
Today we're going to talk about
mental models and representations.
A mental model is the understanding
you hold in your head about
the world around you.
Simulating a mental model allows
you to make predictions and
figure out how to achieve your
goals out in the real world.
A good interface will give the user
a good mental model of the system
that it presents.
In order to develop good medal models we
need to give users good representations
of the system with which
they're interacting.
In that way,
we can help users learn how to use our
interfaces as quickly as possible.
So that's what we'll talk about in this
lesson, creating representations that
help users develop accurate
mental models of our systems.
We'll start by talking about
mental models in general and
how they apply to the interfaces
with which we're familiar.
Then we'll talk about how
representations can make problem
solving easier or harder.
After that, we'll talk about how
metaphors and analogies can be useful
tools to create good representations
that lead to accurate mental models.
Then we'll discuss how user error can
arise either from inaccuracies or
mistakes in the user's mental model,
or just from accidental slips,
despite an accurate mental model.
Finally, we'll close by discussing
learned helplessness, one
of the repercussions of poor interface
design, as well as expert blindspot,
which is one of the reasons
why poor design can occur.