The first part of this learning outcome
to design needed some definition, but
the second part seems pretty
straightforward, right?
Not exactly.
Effectiveness is defined
in terms of our goal.
The most obvious goal here
might be usability and for
a lot of that's exactly
what we're interested in.
If I'm designing a new thermostat,
I want the user to be able to create the
outcome they want as easily as possible.
But maybe usability isn't my goal,
maybe it's research.
Maybe I'm interested in investigating
what makes people think that
the thermostat is working correctly.
In that case, I might deliberately
create some thermostats that are harder
to read, just to see how that changes
people's perceptions of the system.
Or it could be that my goal isn't to
make the certain activity easier but
rather to change that activity.
Maybe I'm interested in reducing
a home's carbon footprint.
In that case, my goal is to get
people to use less electricity.
I might design the interface of
the thermostat specifically to encourage
people to use less.
Maybe I'd show them a comparison
to their neighbor's usage, or
allow them to set energy usage goals.
Or I could make the thermostat
physically harder to turn up and down.
So effectiveness is very much determined
by the goal that I have in mind.
We'll generally assume that our goal is
usability, unless we state otherwise.
But we'll definitely talk about
some of those other goals as well.