For simple problems, identifying
a good representation can be easy.
But what about for
more complex problems?
For those problems,
we might need some examples of
what makes a good representation.
So let's try a complex example.
We'll use a problem with
which you might be familiar.
For now, I'll call it the circles and
squares problem.
On one side of a table,
I have three circles and three squares.
My goal is to move the three circles and
three squares to the other
side of the table.
I can only move two shapes at at time,
and the direction of the moves must
alternate, starting with
a move to the right.
The number of squares on either side can
never outnumber the number of circles
unless there are no circles
at all on that side.
How many moves does it
take to accomplish this?
Try it out and enter the number
of moves it takes in the box.
Or just skip if you give up.