Representations are all around
us in the real world, but
they play a huge role in interfaces.
Designing representations of the current
state of a system is actually one of
the most common tasks you might
perform as an interface designer.
So let's take a look at a few,
here's Google Calendar which is
a representation of my week.
Notice how it actually uses space
to represent blocks of time.
It allows me to quickly feel how long
different things are going to take.
An alternate visualization might show
an entire month instead of a week, but
it would lose those indicators that
linked the individual appointments.
So it doesn't really
represent the structure and
pace of my day,
the way the weekly calendar does.
This representation also allows me
to very easily find conflicts in my
schedule.
So I know when I might need
to reschedule something.
On Friday I can see that I have
a conflict for one of my meetings.
And this interface also
makes it easy to reschedule.
I can pull up the calendar for
the other person I'm meeting with and
identify places where we both
have free in our schedule.
Another example of this is
the PowerPoint animation pang.
The numbers here represent
when different animations
happen concurrently.
The middle icon represents what
triggers the animation, and
the right icon indicates the general
nature of the animation.
Whether it's a movement,
a highlight or an appearance.
The PC version of PowerPoint makes this
even better by actually showing you
a timeline of the different
animations to the right.
That lets you very easily visualize when
two different things are going to happen
at the same time.
Or when something waits for
something else to happen.
These are just two of the many many
representations you use whenever you
use a computer.
Scroll bars for
example, are representations of your
relative position in a document.
Highlighting markers like that rectangle
are representations of what you
currently have selected.
All these representations work together
to help your mental model match
the real state of the system.
Representations when used correctly
can make many tasks trivial, or
even invisible.
And we as interface designers
have a lot of control
over representations in our designs.