In our lesson on design principles,
we touch on a number of principles that
are relevant to these ideas of mental
models, representations, and metaphors.
First, the idea that people reason
by analogy to pass interfaces,
or by metaphors to the real world,
is one of the reasons that the principle
of consistency is so important.
We want to be consistent
with the analogies and
metaphors that people use to
make sense of our interfaces.
Second, when we say that an interface
should teach the user how the system
works, we're echoing
the idea of affordances.
The way the system looks,
should tell the user how it's used.
Just by observing the system the,
user should be learning
how to interact with it.
Third, representations are important
because they map the interphase,
to the task at hand.
A good representation is one that
users can use predict the outcomes
of certain actions.
In other words, a good representation
let's users predict the mapping
between their actions in the interphase,
and the outcomes out in the world.