The final part of our desired learning
outcome is between humans and computers.
We want to design effective interactions
between humans and computers.
Well, what is important to note here,
is where we're placing the emphasis.
Note that we didn't say
designing effective interfaces,
because that puts the entire
focus on the interface.
We're deeply interested in
the human's role in this interaction.
So rather than designing interfaces,
designing programs, designing tools,
we're designing interactions.
We're designing tasks.
We're designing how people
accomplish their goals,
not just the interface that they
use to accomplish their goals.
Take our thermostat for example.
When we started this process, our goal
shouldn't be to design a thermostat.
Our goal should be to design
the way in which a person controls
the temperature in their home.
That subtle shift in
emphasis is powerful.
If you set out to design
a better thermostat,
you might design a wall-mounted device
that's easier to read or easier to use.
But if you set to
design a better way for
people to control the temperature in
their home, you might end up with Nest.
A device that learns from the user and
starts to control
the temperature automatically.