Don Norman further divides slips
into two different categories.
He describes action-based slips and
memory lapse slips.
Action-based slips are places where
the user performs the wrong action, or
performs a right action
on the wrong object,
even though they knew
the correct action.
They might click the wrong button, or
right-click when they should left-click.
A memory lapse slip occurs when the user
forgets something they knew to do.
For example, they might forget
to start a timer on a microwave.
They knew what to do,
they just forgot about it.
So action-based slips
are doing the wrong thing, and
memory lapse slips are forgetting
to do the right thing.
In this dialog,
clicking No when you mean to click Yes
would be an example of
an action-based slip.
The very existence of this dialog is
meant to prevent a memory lapse slip,
where a user would forget to
save their work before closing.