When you're looking to
improve an interface,
user errors are powerful
places to start.
They're indicative either of weaknesses
in the user's mental model or
places where the system isn't capturing
the user's correct mental model.
So let's try to address
an error Morgan's encountering.
Morgan usually texts
with her boyfriend but
she texts with some other people too.
But she finds she's often sending
the wrong messages to the wrong people.
The app by default brings up
the last open conversation and
usually that's her boyfriend.
But sometimes it's someone else and
she accidentally messages them instead.
First, is this a slip or
is this a mistake?