The feedback cycle in HCI is reliant on a relationship
between the users input and the interface's output.
The idea of this cycle is that the user learns from
the output what they should have input.
If they do something that causes an error,
they receive feedback on how to avoid that next time.
If they do something correctly,
then they see that their goal was accomplished.
That's the principle of feedback.
But what happens when there's
no discernible interaction between the input and the output?
What happens when there's a break in this cycle?
What happens when the user acts in the system over and over and over again,
but never receives any output that actually helps?
What if they never even receive output that indicates that
the computer is understanding them or receiving input from them?
That's when something called learned helplessness sets in.
The human working with the interface
learns that they're helpless to actually use the system.
They learn that there is no mapping between their input and the output they receive.
As a result, they believe that there's
just nothing they can do to accomplish their goals.
No one wants to feel that way.
No one wants to feel like no matter what they do,
they are doomed to failure.
No one wants to feel like they're failing at
something that everyone else seems to do very easily.
So, it's very natural for people to develop
this resistance to even try and to learn about this interface.