In order for us to really sympathize
with users suffering from the effects of
learned helplessness and
expert blind spot, it's important for
us to understand what it's
like to be in that position.
We've all experienced these
things at some point in life,
although at the time, we might not
have understood what was happening.
So take a second and
reflect on a time when you
experienced learned helplessness and
the effects of expert blind spot from
someone trying to teach you something.
It might have been in a class, it might
be learning a new skill, or it might be
doing something that everyone else seems
to do just fine day to day, but for
whatever reason,
you've always struggled with.