The fact that I'm filming this in
the kitchen probably tells you where I
experience this.
Anything related to cooking,
I feel completely helpless.
I've given myself food poisoning
with undercooked meat lots of times,
I once forgot to put the cheese
on a grilled cheese sandwich.
I accidentally made toast, and
it wasn't even good toast.
And I've always heard, it's just so
easy, just follow the recipe, but
no, it's not that easy, because many
recipes are written for experts.
So for example,
here's a recipe from my wife's cookbook.
It calls for a medium saucepan.
Is this a medium saucepan?
I have no idea.
Calls for
one egg beaten with a splash of water.
A splash, like a splash when
you over fill a water bottle or
a splash when your sibling
soaks you at the pool?
Pulse to combine.
Cook until the edges are golden brown.
What's golden brown?
Give me a color code and
I'll compare it, but otherwise,
I don't know where on the spectrum from
golden to brown, golden brown lies.
These are examples of places where
the directions are given in a way that
assumes I already have some expertise,
that I really don't have.