When looking at human computer interaction,
we're really looking at the tasks that users perform.
We look at the tasks that they're performing now,
and we try to restructure those tasks to be more efficient using new interfaces.
In all of this, the task is at the heart of the exercise.
What task are they performing?
So today, we're going to talk about two methods for
formerly articulating the tasks that people are completing.
First, we'll discuss human information processor models.
Especially, the Goleman's model,
which focuses on the input to the user,
and the output from the user.
Now, this is similar to the process or model of the user that we discussed elsewhere.
Second, we'll discuss cognitive task analysis,
a way of trying to get inside the user's head,
instead of focusing just on the input and the output.
Note that that's similar to the predictor model
of the user that we also discussed elsewhere.