The GOMS model is a human
information processor model so
it builds off the processor model
of the human's role in a system.
The GOMS model gets it's name from
the four sets of information it
proposes gathering about a task.
G, stands for
the users Goals in the system.
O, stands for the Operators
the user can perform in the system.
M stands for the Methods that the user
can use to achieve those goals.
And S stands for the Selection rules
that the user uses to choose among
different competing methods.
So the GOMS Model proposes that
every human interact with the system
has a set of Goals that
they want to accomplish.
They have sent methods that they can
choose from to accomplish those goals.
Each of those methods is comprise of
a series of Operators that carries
out that method.
And they have some Selection rules
that help them decide what method to
use and when.
The GOMS model is often
visualized like this.
The user starts with some initial
situation, and they have a goal
in mind that they want to accomplish,
so they apply their selection of rule to
choice between different competing
methods to accomplish that goal.
Once they've chosen a method, they
execute that series of operators and
makes that goal a reality