We can take the GOMS model and apply
it to a number of different domains.
So let's take the example of needing
to communicate a message to a coworker.
We have an initial situation,
which is the need to transfer
information to a coworker.
That carries with it the implicit
goal of the information having been
transferred.
We might have a number of
different methods in mind for
how we could do that.
We could email them, we could walk
over and talk to them in person.
And we also have some selection
rules that dictate how we choose
amongst these methods.
If what we need to transfer is very
time-sensitive, maybe we walk over and
talk to them in person or
call them on the phone.
If the information we need
to transfer is complex and
detailed, maybe we write them an email.
Or if it's more casual,
maybe we chat with them or text them.
No matter what method we choose,
we then execute the series of operators
that carries out that method, and
the result is our goal is accomplished,
the information has been transmitted.
Or we could also take
the problem of navigation.
Our initial situation is the need
to get to our destination,
which carries with it the implicit goal
of having reached our destination.
We might have different methods,
like take the scenic route,
take the highway route, take the surface
streets, and some selection rules that
might say something like,
when it's rush hour on the highway,
take surface streets, or if it's not
time sensitive, take the scenic route.
After choosing, we execute those
operators and reach our goal.
So in this way,
GOMS models capture our goals,
our different methods for
carrying out those goals, and
the individual operators that
we use to execute those methods.