Here's one example of how you
might design a GOMS model for
disabling a security system.
Our initial situation is that we're
entering the home with the alarm set and
we have two methods for
disabling the alarm.
We can use the keypad or
we can use the keychain.
Either way, our goal is that
we've entered the home and
reenabled the alarm.
Our selection rules might be something
like if we have our hands full,
we're going to use the keypad so that we
can get inside and put the stuff down.
But if we don't have our hands full,
we'll use the keychain.
You might come up with other models for
this that have either different methods,
different operators,
different selection rules.
There are a lot of different ways we
can capture a task with the GOMS model,
depending on what you
choose to focus on.