There are strengths and weaknesses to the GOMS representation for tasks.
One weakness is that it doesn't automatically
address a lot of the complexity of these problems.
For example, there are likely many different methods
and submethods for addressing this goal.
Before even getting this selection rules among what route to take,
you might decide whether to take
public transportation or whether to work from home that day.
In parallel to that,
even after deciding to drive,
you might decide what car to take if your family has more than one car.
The standard GOMS model leaves those kind of things out,
although there are augmented versions that have been
created to deal with this kind of complexity
like CMN GOMS or in GOMS L. We'll talk about those a bit more later.
A second weakness is that the GOMS model assumes
the user already has these methods in mind,
that means the user is already an expert in the area.
GOMS models don't do a good job of accounting for novices or accounting for user errors.
For example, if you are driving in an unfamiliar location,
you don't even know what the methods are,
let alone how to choose among them.
The strength of GOMS models on the other hand is their ability to
formalize user interaction into steps that we can use to actually make predictions.
We can measure how long each these operators takes and so we
can predict the overall efficiency of using a certain interface.
For example, in this GOMS model if we had included
the operator to pull keys out of the users pocket,
we might quickly identify that the relative efficiency of
these two methods is very much dependent on how long that step takes.
The Key Chain method might be a lot faster
if the user can get their key chain out pretty quickly.
But for other users,
the fact that they need to pull something out of
their pocket while holding bags or holding a baby,
makes a keypad a more efficient option.
By performing that kind of reasoning,
we can focus on areas that either method and the interface as a whole can be improved.