There are several varieties of GOMS models.
These varieties share the commonality of goals, operators, methods,
and selection criteria, but they differ in what additional elements they provide.
Bonnie John and David Kieras cover four popular variations in a paper from 1996.
The first is the Vanilla GOMS we've talked about so far,
and the other three are KLM-GOMS, CMN-GOMS and NGOMSL.
Let's talk about what those acronyms actually mean.
They start with the Keystroke-Level Model,
which is the simplest technique.
Here, the designer simply specifies the operators and execution times
for an action and sums them to find the complexity of an interaction.
This method proposed six different types of operators,
although for moderate interfaces,
we would need some new ones to cover touchscreens and other novel interfaces.
A second variation is CMN-GOMS.
CMN-GOMS is an extension of GOMS that features
sub-methods and conditions in a strict goal hierarchy.
For example, here we see a hierarchy of goals,
as well as the ability to choose between multiple goals in different areas.
Notice also the level of granularity behind these GOMS models.
The goals go all the way down to little goals like moving text or deleting phrases.
These are very, very low-level goals.
Notice also the way this model is being used.
The authors are using it to find
the places where there's a lot of complexity that can be cut out.
They do this by modelling how long each individual action takes,
as well as looking at the number of interactions
required and seeing if it can be cut down a bit.
A third variation is called Natural GOMS Language.
Natural GOMS Language or NGOMSL is
a natural language form of GOMS that lends itself to human interpretation.
In all these cases, the important point of emphasis is the way that these models allow
us to focus in on places where we might be asking too much of the user.
For example, in this model,
the user was being asked to carry a lot of information in working memory.
By making the assumptions and actions and operators this detailed,
this model acts as target where working memory is being overly
taxed in a way that we might miss when we're doing higher level designs.