Within the full course at Georgia Tech,
there are a number of other strategies
in which you'll engage as well.
First, we're really passionate about
leveraging the student community in
this class to improve the experience for
everyone.
Taking this class with you are people
with experience in a variety of
industries, many of whom have
significant experience in HCI.
So some strategies we'll use include
peer learning, collaborative learning,
learning by teaching, and
communities of practice.
You'll learn both from each other and
with each other.
You'll play the role of student,
teacher, and partner, and
you will learn from each perspective.
In addition,
the entire course is built around
the idea of project-based learning.
Early in the semester, you'll form
a team and start looking at a problem
we've selected, or maybe one in
which you're already interested.
This project will then become the domain
through which you explore the principles
and methods of
human-computer interaction.
Who knows?
By the end of the semester,
you might even generate something
with the potential to go forward
as a real-world product,
or as a research project.