Here are five quick tips for developing GOMS models.
Number one, focus on small goals.
We've used some pretty big examples,
but GOMS is really designed to work in the context of
very small goals like navigating to the end of a document.
You can abstract up from there,
but start by identifying smaller moment-to-moment goals.
Number two, nest goals, instead of operators.
It's possible to nest goals.
For example, in our GOMS model of navigation,
we could develop it further and break the overall task of
navigating down to smaller goals like changing lanes or plotting routes.
Operators, however, are the smallest atoms of a GOMS model.
They don't break down any further,
and those must be the actual actions that are performed.
Number three, differentiate descriptive and prescriptive.
Make sure to identify whether you're building a model of what
people do or what you want them to do.
You can build a GOMS model of what people should do with your interface,
but you shouldn't trick yourself into thinking that's necessarily what they will do.
Number four, assign costs to operators.
GOMS was designed to let us make predictions about how long certain methods will take.
The only way we can do that is if we have
some measurement of how long individual operations take.
Usually, this is time, but depending on the domain,
we might be interested in phrasing the cost differently as well.
Number five, use GOMS to trim waste.
One of the benefits of GOMS is it lets you visualize where
an unnecessary number of operators are required to accomplish some task.
That's bolstered by the costs we assign to this operators.
So, use GOMS to identify places where the number of
operators required can be simplified by the interface.