Learning goals are what we
want you to understand.
Learning outcomes or
what we want you to be able to do.
Learning assessments then, are how we
evaluate whether you can do what we want
you to be able to do and understand
what we want you to understand.
The learning outcome to this
class is to be able to design
effective interactions
between humans and computers.
So the primary assessments in this
class are to, say it with me,
design effective interactions
between humans and computers.
You'll start with some relatively small
scale tasks, recommending improvements
to existing interfaces or or undertaking
some small design challenges.
But as the semester goes on, you'll
scope up towards a bigger challenge.
You'll initially investigate
that challenge individually and
then you'll merge into
teams to prototype and
evaluate a full solution
to the challenge you chose.
At the end, you'll be evaluated not just
on the final design you generate but
on the process by which
it was generated.