Every possible application of HCI involves users completing some sort of task.
That task might be something within a domain.
In educational technology, for example,
at that task might be learning how to do a certain kind of problem.
If your area is more technological,
the task might be something that the user is doing through your application like
using virtual reality and gesture recognition to sculpt the virtual statue.
Take a moment and try to think of the kinds of tasks you
might be interested in exploring in your chosen application area.
Did they lend themselves more to an information processor model like gums,
or to cognitive models like hierarchical task analysis and how can you tell?