[MUSIC]
In discussing a human-computer
interaction, there's often a tendency
to look narrowly at the user
interacting with the computer.
Or slightly more broadly at the user
interacting with the task through some
computer.
But many times we're interested
in zooming even further out.
We're interested, not only in
the interaction between the human,
the computer and the task, but
also in the context in which
that interaction takes place.
So today we're going to look at
four different models or theories,
of the context surrounding ACI.
We'll focus primarily on
distributed cognition,
which is one of the dominant theories on
the interplay between multiple agents,
artifacts, and contexts.
We'll also touch on three
other significant theories,
social cognition, situated action,
and activity theory.