One of the seminal works in
distributed cognition research is a paper from the Journal of Cognitive Science from
1995 called How a Cockpit Remembers Its Speeds by Edwin Hutchins.
You might recognize Edwin Hutchins' name from
our lesson on Direct Manipulation and Invisible Interfaces.
He was one of the coauthors there as well along with Don Norman.
This is one of my favorite papers in part simply because of
the very subtle change in emphasis that we see in the title.
We tend to think of remembering as a uniquely human or biological behavior.
We describe computers as having memory,
but we don't usually describe computers as remembering things.
Remembering is more of a human behavior,
but the paper title twist that a little bit.
It isn't the human,
it isn't the pilot remembering,
it's the cockpit remembering.
What is the cockpit?
The cockpit is a collection of controls,
sensors and interfaces as well as the pilots themselves.
The paper title tells us that it's this entire system,
the pilots, the sensors,
the controls in the interfaces among them that do the remembering.
The system as a whole or the cockpit as a whole is remembering the speed,
not just the human pilot or pilots in the cockpit.
No individual part in isolation remembers what the system as a whole can remember.