We're interested in any part of
the system that performs some of
the cognition for Morgan.
While the chair, table, and
light over head make this possible,
they aren't serving any cognitive roles.
Morgan herself, of course, is,
and two piles of bills are too.
They are an external memory of what
bills Morgan has already paid, and
what she still needs to pay.
This way she doesn't have to mentally
keep track of what bills she has
left to do.
The bills themselves remember
a lot of the information for
her as well like the amounts and the
destinations they need to be sent to.
What about the pen and checkbook?
That's when things start to
get a little bit more tricky.
The checkbook itself is part of
the system because it takes care of
the record keeping task for Morgan.
Checkbooks create carbon copies,
which means Morgan doesn't have to think
about tracking the checks manually.
The pen is a means of communicating
between these systems,
which means it's part of our
distributed cognition system as well.