We'll close by talking about the overall
structure of the content you'll be
consuming.
The course's lessons are designed to
be as independent as possible, so
you should be able to
skip around if you want,
but there's a certain logic to
our planned presentation order.
We discussed earlier the model HCI,
how design informs research and
research then informs design, so
we'll start by discussing some of
the core design principles of HCI.
Then we'll discuss
the research methodologies for
uncovering new user information,
the interative design lifecycle.
We'll close by giving you the
opportunity to peek at what's going on
in the HCI community at large.