Distributed cognition is concerned
with how the mind can be extended by
relations with other artifacts and
other individuals.
Because we're interface designers,
we probably focus most of our time
on the artifacts part of that.
After all,
even though we're designing tasks,
the artifacts are what we're actually
creating that's out in the world.
But the other part of
distributed cognition,
distributing across individuals presents
a powerful opportunity as well.
This used to be far more important,
actually.
Before the days of GPS navigation,
a different form of navigation
assistance existed.
It was your spouse or your friend
sitting in the passenger seat,
reading a map and
calling out directions to you.
And while mobile devices and artificial
intelligence may have replaced humans in
some such systems, there are still lot's
of places where the role of distributing
across humans is crucial.
Here's an example of
this in action today.
At Udacity, we use a tool for
managing projects called JIRA.
It breaks down projects into multiple
pieces that can be moved through
a series of steps and assigned to
different responsible individuals.
The entire value of JIRA is that it
manages distributing tasks across
members of a team.
Thus, when a project is completed,
it is completed by the system comprising
the individual team members and
JIRA itself.