The social portion of distributed
cognition is concerned with
how social connections create systems
that can, together, accomplish tasks.
So for example, you and your friend
sitting in the passenger seat, together
form a system capable of navigating
to a new destination without a GPS.
But social cognition is not only
concerned with how social relationships
combine to accomplish tasks.
It's also concerned with the cognitive
underpinning of social interactions
themselves.
It's interested in how perception,
memory, and
learning relate to social phenomena.
As interface designers though,
why do we care?
Well, in case you haven't noticed,
one of the most common applications
of interface design today
involves social media.
Everything is becoming social.
Facebook tries to tell you when
your friends are already nearby.
Udacity tries to connect you
with other students working on
the same material as you.
Video games are increasingly trying to
convince you to share your achievements
and highlights with your friends.
And yet, often times,
our interfaces are at odds with how we
really think about social interaction.
Designing for this well involves
understanding the cognitive
underpinnings of social relationships.
My Play Station, for
example, has a feature for
finding my real life friends, and then
communicating to them my gaming habits.
But really,
I probably don't want them to know
how much I might play video games.
If I come unprepared for recording
today, I certainly don't want Amanda to
know it was because I was playing
Skyrim for six hours last night.
So if we're going to design interfaces
that integrate with social interactions,
we have to understand how social
interactions actually work.
So an understanding of social
cognition is very important
if that's the direction
you want to take.