Let's talk about challenge of
designing for social relationships.
I like to play video games.
I'm friends with people from work.
So it's natural that I might want to
play games with people from work.
But at the same time,
my relationship with people
from work isn't purely social.
If they see I'm playing a game,
maybe they say,
hey, David's got some free time.
I should ask him to help
me out with something.
Or if they see I spend a lot of time
playing video games, maybe they more
generally say hey, David's got plenty
of time to take on a new tasks.
How do we design a social
video gaming system
that nonetheless protects against
these kinds of perceptions?