In 1996, Bonnie Nardi edited
a prominent book on study of contexts in human-computer interaction,
titled "Context and Consciousness".
The entire book is worth reading but two papers in particular stands out to me,
both by Nardi herself.
The first is a short paper that serves in
some ways as an introduction to the book as a whole.
It's not a long paper, only four pages,
so I highly recommend reading it, it won't take you long.
Here, Nardi outlines the general application of activity theory to HCI.
She notes that activity theory offers a set of perspectives on
human activity and a set of concepts for describing that activity.
This is exactly what HCI research needs as we struggle to
understand and describe context, situation, and practice.
She particularly notes that the theory is uniquely suited to addressing
some of the interesting issues facing HCI in 1996.
For that reason, it's also fascinating to view from a historical perspective.
Today, we understand the role that context has grown to play,
especially with emerging technologies.
It's fascinating to me to look back at how
the community was constructing that debate 20 years ago.