Most commonly in HCI, we're interesting
in designing for usability.
We want to make tasks
easier through technology.
So in a car, we might be interested in
designing a GPS that can be used with
the fewest number of taps.
Or a dashboard that surfaces the most
important information at the right time.
Sometimes we're also interested in
designing for research, though.
We might design a dashboard that
includes some kind of visualization
of the speed to see if that changes
the way the person perceives how fast
that they're going.
But a third motivation is to
somehow change the user's behavior.
Designing for change in response
to some value that we have.
Often times that may actually conflict
with those other motivations.
If we're trying to discourage
an unhealthy habit,
we might want to make the interface for
that habit less usable.
Cars actually have a lot of interfaces
created with that motivation in mind.
If I started driving without
a seatbelt on, my car will beep at me.
Some cars will cap your
speed at a certain number.
Those interfaces serve
no usability goals but
rather they serve
the goal of user safety.
Now, that's a simplistic example, but
it shows what I call
the three goals of HCI.
Help a user do a task, understand how
a user does a task, or change the way
a user does a task due to some value
that we hold, like safety or privacy.