In this lesson, I've tried to give you
some expectations of what this course will be like.
We've gone over the course's goals,
outcomes, learning strategies, and assessments.
We've covered the course's learning outcome in great detail,
to design effective interactions between humans and computers.
Now, I focus mostly on the video material because the assignments, projects,
and exams are separate from these videos,
and are likely to change pretty significantly semester to semester.
The video material here will cover three general areas;
principles, methods, and applications.
To really get into the applications,
it's useful to understand the principles and methods.
But the same time, it's useful to keep the applications in mind,
while learning about the principles and methods.
So, next, we're going to briefly preview some of the application areas,
for you to keep in mind during the rest of our conversations.
Then, after we cover principles and methods,
we'll invite you to revisit these application areas
and leave room to explore whatever you find most interesting.