So here's one idea.
Imagine a weather tracking app that
crowdsourced weather monitoring.
Every hour participants are buzzed to go
outside and let their phone take some
temperature readings,
maybe take a picture of the sky.
That design has nothing at all
to do with moving around, but
that's the side effect of it.
Participation in this
seemingly unrelated activity
has the benefit of
getting people moving.
Pokemon GO is a great example
of this in a different context.
It doesn't spark the same kind of
intermittent exercise but it gets people
to exercise more generally, all without
ever actually telling them to do so.