Positive change doesn't always
have to happen by design though.
In fact there are numerous examples
of positive change happening more
as a bi-product of technological
advancement rather than as a goal of it.
In Bijker's, of Bicycles, Bakelites and
Bulbs, this is the bicycle example.
The story looks at what
women can do before and
after the invention of the bicycle.
Before the bicycle, women tend
to be pretty reliant on men for
transportation.
People generally got around with
carriages, which were pretty expensive,
so only wealthy people would own them.
And so, typically men would own them.
So if a woman wanted to go to
a restaurant or go to a show,
she typically had to go either with
her spouse or with her father.
As a result, society rarely
saw women acting individually.
They were usually in the company of
whoever the prominent male in their life
was at the time.
But then the bicycle came along.
The bicycle was affordable enough and
targeted at individuals, so
now women could get around on their own.
So now a woman could go to a show or
go to a restaurant by herself,
instead of relying on a man to take her.
In the book though,
what Bijker covers is not just the fact
that this enabled more
individual transportation, but
rather that this enabled
a profound social shift.
This technological innovation allowed
women to start acting independently.
And it also demanded a wardrobe change,
interestingly enough, because you
couldn't wear a dress on a bicycle.
So the invention of the bicycle
simultaneously changed women's' attire,
and changed the level of independence
they could show in modern society.
And both these changes force society
to challenge traditional gender roles.
The bicycle's role in
women's liberation was so
significant that Susan B Anthony
actually once said, I think bicycling
has done more to emancipate women
than anything else in the world.
But when the bicycle was invented, it's
doubtful that the inventor sat down and
said surely this will be a great
way to emancipate women and
change our culture's gender roles.
That's not what they had in mind.
They were inventing
a technological device.
But as an unintended
positive side effect,
that technological device
profoundly changed society.