Just as we can create positive changes
by accident, if we aren't careful,
we can also inadvertently create
negative changes as well, or
further preserve existing
negative dynamics.
A good example of this is
the proliferation of the Internet in
the first place.
When the Internet first came along,
it piggybacked on existing phone lines.
Then it started piggybacking on
more expensive cable TV lines.
And now it's following along with
very expensive fiber optic lines.
At every stage of the process, areas
with more well developed infrastructure
get the latest Internet speeds first.
However, generally the areas with
well developed infrastructure
are the wealthier areas
in the first place,
either because wealthier citizens
paid for the improved infrastructure.
Or because people with the means to
move wherever they want to move,
will move somewhere with
better infrastructure.
High speed internet access
is a big economic boon.
And yet areas that are already
economically advantaged
are generally the first ones to
get higher speed internet access.
Even today,
in poorer parts of the United States
the only available Internet connections
are slow, unreliable satellite
connections with strict data caps.
And in the rest of the world this
issue can be even more profound,
where many areas have no
internet access whatsoever.
And yet, this isn't intentional.
Unlike the bridges on Long Island,
no one is saying,
let's withhold broadband access
from poor people to keep them poor.
Instead, it's natural to install better
connections where there's already
an existing infrastructure to build on.
But that very natural plan has
profoundly negative implications for
equitable access to the Internet.
So if we're not careful, completely
innocent and completely logical design
ideas can actually perpetuate
negative effects in society.