One of the challenges with value
sensitive design is that values can
differ across cultures.
The internet makes it technologically
possible to design single interfaces
that are used by people in nearly
every country, but just because
it's technologically possible doesn't
mean it's practically possible.
And one reason for
that is different countries and
cultures may have vastly
different values.
A relatively recent news worthy
example of this occurred with
the rights to be forgotten.
The right to be forgotten is
a law in the European union,
that allows individuals some control
over what information is available about
them online.
That's a value held by
the European Union.
However, technologies like Google were
not generally developed with that
value in mind.
So there's actually been
an extraordinary effort to
try to technologically support
that right to be forgotten,
while still providing
search capabilities.
Making this even more
complicated is the fact that
the value isn't universally shared.
Many people argue that the law could
actually effectively become internet
censorship.
So now we start to see some conflict in
the values between different cultures.
One cultures value of privacy,
might run a rye of another
cultures value of free speech.
If we're to design interfaces
that can reach multiple cultures,
we need to understand
the values of those cultures.
Especially if it might force us
to design different systems for
different people in order to
match their local values.