The idea of artifacts or interfaces having
political clout brings up two challenges for us as interface designers.
First, we need to think about places where we can use
interface design to invoke positive social change,
and second, we also need to think about
the possible negative ramifications of our interfaces.
What undesirable stereotypes are we preserving
or what new negative dynamics might we create?
Now, obviously I work in online education and I've been struck by both sides of this.
On the positive side, I've been amazed at the power of
online education to diminish
the significance of superficial obstacles to people's success.
I've spoken with people who have had difficulty succeeding in
traditional college settings due to social anxiety disorders or other disabilities,
things that had no real connection to how well they understood the material,
but that made it difficult to interact with
other people or to attend to physical classes.
But by putting everything in forums and emails and text and videos,
they've been able to overcome those obstacles.
But there's also the risk that online education
will only benefit people who already have advantages.
The early data suggests that the majority of consumers of online education are
middle-class American white males
There's little data to suggest that it's reaching minorities,
reaching women, reaching international students
or reaching economically disadvantaged students,
and while I believe that's a problem that can be solved,
it's certainly something we need to address.
Otherwise, we risk online education being a luxury more than an equalizer.
So, that's how these principles relate to online education.
Take a moment and reflect on how they apply to the area of HCI that you chose to explore.
What role can your technology play in creating
positive societal change and what risks are there if your technology catches on?