You have almost certainly
experienced political or
business motivations changing the way
in which a technology of yours works.
Similar to the fluorescent light bulb,
often times these motivations
are to preserve the power or
profit of an influential organization
in the face of radical change.
Sometimes they might be the products of
a relationship or an agreement between
vendors or organizations to
emphasize one another's content.
Generally, these are instances where
technology either performs sub-optimally
or has certain features because
someone besides the user benefits.
So reflect for a second and
see if you can think of an instance
where some technology you use
was designed with this kind of
political motivation in mind.