[MUSIC]
[SOUND] Computers are finding their
way into more and more devices, and
as a result HCI is becoming more and
more ubiquitous.
It used to be that you wouldn't
really need to think too
much about HCI when designing a car or
designing a refrigerator, but more and
more computing is pervading everything.
At the same time,
new technological developments are
opening up new areas for exploration.
We're seeing a lot of really fascinating
progress in areas like virtual reality,
augmented reality, wearable devices.
As we study HCI, we're going to talk
a lot about things you've already used
like computers and phones.
But we want you to keep in mind some
of these more cutting edge application
areas as well.
After all, if you're really interested
in going into HCI professionally,
you'll be designing for
these new application areas.
So we're going to quickly
preview some of these.
We'll divide them into three areas,
technologies, domains and ideas.
Technologies are emerging technological
capabilities that let us create new and
interesting user interactions.
Domains are pre-existing areas that
could be significantly disrupted
by computer interfaces like
healthcare and education.
Ideas span both of these.
They are the theories about the way
people interact with interfaces and
the world around them.
Now, our delineation of
this is kind of artificial.
There's a lot of overlap.
New technologies like augmented
reality are what allow emerging
ideas like contact sensitive computing
to really have the power that they do.
But for organization,
we'll group our application areas
into these three categories.
When one of these areas catches
your eye, take a little while and
delve into it a little bit deeper.
Then keep that topic area in mind as you
go through the rest of the HCI material.
We'll revisit your chosen area
throughout the course, and
ask you to reflect on the application
of the course's principals and
methods to your application area.