This question can have some
pretty loaded answers and
I encourage you to give those answers.
But I'm going to give
a slightly more innocuous one,
exclusivity agreements in video games.
Imagine I'm a video game developer and
Amanda is Nintendo.
And I'll say hey, Nintendo I'll agree to
release my game only on your console,
if you agree to promote my game
in your console advertisements.
I benefit from free advertising,
Nintendo benefits from getting
a selling point for its console.
There's probably no technological reason
my game can't run on other consoles.
But there's this business relationship
determining the way that the technology
works.