For the most part, we're interested
in something more task-focused.
In fact, this is where we'll likely
spend the majority of our time.
This is the user interacting through
some interface to accomplish some task.
That's what we mean by
the predictor model of the user.
The user is actively involved in looking
at the task, making predictions about
what to do, and making predictions
about what will happen.
This is where we looked at the gulf of
execution and the gulf of evaluation.
How hard is is for
the user to interact with a task?
And how hard is it for them to get
feedback on their interaction?
Here we also look at how the interface
can ideally disappear from this
interaction, making the user feel like
they're working directly with the task,
not interacting with an interface.
Now, many of our design principles
are constructed specifically to
help with this.
To help users more quickly make
sense of the interface, and
understand the underlying task.
But in order to design this interaction
effectively, we have to understand
the way the user thinks about
the task they're performing.
We have to understand
their mental models and
in turn, we have to help make sure their
mental models match the actual task.
Here we have to get into questions like
understanding the user's errors and
understanding the mapping
between representations and
the understanding tasks.
We also have to address questions
like expert blind spot and
learned helplessness.
Now, fortunately,
we have a tool to help us with this.
Cognitive task analysis and
its related hierarchical task analysis.
So much of what we deal with in HCI
occurs within this process of a human
completing a task
through some interface.