However, that's not all
we're interested in.
We're also interested in how this
interaction occurs beyond just
the individual and
the interface and the task.
That's what was meant by
the participant model of the user.
The user is not merely
interacting with an interface or
interacting with a task
through an interface.
They're interacting
with other interfaces,
other individuals and
society as a whole.
They are active participants
in the world around them.
For example, sometimes we're interested
not only in the tasks of the users
performing, but also in their
motivations and reasons for
performing it.
That's what activity theory advocates.
Treating the unit of
analysis not as a task, but
as an activity including some elements
of the context surrounding the task.
Other times we're interested
in how artifacts and
minds combine to help
accomplish the task.
That's what distributing
cognition advocates.
Or other times we are interested in
deeply understanding the situated
context in which a person is acting,
that's where situated action comes in.
And other times, we're interested in how
this all integrates with existing social
norms and social relationships.
That's what social
cognition tries to examine,
other times we're interested in
dynamics even broader than this.
Sometimes, we're interested in how the
interfaces we design can create positive
social change.
Or sometimes we're interested in
how the interfaces we design might
risk perpetuating existing
negative relationships in society.
That's exactly the goal of some
of our design guidelines as well.
To use interfaces to create a more
equal society for all people.
So this diagram describes from a very
low level to a very high level,
what we're interested in
throughout this portion of HCI.