Let's go back to our original
design challenge for
Morgan from the very
beginning of this unit.
We talked about how Morgan wants to
be able to listen to audio books on
the go which includes things like
leaving bookmarks and taking notes.
Using everything we've talked about so
far, revisit this problem.
Start by thinking narrowly about the
physical interactions between Morgan and
the interface and then zoom out to her
interactions with the task as a whole,
then zoom out even further to how
the interaction between Morgan and
the interface or relates to other things
going on in the world around here.
And last,
think about how interfaces like this
have the potential to
effect society itself.