I mentioned in one of our first conversations that
this course is distinct from user interface design course.
We're interested in general principles and general methods for designing interactions
between humans and various different kinds of computational devices.
Designing for traditional screens has its own set of specific principles.
However, it's quite likely that you'll be designing for this kind of traditional device.
So, here are five quick tips for designing effective onscreen user interfaces.
Number 1, use a grid.
Grids are powerful ways of guiding users site around your interface,
highlighting important content, grouping together content, and so on.
There's a reason why newspapers and magazines have used grid-based layouts for decades.
Number 2, use whitespace.
Users are very good at consuming small chunks of information at a time.
Notice how news articles often use very short paragraphs and how,
why science have lots of whitespace around the text.
Whitespace works with grids to provide context and
guide the user's visual perception of the interface.
Number 3, know your Gestalt principles.
Gestalt principles in UI design refer to how users perceive groups of objects.
It uses group objects together when they're especially close together,
when they're visually similar,
when they're moving together, so use that.
Number 4, reduce clutter.
The eye has difficulty processing cluttered information,
so reduce clutter wherever possible.
Grids, whitespace, and Gestalt principles can help with this because they invisibly
communicate content that might otherwise need to be communicated visually.
Instead of drawing a box to group controls together,
you can surround them with whitespace.
Instead of using headers and texts to label different portions of some content,
you can separate them with a grid and so on.
Number 5, design in grayscale.
Color can be a powerful tool,
but it also runs array of universal design.
There are enough color blind individuals in the world that
relying on color too much is really problematic.
Color can emphasize the content and structure of your interface,
but it shouldn't be necessary to understand it.
Take a stoplight, for example.
Red means stop and green means go,
which is a problem if you're deuteranopic or red-green colorblind,
but the red light is always at the top and the green light is always at the bottom.
So, even if you are deuteranopic,
you can still understand what the light is saying.
Color emphasizes the content,
but the content doesn't rely on the color.
If you're going to be doing a lot of screen-based UI design,
I do highly recommend taking a class in the topic.
It will cover these principles and a lot more depth,
give stronger rules for designing good grades and using whitespace,
and cover one of my favorite topics, typography.
Amanda can testify that more thought went into selecting the fonts to use
in this course than nearly any other element of its design.
If you're curious, it's Ubuntu Condensed for the diagrams and Oswald for the loops.
Well, except that one.