When you start to design a new interface,
your goal is to design an interface that will meet
the needs of the user better than the existing design.
It's very rare that we design for tasks that users have never even performed before.
We're almost always developing new ways to accomplish old tasks.
Facebook, for example, was a new way to socialize and communicate with others,
but the fundamental activities of socializing and communicating weren't new.
Facebook just met those needs better or,
at least, met certain needs better depending on who you ask.
In order to design interactions that are better than existing designs,
it's important to take into consideration
the user's needs at every stage of the design process.
That's what this unit of this course will cover.
We don't generally want to build
creative novel interfaces just for the sake of creativity or novelty.
We want novelty to have a purpose and to achieve that purpose,
it must be used with a strong understanding of the user's task.
So, in this unit, we'll cover the design life cycle as well as methods for gathering
feedback and information from users at every stage of the cycle.
However, before we get started on that,
we need to set up some basic concepts we use throughout our discussions.
We'll start by discussing user-centered design and then
we'll introduce the four-stage design life cycle.
We'll discuss a few different general methods for pursuing the design life cycle.
Then finally, we will discuss the two kinds of information or
data that we gather, qualitative and quantitative.