The International Standards Organization has outlined
six principles to follow when pursuing user-centered design.
Number one, the design is based on
explicit understanding of users, tasks, and environments.
That means we must gather information about the users,
the task they performed, and where they perform those tasks.
We need to leverage that knowledge throughout the design process.
Number two, users are involved throughout design and development.
Involvement can take on many forms from
regularly participating with interviews and surveys about
our designs to actually working on the design team alongside the designers themselves.
Number three, the design is driven and refined by user-centered evaluation.
We absolutely must have real users
evaluating the prototypes and interfaces that we assemble.
Number four, the process is iterative.
No tool is developed once,
released, and then abandoned.
Designs undergo constant iteration and improvement even after being released.
Number five, the design addresses the whole user experience.
Many designers are tempted to delineate a certain portion
of the experience as their primary interest,
but we must address the entire user experience.
Number six, the design team includes multidisciplinary skills and perspectives.
Good teams for pursuing user-centered design include
people with a number of different backgrounds like psychologists,
designers, computer scientists, domain experts, and more.
So, keep these principles in mind when you're doing user experience design.