User centered design is about
integrating the user into
every phase of the design life cycle.
So, we need to know two things.
What the design life cycle is and how
to integrate the user into each phase.
Now if you look up design life cycles
you'll find a lot of different ideas.
We're going to discuss in terms of
a four phase design life cycle that's
pretty general and probably subsumes
many of the other ones you'll find.
The first part of this is Needfinding.
In Needfinding, we gather a
comprehensive understanding of the task
the users are trying to perform.
That includes who the user is,
what the context of the task is,
why they're doing the task, and
any other information related
to what we're designing.
Second, we develop multiple
design alternatives.
These are very early ideas on
the different ways to approach the task.
It's important to develop multiple
alternatives to avoid getting stuck in
one idea too soon.
The third step is prototyping.
We take the ideas with the most
potential and we build them into
prototypes that we can then
actually put in front of a user.
Early on we might do this in very low
fidelity ways like with a paper and
pencil, or
even just verbally describing our ideas.
But as we go on we refine and improve.
Fourth, and most importantly,
we perform user evaluation.
We take our ideas that we prototyped and
put them in front of actual users.
We get their feedback, what they like
and what they don't like, what works and
what doesn't work, and
then the cycle begins anew.
The feedback we gain from the users,
as well as our experience
with these prototypes and
design alternatives, improves our
understanding of the problem.
We now know new areas of the problem
we might need to explore with some more
need finding.
Now we might have some new ideas for
design alternatives, or
some new ways of expanding
the designs that we already have.
We then take those things and
use them to improve our prototypes.
Either prototyping new ideas
that we didn't have before, or
making our prototypes more rigorous and
more polished,
so that we can get
even better evaluation.
And then we put them in
front of users again.
Each time we go through this
cycle our understanding improves,
our designs improve, and
our prototypes improve.
Eventually our prototypes develop to
the point of being designs ready for
launch, but the cycle doesn't end there.
We keep iterating, now with live
users doing the evaluation.