Virtual reality generally works by
replacing the real world's visual,
auditory, and
sometimes even all factory or
kinesthetic stimuli with it's own input.
Augmented reality on the other hand,
compliments what you see and
hear in the real world.
So for example, imagine a headset
like a Google Glass that
automatically overlays directions
right on your visual field.
If you were driving,
it would highlight the route to take,
instead of just popping
up some visual reminder.
The input it provides complements
stimuli coming from the real world,
and instead of just replacing them.
And that creates some
enormous challenges, but
also some really incredible
opportunities as well.
Imagine the devices that can integrate
directly into our everyday lives,
enhancing our reality.
Imagine systems that could, for example,
automatically translate text or
speech in a foreign language,
or could show your reviews for
restaurants as you walk down the street.
Imagine a system that students could
use while touring national parks or
museums, that would automatically
point out interesting information,
custom tailored to that
student's own interests.
The applications of augmented
reality could be truly stunning, but
it relies on cameras to take
input from the world, and
that actually raises some
interesting societal problems.
There are questions about what
putting cameras everywhere would mean.
So keep those in mind when we get to
interfaces and politics, in unit two.