When we talk about feedback cycles,
we talk about how they're ubiquitous
across nearly every field.
And each CI itself, isn't any different.
In a feedback cycle,
the user does something in
the interface to accomplish some goal.
And then judges based on
the output from the interface,
whether the goal was accomplished,
then they repeat and continue.
In HCI, we're brainstorming and
designing interfaces
to accomplish goals.
And then based on the output of our
evaluations, we judge whether or
not the goals of the interface
were actually accomplished,
then we repeat and continue.
In many ways, we're doing the same
things that our users are doing,
trying to understand how to
accomplish a task in an interface.
Only in our case,
our interface is the tools to build and
evaluate interfaces and our goal is
to help them accomplish their goal.