Just as there are different types of quantitative data,
so also there are different types of qualitative data.
In practice though, the types of qualitative data we generate are
usually much more closely integrated with the way in which they were generated.
For example, we could have discrete ratio data that
comes from self-reported responses on a survey,
or naturalistic observations in the wild,
or logs from real interfaces.
Qualitative data, on the other hand,
tends to be determined more by how it's gathered.
Some common types of qualitative data we'll deal with
are transcripts from things like interviews and focus groups,
field notes we might take during naturalistic or participant observation,
artifacts like reviews left for
existing interfaces or the existing interfaces themselves,
and lots, lots more.
Quantitative data is numeric data,
and qualitative data is everything else.
So, the span of possible qualitative data is a lot larger.
The qualitative data is strong because these types of data
provide a much richer picture of what we're investigating.
But with that strength comes some costs.
Qualitative data is also more expensive to analyze,
and it's also a lot more prone to interpretation biases.
So, for that reason, we often convert
qualitative data to quantitative data for the purpose of analysis.
We do this through a process called coding.
Now here, coding isn't writing Python code or doing anything like that.
Coding is a process of taking
free foreign qualitative data and boiling it down into some numeric categories.
Typically, these categories are nominal,
which allows us to do whatever kind of statistical test
we can do on nominal quantitative data.
During this process, we lose some of that rich data.
But what we gain is a numeric representation that we can use in new ways,
and plus we didn't really lose that original data.
It's just not part of the output of this coding process.
So, we can still go back and look at it if we need to.
The other thing that comes out of this process is
a documented methodology for actually coding the qualitative data to quantitative data.
So, if anyone asks where we got these numbers,
we can actually show them the process we went through.
That helps us argue that our interpretations are not
just biased interpretations of what happened,
but they are actually rigorous analyses based on that qualitative data.
In HCI., we almost always want to use some mix of these two.
Our problems are far too rich to address with quantitative data alone,
but for that same reason,
we risk being dominated by biases if we focus solely on qualitative analysis.