In this lesson, we introduced the concept of the Design Life Cycle.
There are lots of versions of the Design Life Cycle out there,
but we're going to focus on the most general four-step cycle.
The cycle starts with need-finding,
then goes to constructing design alternatives,
and to prototyping, and then the user evaluation,
and then the cycle repeats.
The goal of this cycle is to realize user-centered design.
Design that takes into consideration the user's needs at every step.
In the rest of this unit,
we're going to focus on filling up your Design Life Cycle toolbox with
tools for gathering the right kind of data at
the right time and using it in the right way.