[MUSIC]
Before we start working with real users
there are a few ethical considerations
we have to make.
If you are doing a research as part of
a university these are part of your
contract with the university to
do research on their behalf.
Even if you are doing
research independently for
an industry there are still
ethical obligations to follow.
These considerations are important not
only to preserve the rights of our
users, but also to ensure the value
of the data that we gather.
In this lesson, we'll talk a little
bit about where these kinds of ethical
considerations came from.
Then we'll talk about some of
the basic ethical considerations
that we need to make.
We'll also talk about
Institutional Review Board, or IRB,
the university organization that
governs human subjects research.