In the first half of the 20th century,
a number of pretty clearly unethical
human subjects experiments took place.
Many of them were conducted
by scientists working for
the Axis powers during World War II.
But famously, many were also conducted
right here in our own backyard,
here in the United States.
Among them were Milgam's obedience
experiment where participants were
tricked into thinking that
they had administered lethal
shocks to other participants to
see how obedient they would be.
There was the Tuskegee syphilis study
where rural African American men were
intentionally injected with syphilis
to study its progression and there was
the Stanford prison experiment where
participants were psychologically abused
to test their limits or test how they
would act under different circumstances.
In response to all this, the National
Research Act of 1974 was passed,
which led to the creation of
institutional review boards to oversee
research at universities.
The Belmont Report further summarizes
basic ethical principals that research
must follow in order to
receive government support.
Among other things, the law dictated
that the benefits to society must
outweigh the risks to the subjects
in the case of these experiments.
It also dictated that subjects
must be selected fairly,
which was a direct response to
the Tuskegee syphilis study.
And perhaps most importantly,
it demanded a rigorous
informed consent procedures.
So, the participants know
what they're getting into and
can back out at any time.
These efforts all attempt to make sure
that the positive results of research
outweigh the negatives and that
participant rights are always preserved.