In this lesson, we're largely
focusing on the practical steps we
go through to get approval for
human subject's research.
But before we get into that, I want to
highlight that this isn't just a bunch
of bureaucratic steps necessary to
make sure the people are treated
ethically at all stages of research,
IRBs main task is to make sure
the potential benefits of the study
are worth the potential risks.
So as part of that,
part of the role is to make sure
the potential benefits are significant.
A lot of the steps of the process are
going to ensure that the data that we
gather is useful.
So for example, the IRB is sensitive
about the perception of coercion.
When participants feel coerced
to participate in research,
the data they actually supply may be
skewed by that negative perception
which impacts our results.
Similarly, we might design studies
that have some inherent biases or
issues to them.
We might demand too much
from participants or
ask questions that are known
to affect our results.
Much of the initial training to be
certified to perform research is
similarly not just about
doing ethical research but
also about doing good research.
By recording who is certified,
IRB helps ensure that research personnel
all understand the basics
of human subjects research.
IRB is also there to monitor for these
things as well and many of the steps of
this process ensure that the research
we perform is sound and useful.
After all, if the research
we perform is not useful,
then even the smallest risks will
outweigh the nonexistent benefits.