If you're going to be doing a research
just part of a University project or
University class, you need IRB approval.
Different universities have
different processes and
policies for getting started with IRB.
We're going to discuss the Georgia Tech
policies and sets where these class is
based but you should check with your
university if you're from somewhere else
to make sure you're following
the right policies for your school.
To get started, we need to
complete the required training.
So here I'm showing the IRB website,
which is
researchintegrity.gatech.edu/irb.
And to get started, you need to
complete your required training.
So click required training
over on the left.
This'll take you to a page that
overviews the IRB required training and
gives you a link of the left
to begin your CITI training.
So click that,
then login to your Georgia Tech account.
And you're going to want to
complete Group 2, Social and
Behavioral Research Investigators and
Key Personnel.
I can't show you exactly what it looks
like to sign up fresh because I've
already completed it.
But you should be able to add
a course and add that as your course.
After you've completed CITI training
you'll receive your completion report
and then you'll be ready
to get started with IRB.