After you've completed
any necessary training
you can access the IRB application for
your own university.
We're doing this in
terms of Georgia Tech,
so here's the tool we
used called IRBWISE.
Here under my protocols,
you'll see a list of all of
the protocols to which you're added.
A protocol is a description of
a particular research project.
It outlines the procedures that the IRB
has approved regarding consent,
recruitment, experimentation and more.
Here we see approved protocols.
Protocols that are new and
haven't been submitted yet.
Protocols that are waiting for
the IRB to act on them.
And amendments to protocols.
Amendments are how we change earlier
protocols to add new researchers or
change what we're approved to do.
After a protocol is approved,
any changes must be submitted to the IRB
as an amendment to be
accepted separately.