Generally speaking,
you might not ever be asked to
complete a protocol yourself.
You might instead just be
added to an existing protocol.
Still, you need to make sure to
understand the procedures outlined by
any protocol to which you're added,
because they still govern what you do.
So we'll run through the process of
creating a protocol, but this will also
cover the details to know about any
protocol to which you are added.
So for this,
I have a draft protocol covering our
user study on people who exercise.
Every protocol starts with
the title of the protocol, and
some certified personnel.
These are required just
to save the protocol.
We add approved research personnel
on the study personnel page.
We would enter their name,
select their role, and
if their certification isn't already
in the system, we would attach it here.
After adding them,
they'll appear down here.
The primary investigator, PI,
must always be added first and
it must be a faculty member.
The protocol description covers
the study at a high level.
This should briefly touch
on what will be done,
what the goal of the research is and
what subjects will be asked to do.
It doesn't cover all the details,
but it covers enough for
someone to understand generally what
we're going for with this study.
Under the research design and
methodology section,
we describe our research.
First, we describe the research
design in the methodology.
With human subjects research,
this focuses on what users will
experience and in what order.
It also covers some experimental details
like how subjects might be assigned
different experimental conditions.
Then we describe the duration of subject
participation to make sure subjects
aren't being asked to do too much.
Depending on what we're doing, we may
need to provide data collection methods.
This includes things like surveys,
pre-tests and post-tests interview
scripts, anything pre-prepared to
elicit data for the participant.
Then we also need to fully describe
the potential benefits of the study.
Remember, IRB is about making sure
that the benefits out way the risks.
If there are no benefits, then
the benefits can't out way the risks.
Benefits don't need to be to
the individual participants though,
but they could be to the greater
community as a whole.
Similarly, we also needed to describe
the risks associated with the study.
For usability studies,
very often our risks are not
going to be very significant.
Our risks might be those associated
with normal work at a computer.
But we still need to address this to
acknowledge that we thought about what
risks might arise to participants.
Then we describe the plan for
the statistical analysis if we have one.
Qualitative research might not have
a statistical analysis plan, so
that's why I've left this blank.
Finally, we need to describe start and
end dates of the research.
Very often, this will break the research
into a data collection phase and
a research phase, where we actually
analyze the data that we collected.
Now we won't generally need to worry
about many of the remaining options on
this form, because we're not
doing clinical studies and
we generally don't have external funding
unless you're working on a professor's
research project.
So now let's move on to subject details.