One of the most important elements
of IRB approval is consent,
that was one of the things
created by the Belmont Report.
If we're doing any interaction
with our human subjects,
we definitely need to think
about consent procedures.
On the consent information page, first,
we need to indicate what kind
of consent we'll receive.
Most commonly,
this will be written consent required.
In this case, participants will sign or
digitally sign,
a consent form to start the study, but
in some cases a waiver may be obtained.
First, a waiver of consent can
be obtained under certain,
pretty narrow circumstances,
this generally means we don't need to
receive the subject's consent at all.
Most of the time this only applies
when subjects will not be directly
affected by the research.
So for example,
if we wanted to study educational or
health data that's already
been generated and
is already anonymized,
we might receive a waiver of consent.
Because those subjects won't be
impacted by the fact we're now
researching their data.
Similarly, if we were to go sit in
a coffee house and just take notes on
the order taking process in a way
that didn't identify anyone.
We might receive a waiver of consent,
because our observation is
not affecting those people.
We might also receive a waiver
of documentation of consent.
This occurs for low risk research,
where the written consent itself,
would be the only record of
the participants identity.
This applies to a lot of survey
research or unrecorded interviews,
where participants can be informed
of their rights at the start, and
their own continued participation
constitutes continued implied consent.
There's no reason to have them sign a
consent form, because that consent form
is the only reason we'd ever be able
to identify them after the study.
After selecting our option,
we need to provide a justification,
if we requested a waiver.
If we didn't,
then no justification is necessary.
We'll then describe the plan for
obtaining informed consent.
Generally, this will be to provide
the consent form to participants
at the start of a study, and
make it very clear that they can
withdraw from the study at any time.
If we're involving children,
non english speakers or other at risk
populations in our study, there may
be some additional boxes to complete.
It's also important for
us to assess whether participants
are continuing to consent to the study.
Often times, we do this by making it
very clear at the start of the study
that they can withdraw at any time.
So that their continued participation
constitutes implied continued consent.
Finally, it's also possible to
have protocols where deception or
concealment is proposed.
In HCI, for example, we might want to
tell participants that an interface is
functioning even if someone behind the
scenes is actually just making it look
functional, so that we get good research
data out of those participants.
For example, if we were testing
something like a new version of Siri,
we might tell participants
that it's functioning,
when in reality someone is
writing the responses by hand.
If we're using deception or concealment
like that, we'll indicate so here.
Then finally,
we need to upload our consent forms.
At Georgia Tech the Office of Research
Integrity Assurance provides consent
form templates that we can tweak to
match the specific needs of our study.
The templates provide in depth
directions on what to supply.
Generally, this is where we disclose
to participants the details of the rest
of the protocol.
What we're researching, why, how, and
why they were invited to participate?