Institutional review boards
govern any research institutions
that receive support from
the federal government.
But what about research that doesn't
receive any federal support?
Very often, companies will
do research on their users.
This is especially common in HCI.
Lots of companies are constantly
doing very interesting testing on
their users with a lot
of rapid AB experiments.
There's a lot of potential knowledge
there, but at the same time
much of what they do likely would not
pass IRB if it were university research.
This actually came up recently
with Facebook in a paper they
published titled experimental evidence
of massive-scale emotional contagion
through social networks.
Basically, Facebook wanted to see if
they could predict what would make
users happy or sad.
And as a result they
tweaked the news feed for
some users to test out their ideas.
In other words, they tried to
manipulate their user's mood for
experimental purposes.
Now, Facebook argues that this
was consistent with their
own data use policy, which permits
them to perform experiments like this.
Some social scientists however would
argue that this does not constitute
informed consent.
Informed consent they say is specific
to a certain experiment, temporary for
a known period of time and
given without coercion.
Some would argue that if you don't
agree you can't use Facebook
qualifies as coercion.
These are some difficult issues and
if you end up working in HCI industry,
you'll likely find yourself
wrestling with some of them.