A lot of the current focus on robotics is on their physical construction and
abilities or on the artificial intelligence that underlies their physical forms.
But as a robotics becomes more and more mainstream,
we're going to see the emergence of a new sub-field of
human-computer interaction, human-robot interaction.
The field actually already exists.
The first conference on human-robot interaction took place in 2006 in Salt Lake City,
and several similar conferences have been created since then.
As robots into the mainstream,
we're going to have to answer some interesting questions about how we interact with them.
For example, how do we ensure that robots don't harm humans through faulty reasoning?
How do we integrate robots into our social lives or do we even need to?
As robots are capable of more and more,
how do we deal with the loss of demand for human work?
Now, these questions all lie at the intersection of
HCI artificial intelligence and philosophy,
in general, but there's some more concrete questions we can answer as well.
How do we pragmatically equip robots with the ability to
naturally interact with humans based on things like voice and touch?
How do we provide tacit subtle feedback to humans interacting with robots to
confirm their input is being received and properly understood?
How do we support humans in teaching things to robots instead of just programming
them or alternatively can we create robots that can teach things to humans?
We already see robotics advances applied to things
like health care and disability services,
and I'm really excited to see where you take it next.