If you said yes, there are several
reasons you might have stated.
You might agree that because
the terms of service covered it,
it was technically ethical research.
The users did agree to things like this.
You may have actually read the article
or read other publications about it and
noted that Facebook actually has
an internal IRB that reviews things
like this.
And in this case,
an external IRB did review the study.
If you said no, the reason you
gave may have been that we know
users are not aware of
what's in terms of use.
We have plenty of studies that indicate
that users really don't spend any time
reading what they're agreeing to.
And while technically, it's true
that they're still agreeing to it,
what we're interested in here
are participants' rights.
If we know that users aren't
reading what they're agreeing to,
don't we have an ethical obligation to
make sure they're aware before we go
ahead with it.
We also might say no because users
couldn't opt out of this study.
Part of that is because opting out of
the study alone means deactivating your
entire Facebook account or
just stopping using the tool.
But part of it is that users also
weren't aware that a study was
now going on.
They couldn't opt out of
the study specifically, nor
could they even opt out of it by closing
down their entire Facebook account
because they didn't know
when the study had started.
That ties into the other issue.
Users weren't notified that they
were participants in an experiment.
So even though they technically agreed
to it when they agreed to Facebook's
terms of service, one could argue
the fact they weren't notified when
the study was beginning and ending
means that it wasn't ethical research.
I'm not going to give you a right or
wrong answer to this.
There's a very interesting
conversation to have about this.
But what's most important here are the
interesting questions that it brings up.
Especially in regard to companies
doing human subjects research
that doesn't have any over sight
from the federal government.
If you agreed with these
reasons why it wasn't ethical,
what could they have done to fix it?
Maybe they could have separated
out the consent process for
research studies from the rest
of Facebook as a whole.
Maybe they could have specifically
requested that individual users opt-in,
and alert them when the study was done,
but
not tell them what's
actually being manipulated.
And even if the original
study was ethical,
there were likely things that
could have reduced the backlash.
At the same time, those things
might have affected the results.
These are the tradeoffs
that we deal with.