In this lesson, we've talked about research ethics.
Research ethics guide the human subjects research we do
to make sure we're respecting the rights of our participants,
but it also makes sure the data we're gathering is good and useful.
At every stage of our design life cycle,
we want to keep respect for our participants at the forefront of our thoughts.
That means being wary of experimenting in ways that might negatively affect users.
That also means only asking users to dedicate
their time to evaluating interfaces that are well thought out,
and that means respecting user's viewpoints and position in the design process.