Before we start our need-finding
exercises, we also want to enter with
some understanding of
the data we want to gather.
These are the questions we
ultimately want to answer.
That's not to say we should be answering
them every step of the way, but rather,
we want to gather the data necessary
to come to a conclusion at the end.
Now, there are lots of inventories of
the types of data you could gather, but
here's one useful list.
One, who are the users?
What are their ages, genders,
levels of expertise?
Two, where are the users?
What is there environment?
Number three,
what is the context of the task?
What else is competing for
users' attention?
Four, what are their goals?
What are they trying to accomplish?
Five, right now, what do they need?
What are the physical objects?
What information do they need?
What collaborators do they need?
Six, what are their tasks?
What are they doing physically,
cognitively, socially?
And seven, what are the subtasks?
How do they accomplish those subtasks?
When you're designing your
need finding methods,
each thing you do should match up
with one or more of these questions.