Just as we want to get an idea of the physical space of the problem,
we also want to get an idea of the space of the user.
In other words, we want to understand who we're designing for.
That comes up a lot when doing design alternatives and prototyping,
but we also want to make sure to gather information about
the full range of users for whom we're designing.
So, let's take the example of designing an audiobook app for people that exercise.
Am I interested in audiobooks just for kids or for adults too?
Am I interested in experts who are exercising or novices at it?
Am I interested in experts listening to audiobooks?
Or am I interested in novices at that as well?
Those are pretty key questions.
They differentiate whether I'm designing for business people who want to be able to
exercise while reading or
exercisers who want to be able to do something else while exercising.
The task is similar for both,
but the audience, their motivations,
and their needs are different.
So, I need to identify these different types of users and
perform need-finding exercises on all of them.
One of the most successful products of all times
exceeded because of the tension to user types.
The Sony Walkman became such a dramatic success because
they identified different needs for different types of people,
design their product in a way that it met all those needs,
but then they marketed specifically to those different types of individuals.
You can read more about that in a book called
Doing Cultural Studies by Hugh Mackay and Linda Janes.