During need-finding, there are some significant considerations that
need to be made to avoid biasing your results.
Let's go through five of these possible biases.
Number one, confirmation bias.
Confirmation bias is the phenomenon where we see what we want to see.
We enter with some preconceived ideas of what we'll see and
we only notice the things that confirm our prior beliefs.
Try to avoid this by specifically looking for signs that you're wrong,
by testing your beliefs empirically,
and by involving multiple individuals in the need-finding process.
Number two, observer bias.
When we're interacting directly with users,
we may subconsciously bias them.
We might be more helpful, for example,
with users using the interface that we
designed compared to the ones that other people designed.
On surveys, we might accidentally phrase questions in
a way that elicits the answers that we want to hear.
Try to avoid this by separating experimenters with motives from the participants,
by heavily scripting interactions with users,
and by having someone else review
your interview scripts and your surveys for leading questions.
Number three, social desirability bias.
People tend to be nice, people want to help.
If you're testing an interface and the participants
know that you're the designer of the interface,
they'll want to say something nice about it to make you happy,
but that gets in the way of getting good data.
Try to avoid this by hiding what the socially desirable response
is by conducting more naturalistic observations and by recording objective data.
Number four, voluntary response bias.
Studies have shown that people with stronger opinions are
more likely to respond to optional surveys.
You can see this often in online store reviews.
The most common responses are often fives and ones.
For us, that means if we prefer quantitative analysis on surveys,
we risk oversampling the more extreme views.
Avoid this by limiting how much of
the survey content is shown to users before they begin survey,
and by confirming any conclusions with other methods.
Number five, Recall bias.
Studies have also shown that people aren't always very good at recalling what they did,
what they thought or how they felt during an activity they completed in the past.
That can lead to misleading and incorrect data.
Try to avoid this by studying casks and contexts by having users think out
loud during activities or conducting interviews during the activity itself.
Now, these biases can be largely controlled also
by making sure to engage in multiple forms of need-finding.