For certain tasks, a great way for
us to understand the users
need is to simply watch.
A great way for
me to start understanding what it's like
to need an audiobook app for exercising
is to come somewhere where people are
exercising and just watch them exercise.
This is called naturalistic observation,
observing people in
their natural context.
So I'm fortunate that I actually live
across the street from a park, so
I can sit here in my rocking chair on my
porch and just watch people exercising.
Now, I want to start with very
specific observations and
then generalize out to
more abstract tasks.
That way I'll observe something
called confirmation bias which is
basically when you see what you
want to see, so what do I notice?
Well, I notice that there's a lot
of different types of exercisers.
There are walkers, joggers,
runners I see some rollerbladers,
I see some people doing yoga.
I see a lot of people riding bikes but
the bikers seem to be broken into
two different kinds of groups.
I see a lot of people biking
kind of leisurely but
I also see some bikers who are a little
bit more strenuous about it.
I'm also noticing that while
joggers might be able to stop and
start pretty quickly, that's harder for
someone riding a bike.
So I might want to avoid
designs that force the user to
pull out their phone a lot because
that's going to be dangerous and
awkward for people riding bikes.
Now I also see people
exercising in groups and
also people exercising individually.
For those people exercising in groups,
I don't actually know if
they'd be interested in this.
Listening to something might
kind of defeat the purpose of
exercising together.
So I'm going to have to note that
down as a question I want to ask
people later.
I also see that many people
tend to stretch before and
after exercising and
I'm wondering if we can use that.
Then we can have some kind of starting
and ending sequence for this, so
that a single session is kind of
book ending by both stretching, and
interacting with our app.
Note that by just watching people
engage in the task of exercising,
I'm gathering an enormous amount of
information that might affect my design.
But note also, that while
naturalistic observation is great,
I'm limited ethically in what I can do.
I can't interact with users directly and
I can't capture identifying information
like videos and photographs that's why I
can't show you what I'm seeing out here.
I'm also limited in that I don't
know anything about what those users
are thinking.
I don't know if the people working
out in groups would want to be
able to listen to audiobooks
while they're doing yoga.
I don't know if bluetooth
headsets would be problematic for
people riding bike, I need to do a lot
more before I get to the design phase.
But this has been very informative in my
understanding of the problem space and
giving me things I can
ask people later on.