One of the biggest changes to computing over the past several years
has been the incredible growth of mobile as a computing platform.
We really live in a mobile first world,
and that introduces some significant design challenges.
Screen real estate is now far more limited.
The input methods are less precise,
and the user is distracted.
The mobile computing also presents some really big opportunities for HCI.
Thanks in large part to mobile,
we're no longer interested just in a person sitting in front of a computer.
With mobile phones, most people have a computer with them at all times anyway.
We can use that to support experiences from navigation to stargazing.
Mobile computing is deeply related to fields like context-aware computing,
ubiquitous computing, and augmented reality as it
possesses the hardware necessary to complement those efforts.
But even on its own, mobile computing presents some fascinating challenges to address.
For me, the big one is that we haven't yet reached a point where we can
use mobile phones for all the tasks we do on computers.
Smart phones are great for social networking,
personal organization, games, and lots of other things.
But we haven't yet reached a point where the majority of people would
sit down to write an essay or do some programming on smartphones.
Why haven't we? What do we need to do to make smart phones into
true replacements for traditional desktop and laptop computers?