If we're designing interfaces for
particularly complex tasks,
we might quickly find out that just
talking to our participants or
observing them really isn't enough to
get the understanding we need to design
those interfaces.
For particularly complex tasks,
we might need to become
experts ourselves in order
to design those programs.
This is informed by
the domain of ethnography,
which recommends
researching a community or
a job or anything like that,
by becoming a participant in it.
It goes beyond just
participant observation though,
it's really about integrating
oneself into that area and
becoming an expert in it and
learning about it as you go.
So we bring in our expertise and
design in HCI and use that combined with
the expertise that we develop to create
new interfaces for those people.
So for example, our video editors
here at Udacity have an incredible
incredibly complex workflow involving
multiple programs, multiple workflows,
lots of different people and
lots of moving parts.
There's no possible way I could
ever sit down with someone for
just an hour and get a good enough
picture of what they do, to design
a new interface that will help them out,
I really need to train under them.
I really need to become
an expert at video editing and
recording myself,
in order to help them out.
It's kind of like
an apprenticeship approach.
They would apprentice
me in their field and
I would use the knowledge that I gain to
design new interfaces to help them out.
So ethnography and apprenticeship
are huge fields of research
both on their own and
as they apply to HCI.
So if you're interested
in using that approach
take a look at some of
the resources that we're providing.