Personally, I think three of
these are good questions.
Do you exercise, is not a great
question, because it's kind of a yes or
no question.
How often do you exercise,
is actually the better way
of asking the same question.
It's subsumes all the answers to do
you exercise, but leaves more room for
elaboration or more room for detail.
Do you exercise for health or for
pleasure, is not a great question,
because it presents to
the user a dichotomy.
It might not be the way they
actually think about the problem.
Maybe there's some other
reason they exercise.
Maybe they do it to be social,
for example.
We want to leave open all
the possibilities a user might have.
So instead of asking,
do you exercise for health or
for pleasure, we probably want to ask,
why do you exercise?
The next two questions work pretty well,
because they leave plenty of room for
the participant to have
a wide range of answers, and
they're not leading them
towards any particular answer.
We're not asking, for example,
what smartphone do you use to listen to
something, because maybe
they don't use a smartphone.
This sixth one is interesting.
We're developing an app for listening
to audiobooks while exercising.
Would that be interesting to you?
What's wrong with that question?
When we say, we're developing an app,
we introduce something called
social desirability bias.
Because we're the ones
developing the app,
the user is going to feel some pressure
to agree with us, to support our ideas.
People like to support one another.
And so even if they wouldn't
be interested, they'll likely
say that they would, because that's
the supportive thing to say.
No one wants to say, hey, great idea,
David, but I would never use it.
So what we want to make sure to
do is create no incentive for
a user to not give us the complete,
honest answer.
Worrying about hurting our
feelings is one reason
why they wouldn't be totally honest.
So we might reword this question just to
say, would you be interested in an app
for listening to audiobooks
while exercising?
Now granted, the fact that we're the
ones asking still probably will tip off
the user that we're probably thinking
about moving in that direction, but
at least it's going to be
a little more collaborative.
We're not tipping them off that
we're already planning to do this,
we're telling them that we might
be thinking about doing it.
And so if they don't think it's a good
idea, they kind of feel like they should
tell us right now,
to save us time down the road.
So by rephrasing the question that way,
we hopefully,
avoid biasing the participant to
just agree with us to be nice.