Survey design is a well documented art form.
In fact, designing surveys is very similar to designing interfaces themselves.
So, many of the lessons we've learned in our conversations apply here as well.
Here are five quick tips for designing and administering effective surveys.
Number one, less is more.
The biggest mistake that I see novice survey designers make is to ask way too much.
That affects the response rate and the reliability of the data.
Ask the minimum number of questions necessary to get the data that you need,
and only ask questions that you know that you'll use.
Number two, be aware of bias.
Look at how you're phrasing the questions.
Are there positive or negative connotations?
Are participants implicitly pressured to answer one way or the other?
Number three, tie them to the inventory.
Make sure every question on
your survey connects to some of the data that you want to gather.
Start with the goals for the survey and write the questions from there.
Number four, test it out.
Before sending it to real participants,
have your co-workers or colleagues test out your survey.
Pretend they're real users and see if you would
get the data you need from their responses.
Number five, iterate.
Survey design is like interface design.
Test out your survey, see what works and what doesn't,
and revise it accordingly.
Give participants a chance to give feedback on the survey
itself so that you can improve it for future iterations.