Writing survey questions is an art,
as well as a science.
So let's take a look at an intentionally
poorly designed survey, and
see everything we can find
that's wrong with it.
So on the left is a survey.
It's kind of short,
mostly because of screen real estate.
Write down in the box on the right
everything that is wrong with
this survey.
Feel free to skip forward if you
don't want to listen to me read
out the questions.
On a scale of 1 to 4
with 1 meaning a lot and
4 meaning not at all,
how much do you enjoy exercising?
Why do you like to exercise?
On a scale of 1 to 6 with
1 meaning not at all and
6 meaning a lot,
how much do you like audiobooks?
Have you listened to
an audiobook this year?