Here are a few of the problems that
I intentionally put into this survey.
Some of them are kind of obvious, but
hopefully a couple others were a little
bit more subtle and
a little bit more interesting.
First when I say on a scale of one
to four with one meaning a lot and
four meaning not at all,
what do two and three mean exactly?
It's not a very clear scale
to just say the endpoint.
Just giving the endpoints
doesn't give a very clear scale.
We usually also want to provide
an odd number of options, so
that users have kind of
a neutral central option.
Sometimes we'll want to force our
participants to take one side or
the other, but generally we want to
give them that middle neutral option.
Either way though, we definitely don't
want to change the number of options
between those two questions.
Having one be 1 to 4 and
the other be 1 to 6 is just confusing.
And even worse, notice that we're
reversing the scale between these two.
In the first question,
the low number means a lot.
In the second question,
the high number means a lot.
That's just terrible design.
We want to be consistent
across our entire survey,
both with the direction of our scale and
the number of options unless
there's a compelling reason not to.
The second question is also guilty
of being quite a leading question.
Why do you like to exercise assumes
the participant likes to exercise.
What are they supposed
to say if they don't?
And finally, the last question
is a yes or no question.
Have you listened to
an audiobook this year?
Yes or no.
No is kind of an interesting answer,
but yes, I don't know if you
listened to one audiobook this year or
a 100 audiobooks this year.
I don't know if you listened
every single day or
if you just listened once because
you had a gift certificate.
So we want to reword this question
to be a little more open-ended and
support a wider range
of participant answers.