In this lesson we've covered a wide
variety of different methods for
need finding.
Each method has its own
disadvantages and advantages.
So let's start to wrap up the lesson
by exploring this with an exercise.
Here are the methods we've covered,
and here are the potential advantages.
For each row, for each advantage,
mark which need-finding method
actually has that advantage.
Note that these might be
somewhat relative, so
your answer may differ from ours.
Go ahead and skip to the exercise
if you don't want to listen to me
read these out.
The columns from left to right
are Naturalistic Observation,
Participant Observation,
Errors and Hacks, Interviews,
Surveys, Focus Groups,
Apprenticeship, and Think-Aloud.
The potential advantages are Analyzes
data that already exists,
Requires no recruitment,
Requires no synchronous participation,
Investigates the participant's thoughts,
occurs within the task context, and
cheaply gathers lots of users' data.