Here's my answer to this
very complicated exercise.
Two methods that analyze
data that already exists
are Naturalistic Observation and
Errors and Hacks.
Naturalistic Observation doesn't
necessarily analyze data that
already exists, but
it analyzes data that's being produced
already on its own without observing it,
so we don't have to go out and create
an opportunity for data to happen.
We just have to observe it and capture
it where it's already taking place.
Errors and Hacks, look at the way users
already use interfaces to see what
errors they regularly make or when they
have to work around the interface.
The two methods that require no
recruitment are Naturalistic Observation
and Participant Observation.
In both cases, we don't need
other human participants to
come do anything differently based on
the fact that we're doing some research.
With interviews, surveys, Focus Groups,
apprenticeship and Think-Aloud, we're
always asking users to do something to
accommodate us or to give us some data.
And with Errors and Hacks, even if
we can view that data on our own,
we still need the user to give us
permission to view their workspace or
watch them do whatever they're doing.
There might be some times when
you can look for Errors and
Hacks with Naturalistic Observation,
but generally you need to get
enough into the users head to
understand why something's an error or
why they need to use a certain hack.
For the most part,
all of these are going to need
some synchronous participation.
There might be some exceptions.
For example, we could do a retrospective
analysis of Errors and Hacks, or
we can have someone do a Think-Aloud
protocol where they actually write down
their thoughts after doing a task.
But generally speaking,
the way most of these are usually done,
they require synchronous participation.
Surveys are the exception.
Surveys we usually send out to someone,
wait some period of time,
and get back the results.
So we never have to be interacting
live with any of our participants.
That's one of the reasons why
surveys can get a lot more
data than other methods.
Adding more participants doesn't
necessarily require more of our time,
at least not to gather
the data in the first place.
Analyzing it might require
more time at the end, but
that's not synchronous either.
As far as investigating
participant thoughts is concerned,
almost all these methods can
investigate this when used correctly.
We could do a survey does not actually
investigate participants thoughts, but
a well designed survey is going to
trying get a heart of the users thinks
about things.
The only exception is Naturalistic
Observation where by definition,
we're just watching people we're
not interacting with them or
we're not asking them
what they are thinking.
It's always extremely valuable for us
to be able to do some needfinding that
occurs within the task context itself.
And unfortunately interviews and
surveys,
which are some of our most
common data gathering methods,
very often don't occur
within the task context.
Naturalistic Observation and Participant
Observation obviously do, but
since they don't involved getting
inside the real users head,
their contributions
are a little bit more limited.
Apprenticeship and Think-Aloud really
capture the benefits of occurring within
the task context, because either
way we get the user's thoughts
while they're engaging with the task,
or immediately thereafter.
It is possible to do interviews and
Focus Groups within the task contexts
as well, it just isn't quite as common.
Errors and Hacks are certainly debatable
as well, because the Errors and
Hacks themselves definitely occur
within the task context, but
our analysis of them usually doesn't.
And finally, as we talk about when
we discuss cognitive task analysis,
one of the challenges with needfinding
is that most of our approaches
are extremely expensive.
If we want to gather
a lot of data cheaply,
then we probably need
to rely on surveys.
Everything else is either going to
incur a pretty significant cost or
it just isn't capable of
gathering a lot of data.
For example, we could cheaply
be participant observations for
weeks on end, but
we're only ever going to gather data
from one person and that's never ideal.