We could apply pretty much every single
need-finding method that we've discussed
to this task.
We could, for example, go to the library
and just watch people reading and
see how they're taking notes.
We've all likely done it ourselves.
We can reflect on what we do
while reading, although again,
we need to be careful not to over-value
our own priorities and approaches.
Reading is common enough,
that we can easily find participants for
interviews, surveys, think alouds.
The challenge here will be
deciding who our users really are.
Books are ubiquitous.
Are we trying to cater to
everyone who reads deliberately?
If so, we need to sample a wide
range of users or initially,
we could choose a subset.
We might cater to students who
are studying or busy business people, or
people that specifically walk or
bike to work.
We might start with one of those groups
and then abstract out over time.
We might eventually abstract all the way
to just anyone who's unable to read and
take notes the traditional way
like people driving cars or
people with visual impairments but
that's further down the road.
The more important thing is
that we define who our user is,
define the task in which we're
interested, and deliberately design for
that user and that task through
out the design life cycle.