As this course goes, on you'll find that I'm on camera more
often than you might be accustomed to seeing any udacity course.
Around half this course actually takes place with me on camera,
there are a couple of reasons for that.
The big one is that this is human-computer interaction,
so it makes sense to put a strong emphasis on the human.
But another big one is that when I'm on camera I can express myself
through gestures instead of just through words and voice intonations.
I can, for example, make a fist and really drive home and emphasize a point.
I can explain that a topic applies to
a very narrow portion of the field or a very wide portion of the field.
We communicate naturally with gestures every day.
In fact, we even have an entire language built out of gestures.
So, wouldn't it be great if our computers can interpret our gestures as well?
That's the emerging field of gesture-based interaction.
You've seen this with things like the Microsoft Kinect which
has far-ranging applications from health care to gaming.
We've started to see some applications of gesture-based interaction on the go
as well with wristbands that react to certain hand motions.
Gesture-based interaction has enormous potential.
The fingers have some of the finest muscle movements,
meaning that a system based on
finger movements could support an incredible number of interactions.
We might see a day when it's possible to type invisibly in the air in front
of you based on the system's recognition to the movement of the muscles in your wrist.
That might finally allow mobile devices to despise traditional computers altogether.