During these need-finding exercises,
you'll have gathered an enormous amount
of information about your users.
Ideally, you've combined different
sets of these approaches.
You've observed people
performing the tasks,
you've asked them about their thought
process, and you tried it some yourself.
Pay special attention to some of the
places where the data seem to conflict.
Are these cases where you as
the designer understand some elements of
the task that the users don't?
Or are these cases where your expertise
hasn't quite developed to the point of
understanding the task?
Once you've gone through
the data gathering process,
it's time to revisit that inventory of
things we wanted to gather initially.
One, who are the users?
Two, where are the users?
Three, what is the context of the task?
Four, what are their goals?
Five, right now, what do they need?
Six, what are their tasks?
And seven, what are the subtasks?
Revisit these, with the results
of your data gathering in mind.