Now that you have some understanding of the user's needs,
it's time to try to formalize that into something we can use in design.
There are a number of different ways we can do this.
For example, maybe we create
a step-by-step task outline of the user engaging in some task.
We can break those tasks down into sub-tasks as well,
all the way down to the operator level.
We can further develop this kind of task outline into a hierarchical network,
like we talked about before.
This might involve more complexity than simply a linear series of actions.
We might further augment this with a diagram of
the structural relationships amongst the components in the system and how they interact.
This might give us some information about how we get feedback back to
the user or how they interact with our interface in the first place.
From there, we might develop as even more into
a flowchart equipped with decision-making points or points of interruptions.
Notice how these representations are very similar to the outcomes of
the task analyses and we talk about in the principles unit of our conversations.
We can similarly use the data gathered from here to summarize
a more comprehensive task analysis that will be
useful in designing and prototyping our designs.