Today, we've talked about needfinding.
Needfinding is how you develop your understanding of the needs of your user,
what tasks are they completing,
what is the context of those tasks, what else is going on,
what are they thinking during the task,
and what did they have to hold in working memory.
All these things feed into your understanding of your users' needs.
We've discussed a number of different techniques to approach this,
ranging from low intervention to high intervention.
On the low side, we can just observe our users in the wild
or we can become users ourselves and participate in the task.
Working up, when you try to look at more closely at users areas to
find errors or hacks or perused the data that they're already generating,
we might interact with them directly through surveys,
interviews, or focus groups,
or we might choose to work alongside them,
not just participating in the task independently,
but learning from them and developing expertise itself.
Once you've gained the efficient understanding,
it's time to move on to the next step, brainstorming design alternatives.