[MUSIC].
When we've developed a good
understanding of the needs of our user,
it's time to move on to the second
phase of the design life cycle,
design alternatives.
This is when we start to brainstorm
how to accomplish the task we've been
investigating.
The problem here is that design is very
hard, it's hard for a number of reasons.
The number of choices we have to make,
and
things we have to control is
more expansive than ever before.
Are we designing for desktops,
laptops, tablets, smart phones,
smart watches, augmented reality,
virtual reality, 2D, 3D,
gesture input, pen input, keyboard
input, mouse input, voice input?
In this lesson, we're going to talk
about how to generate ideas for designs.
And then we'll chat about how to
explore those ideas a bit further
to figure out what you
want to actually pursue.