When we talk about the problem we're
solving here we define the problem space
as disabling a security
system as we enter a home.
We defined our problem as
far as possible away from
the current interfaces for doing it.
The design space on
the other hand is the area
in which we design our
solutions to this problem.
The current design space for
this problem is wall mounted devices and
portable devices like my key chain.
But as we design, the space of
possible ideas might expand.
For example, as we go along we might
be interested in voice interfaces or
interfaces with our mobile phones or
wearable devices.
Our goal during the design alternative
phase is to explore the possible design
space.
We don't want to narrow down too
early by sticking devices on walls or
devices on keychains.
We want to brainstorm lots
of possible approaches, and
grow a large space of possible designs.