So, I'm going to demonstrate this for you real quick.
I'm going to brainstorm ideas for our problem of
allowing exercisers to consume books and take notes.
So, my paper for brainstorming.
So, please enjoy this 30-minute video of me sitting here writing at a desk.
Here's my list of ideas.
As you might be able to tell it gets kind of crazy,
it's all over the place.
You can kind of trace through my entire reasoning process on here.
So, some of the ideas are somewhat straightforward.
I've got voice commands,
I've got gestures, I've got voice transcription.
I tried to separate it out into feedback methods and also the way
the user actually interacts because we could kind of combine those.
Some of these are actually pretty crazy.
I've got on skin interface.
So, I've seen some prototypes for things that would let you actually just press on
your skin to do different kinds of interactions.
I've also got augmented reality like Google Glass.
I've got a portable keyboard like twiddler.
So, notice that this is kind of a mess. That's a good thing.
Lists are fine but chances are a lot of your ideas are related to each other.
Notice also that I never crumpled up my piece of paper, I never throw it away.
I crossed one thing out. That's because I wrote the wrong word.
Really at this stage, you don't want to reject any ideas.
Your goal is just to kind of free-form brainstorm and get all your thoughts out there.