The brainstorming process
should lead you to a list of
bunch of high level general
design alternatives.
These are likely just a few words or
a sentence each but
they described some very general idea
of how you might design the interface,
to accomplish this task.
Your next step is to try to flush
these ideas out into three or
four ideas that are worth taking
forward to the prototyping stage.
Some of the ideas you might be
able to dismiss pretty quickly,
that's all right.
You can't generate good ideas
without generating a lot of ideas.
Even though you won't end
up using all of them.
In other places, you might explore
an idea a little before dismissing it or
you might combine two
ideas into a new idea.
In the rest of this lesson,
we'll give you some thought experiments
you can use to evaluate these ideas and
decide what to keep,
what to combine and what to dismiss.