Design alternatives are where you explore different ways to facilitate the users task.
If you've already chosen to focus on a certain area of technology
like wearable devices or gestural interaction,
then in some ways you've put the cart before the horse.
You've chosen your design before exploring the problem.
As a learning experience though, that's perfectly fine.
It's fine to say, I want to explore
augmented reality and I'm going to find a task that lets me do that.
You're still exploring whether or
not augmented reality is the right solution for that task.
You're just altering the task if not,
instead of altering the design, if not.
For other domains, you might need to make sure to create personas
for different stakeholders in health care for instance.
You would want to make sure any interface you design takes into consideration nurses,
doctors, patients, managers, family members, and more.
So, do you want to create personas for all those different types of people as
well and make sure to explore scenarios that affect each stakeholder.