Prototyping is largely about the trade-offs we have to make.
Low-fidelity prototypes like drawings are easy to create and modify,
but they aren't as effective for detailed comprehensive evaluations.
High-fidelity prototypes like actual working interfaces
can be used for detailed feedback and evaluation,
but they're difficult to actually put together.
So, our goal is to maximize these trade-offs.
We want to start with the easier low-fidelity prototypes to get
initial ideas to evaluate big designs
and big plans and to make sure we're on the right track.
Then as we go along,
we can move towards the higher-fidelity prototypes to take more time to
assemble because we have initial evidence that our designs are actually sound.
It's really important here also to note that our prototypes are prototypes.
They aren't complete interfaces.
We've discussed in the past that designers often have a tendency
to jump straight to designing rather than getting to know their users.
That's a big risk here as well because we're designing,
but we're designing specifically to get more feedback.
So, don't become a runaway train of designing.
Designed deliberately and get feedback often.