Here are five quick tips for effective prototyping.
Number 1, keep prototypes easy to change.
Your goal here is to enable rapid revision and improvement.
It's easy to make quick changes to something on paper,
but it's harder to make it a code or physical prototypes.
Number 2, make it clear that it's a prototype.
If you make a prototype look too good,
users may focus on superficial elements like colors or font.
By letting your prototype look like a prototype,
you can help them focus on what you're ready to test.
Number 3, be creative.
Your goal is to get feedback.
Do whatever it takes to get feedback.
Don't let the type of prototype you're designing
constrain the kind of feedback you can get.
If you find your current prototypes don't give you
the right kind of feedback, find ones that do.
Number 4, evaluate risks.
One of the biggest goals of prototyping is to minimize the time spent
pursuing bad designs by getting feedback on them early.
How much would you lose if you found that users hate
the parts of your design that they haven't seen yet?
Whenever that answer gets to be longer than a couple hours,
try to get feedback to make sure you're not wasting time.
Number 5, prototype for feedback.
The goal of a prototype is to get feedback.
You could spend a lot of time focusing on details like font selection and color choice,
I know I do, but that's probably not the feedback
you need when you're exploring your big alternatives.
Prototype for the kind of feedback you want to get.