At the very simplest, we have verbal prototypes.
That means we're literally just describing the design we have in mind to our user.
That's probably the lowest fidelity prototype possible.
It's literally just telling the user the same thing we tell our co-designers.
So, it's extremely easy to do,
although it can be hard to do effectively.
Social desirability bias is big here because it's difficult to describe
our idea in a way that allows the participant to feel comfortable disagreeing with us.
So, we need to make sure to ask for specific and critical feedback.
At the same time though, how do we really
know that the user understands the design we're describing?
We're working toward becoming experts in the areas which we're designing,
and we don't want to fall victim to extra blind spot
by assuming our explanation makes sense to a novice.
For that reason, analogies can be powerful tools for explaining prototypes.
Describe your interface in terms of other tools a user might already know about.
So, for example, imagine I was pitching the idea of Instacart,
a grocery delivery company.
I might have described it like it's like Uber for groceries.
Uber is a service like taxis,
and Instacart is like a taxi for groceries.
That way of describing it in terms of an analogy to another interface can be
a powerful way of helping your participant understand your idea more quickly.