So here are my answers.
First when we're talking about things
that are revisable during interaction,
we're talking about things that
I as the experimenter can get
feedback from my user and
immediately change my prototype.
So if they say that that button
label doesn't really makes sense,
I can cross out that button label and
immediately change it.
That makes sense for
prototypes that are very low fidelity.
Verbal prototypes,
I can immediately say okay,
then let's make it the way
you just described.
Paper prototypes or card prototypes,
I could quickly erase or
cross out something on my prototype and
change it.
Wizard of Oz is similar.
Since I'm running what's
going on behind the scenes,
I can just change
the way I'm running it.
Those four prototypes,
because they're more low fidelity,
also disguises superficial details.
No one is going to look at
a prototype that I drew by hand and
say they don't like the font.
No one is going to to listen to me
run a Wizard of Oz prototype for
a voice interface and say, I don't
like the voice that you're using.
These help us focus on the overall
patterns of interaction and
disguise some of the superficial
elements that users would often have
a tendency to get distracted by.
However, as we prototype,
we need to move from designing
interfaces to designing interactions.
Verbal prototypes and paper prototypes
don't really cover interactions,
they cover showing something and
asking the user what they think,
but they don't really
go further than that.
Card prototypes,
Wizard of Oz prototypes, to a certain
extent wireframing and to a certain
extent physical prototypes all let us
actually simulate the user interaction.
With a card prototype,
we're actually saying if you did that,
then you would see this, so they can
walk through the pattern of interaction.
Wizard of Oz,
we can simply call out or describe or
simulate, this is what would happen
if you do what you just described.
Now, wifeframing you could do more like
a paper prototype, where it's just
a simple wire frame, but more generally,
we use wire frames when we're ready to
actually show different interfaces and
the movement between them.
Similarly with physical prototypes,
the main reason why we would do
a physical prototype is to hand a user,
and say, pretend you're jogging, or
pretend you're working in your office.
How would this interact with
what you're actually doing?
We're simulating the way they
would physically use it.
Now among all of these, the wires frames
are really the ones that are most
easily distributable to remote users.
You can make an argument that we can
send scans for a paper prototypes but
generally, a paper prototype
isn't just about what's on paper.
It's also about the conversations and
descriptions that we're having around it
and asking users what they
think about certain elements.
Whereas a wire frame is more about
a general impression that users get.
You can make the argument that paper
prototypes can be sent easily, as well.
But for me, I would only share
wire frames with remote users.
Now prototyping look and feel is really
just the inverse of disguise and
superficial details.
Look and feel is really about those
superficial elements that have
a significant user impact, but are more
easily modifiable within an overall
pattern of functional interaction.
So just as the earlier low fidelity
prototypes support disguising details,
the later ones support
prototyping look and feel.
As computers become more ubiquitous, and
users are moving around while
interacting with interfaces more and
more, allowing mobility
is really valuable.
Wizard of Oz, since we're just
calling things out to the user,
let them move around, and
same with physical prototypes.
We can actually hand them to a user and
have them physically interact,
the way they would with
the actual interface