At this point,
there's a risk of a major misconception
that we should cut off right now.
We started with need finding, then
develop some design alternatives, and
now we're prototyping.
We've talked about how prototyping
follows a timeline to low fidelity
to high fidelity prototypes,
from early to late prototyping.
We might think that we move on to
evaluation when we're done prototyping.
That's not the way the design
life cycle works though.
We go through this cycle several
times for a single design and
a single prototype corresponds to
a single iteration through the cycle.
So we did some initial needfinding,
we brainstormed some alternatives, and
we prototyped those
alternatives on paper.
We don't jump straight from doing them
on paper to doing them via wire framing
or doing a functional prototype.
We take those prototypes and
we use them for evaluation.
We evaluate those paper
prototypes with real people.
The results of that evaluation
tell us if we need to go back and
understand the task even better.
Those results help us reflect
on our alternatives as a whole,
maybe come up with some new ones.
Then, equipped with the results of that
evaluation, that additional needfinding,
and that additional brainstorming,
we return to the prototyping phase.
If our prototype seemed to
be pretty successful and
pretty sound, then maybe it's
time to raise the fidelity of it.
Maybe we take it from a paper prototype
and actually do some wire frames, or
do a car prototype around
the actual interaction.
If it wasn't very successful though,
when we reach back here, we're going
to do a different paper prototype, or
a different low fidelity prototype,
and then go to evaluation again.
Each time we develop a new prototype
we go through the same cycle again.
Now that might sound extremely slow and
deliberate but we also go through this
on a very different time scales too.
So for example,
after we've gone through needfinding and
designing alternative brainstorming,
we can develop a paper prototype.
We give it to a user and
get their evaluation.
They say that they don't like it.
We ask them why,
we ask them to describe what about their
task isn't supported by that interface.
That's in some ways
another needfinding stage.
Then we brainstorm real quick
how we could resolve that.
Maybe we just do that while
we're sitting with that user and
think it didn't support this element
of what they described, but I could add
that pretty quickly just by making this
button or this function more visible.
Now we very quickly have a new
prototyping just by sketching out that
addition to that paper prototype and
now we can do it again.
This cycle could take one minute.
We could take one prototype, put it in
front of a user, get their evaluation,
figure out what they liked and didn't
like, brainstorm a way to fix that, and
then immediately revise it and
try it again.
We can go through this very,
very quickly.
We could also go through
this very slowly,
we could have prototypes
that take months to develop.
And generally that's why we only want
to do that after we've gone through
the cycle a few times.
Because if we're going to take months
to develop a prototype, we want to
make sure we're probably going to get
some pretty good evaluations on it.
And we can make sure of that by
prototyping the elements in lower
fidelity first.