There's one other misconception
that I've seen in some designers
I've worked with that I feel is also
worth explicitly acknowledging.
All your prototypes don't have to be
at the same level, at the same time.
Take Facebook for example.
Facebook is a complete
app already implemented.
Imagine that Facebook wanted to
redesign their status update box, which
they've done pretty recently and have
probably done since I recorded this.
Just because the interface is complete
in other ways doesn't mean that
all future prototyping efforts need
to be similarly high fidelity.
They don't need to implement an entire
new status composition screen
just to prototype it.
They can prototype it in lower fidelity
with sketches, or wire frames, put that
in front of users, get their feedback,
before ever actually implementing it
into a functional prototype or
a working part of the website.
This applies particularly
strongly to the design of apps or
programs with multiple functions.
So take something like the LinkedIn app.
It has a number of different functions
like editing your own profile, or
connecting with others, or
browsing your news feed.
Each of these individual screens
has its own tasks and interactions.
And moving amongst them, is itself
a task or a type of interaction.
Trying to design all the screens and
the transitions among them all at
the same time is likely far too much.
So we could take the bottom-up approach,
where we would design the individual
screens first, and then design
the app experience as a whole.
Or we might take
the top-down approach and
design the overall experience of moving
between these different screens, and
then design the contents
of the individual screens.
The point of this is that at any time,
protoyping can and
should exist at multiple
levels of fidelity.