Social computing is the portion of HCI that's interested
in how computers affect the way we interact and socialize.
One thing that falls under this umbrella,
is the idea of re-creating social norms within computational systems.
So, for example, when you chat online,
you might often use emojis or emoticons.
Those are virtual re-creations of some of
the tacit interaction we have with each other on a day-to-day basis.
So, for example, these all take on different meanings depending on the emotion provided.
Social computing is interested in a lot more than just emojis, of course,
from online gaming and Wikipedia to social media to dating websites.
Social computing is really interested in all areas,
where computing intersects with our social lives.