[MUSIC]
The heart of user-centered
design is getting
frequent feedback from the users.
That's where evaluation comes into play.
Evaluation is where we take
what we've designed and
put it in front of users
to get their feedback.
But just as different prototypes serve
different functions at different stages
of the design process,
so also our methods for
evaluation need to match as well.
Early on,
we want more qualitative feedback.
We want to know what they like, what
they don't like, whether it's readable,
whether it's understandable.
Later on,
we want to know if it's usable.
Does it actually minimize your workload?
Is it intuitive?
Is it easy to learn?
Then at the end, we might want to
know something more quantitative.
We might want to actually measure, for
example, whether the time to complete
a task has changed, or whether
the number of sales has increased.
Along the way, we might also want
to iterate even more quickly
by predicting what the results
of user evaluation will be.
The type of evaluation we
employ is tightly related to
where we are in our design process.
So in this lesson,
we'll discuss the different methods for
performing evaluation to get
the feedback we need when we need it.