In designing evaluations, it's critical that we define what we're evaluating.
Without that, we generally tend to bottom out
in vague assessments about whether or not users like our interface.
So, here are five quick tips on what you might choose to evaluate.
Number one, efficiency.
How long does it take users to accomplish certain tasks?
That's one of the classic metrics for evaluating interfaces.
Can one interface accomplish a task in pure actions or in less time than another?
You might test this with predictive models or you might
actually time users in completing these tasks.
Still though, this paints a pretty narrow picture of usability.
Number two, accuracy.
How many errors do users commit while accomplishing a task?
That's typically a pretty empirical question
although we can address it qualitatively as well.
Ideally, we want an interface that reduces
the number of errors a user commits while performing a task.
Both efficiency and accuracy, however,
examined the narrow setting of an expert user using an interface.
So, that brings us to our next metric.
Number three, learnability.
Sit under user down in front of the interface.
Define some standard for expertise.
How long does it take the user to hit that level of expertise?
Expertise here might range from performing
a particular action to something like creating an entire document.
Number four, memorability.
Similar to learnability,
memorability refers to the user's ability to remember how to use an interface over time.
Imagine you have a user alone in an interface,
then leave and come back a week later.
How much do they remember?
Ideally, you want interfaces that need only be learned once,
which means high memorability.
Number five, satisfaction.
When we forget to look at our other metrics,
we bought them out in a general notion of satisfaction.
But that doesn't mean it's unimportant.
We do need to operationalize it though.
Experience is things like uses enjoyment of
the system or the cognitive load they experience while using the system.
To avoid social desirability bias,
we might want to evaluate this in creative ways like finding out,
how many participants actually download an app they tested after the session is over?
Regardless of what you choose to evaluate,
it's important that you very clearly articulate at the beginning,
what you're evaluating, what data you're gathering,
and what analysis you will use.
These three things should match up to address your research questions.