When we discussed prototyping,
we talked about how over time
the nature of our prototypes
get higher and higher fidelity.
Something similar
happens with evaluation.
Over time, the evaluation
method we'll use will change.
Throughout most of our design process
our evaluations are formative.
Meaning their primary purpose is to help
us redesign and improve our interface.
At the end, though, we might want
to do something more summative to
conclude the design process,
especially if we want to demonstrate
that the new interface is better.
Formative evaluation is
evaluation with the intention of
improving the interface going forward.
Summative is with the intention
of conclusively saying at the end
what the difference was.
In reality, hopefully we never
do summative evaluation.
Hopefully our evaluations
are always with the purpose
of revising our interface and
making it better over time.
But in practice, there might come times
when you need to demonstrate a very
clear quantitative difference.
And because of this difference,
our early evaluations tend
to be more qualitative.
Qualitative evaluations tend to be
more interpretative and informal.
Their goal is to help us improve or
understand the task.
Our later evaluations are likely more
empirical, controlled, and formal.
Their goal is to demonstrate or
assess change.
So while formative evaluation and
summative evaluation were
the purposes of our evaluations,
qualitative evaluations and
empirical evaluations are ways to
actually fulfill those purposes.
Predictive evaluation is
a little outside the spectrum,
so we'll talk about that as well.
As far as this is concerned,
predictive evaluations tend to be very
similar to qualitative evaluations.
They inform how we revise and
improve our interfaces over time.
These three categories actually form
the bulk of what we'll talk about
in this lesson.
Recall also that earlier we talked about
the difference between qualitative and
quantitative data.
As you've probably realized,
if qualitative evaluation occurs early,
an empirical evaluation occurs late.
And chances are, we're using
qualitative data more early, and
quantitative data more late.
In reality, qualitative data is really
always useful to improve our interfaces,
whereas quantitative data,
while always useful,
really can only arise when we
have pretty rigorous evaluations.
And then one last area we can look at
is where the evaluation takes place.
In a controlled lab setting or
actually out in the field.
Generally when we're testing our
early low fidelity interfaces,
we probably want to do it in a lab
setting as opposed to out in the wild.
We want to bring participants into our
lab and actually describe what we're
going for, the rationale behind certain
decisions, and get their feedback.
Later on we might want to do real field
testing where we give users a somewhat
working prototype, or something
resembling a working prototype.
And they can actually reflect on it
as they go about their regular lives,
participating in whatever task that
interface is supposed to help with.
This helps us focus exclusively
on the interface early on, and
in transition to focusing on
the interface in context later.
But of course we want to also
think about the context early on.
We could for example, develop a very
navigation app that works great when we
test in our lab, because it demands
a very high cognitive load.
But doesn't work at all out in the field
because when participants are actually
driving, they can't spare that
cognitive load to focus on our app.
Now of course none of these are hard and
fast rules.
We'll very likely often do
qualitative evaluation late or
maybe do some field testing early.
But as general principles, this is
probably the order in which we want to
think about our different
evaluation styles.