Let's run through some of the questions you'll have to
answer in designing a qualitative evaluation.
First, is this based on prior experience,
or is it a live demonstration?
If you're bringing in users to answer questions about
some interface that they're already using regularly,
I'd probably argue you're actually doing need-finding.
Now, the distinction can be subtle because
evaluation does lead to additional need-finding,
but most of these questions are going to apply more to a live demonstration.
This is where you're bringing users in to test out some new interface for new prototype.
Second, is the session going to be synchronous or asynchronous?
In a synchronous session,
you're sitting and watching the user live.
You're actually watching them use this interface you use in this prototype.
If they're going to complete it on their own and just send you the results,
and then it's an asynchronous session.
Synchronous is usually beneficial because we see
a much greater amount of the interactions taking place.
We might also be able to interrupt the user and get their thoughts live.
Asynchronous, though is often much easier to carry out,
especially with larger populations.
I generally recommend synchronous whenever possible,
but asynchronous is certainly better than nothing.
Third, how many prototypes or how many interfaces will they be evaluating?
You might have users come in to evaluate only one interface,
or you might have them look at multiple prototypes to compare between them.
If you're having them look at more than one prototype,
you want to make sure to vary the order in which you present them, otherwise,
you might get consistently different feedback just because the user is
already familiar with the problem domain when they get to the second interface.
That can be particularly significant if you're trying out
some new interface compared to an interface that you've used in the past.
If you always present the old first,
then you'll probably get a lot of users saying the new one is much better,
when in reality, they're just more familiar with the problem now.
Fourth, when do you want to get feedback from the user?
There are two main protocols for doing this.
There's a Think Aloud Protocol and a Post-Event Protocol.
In a Think Aloud Protocol,
you ask the user to actually think out loud
while they're using your interface or prototype.
You ask him to explain what they're seeing and explain how they interpreted,
and explain what they think the outcome of their actions will be.
In a Post-Event Protocol,
you have the user go through some session
using the interface or testing out the prototype,
and then only giving you thoughts at the end.
A Post-Event Protocol has the drawback,
that you're only getting the user's feedback at the end.
So, if they experience some difficulty early on,
they may have forgotten it by the time you actually get feedback from them,
but a Think Aloud Protocol has a problem,
and then it might introduce some new biases.
Research shows that when users are asked to think out loud while using an interface,
the way they use the interface actually changes.
They're more deliberative. They're more thoughtful.
They're less intuitive about their interactions.
In general, what that means,
is that when we ask users to think out loud about an interface, oftentimes,
they'll figure out how the interface works, but then,
if users use the same interface without having to think out loud,
they find it much more confusing.
Talking through their thought process helps them understand,
but our real end-users aren't going to talk through their thought process,
so it's often good to use a mix of these two.
In fact, I'd usually suggest doing a Think Aloud Protocol earlier,
and using a Post-Event Protocol more as
a summative evaluation once you're already pretty confident in how good your interfaces,
but others advice may differ.
In either case, it's worth noting that users are not
often very good at explaining why they like something or why they did something,
so we should always take the feedback that we get with a grain of salt.
Finally, do you want to get feedback from individuals or from groups?
Focus groups are used when multiple users talk together about their experiences.
This can actually lead to better explanations,
because users build on each other and expand each other's ideas,
but it can also strongly biased the group
towards the opinions of the most powerful personalities.
Individual interviews and surveys force the user to be the only source of knowledge,
which can be bad, but it also means the user isn't biased by other outside views.
As you'll notice and has probably become a trend,
whenever we talk about multiple different options for
doing evaluation or need-finding or whatever,
different approaches have different strengths,
and they address the weaknesses of other approaches.
So, generally, if you're going through multiple iterations of the design life cycle,
you'll probably use all of these different ideas at different times.