With qualitative research,
we want to capture as much
of the session as possible.
Because things could come up
that we don't anticipate.
And we'd like to look
at them again later.
So how do we do that?
One way is to actually
record the session.
The pros of recording a session are that
it's automated, it's comprehensive, and
it's passive.
Automated means that it runs
automatically in the background.
Comprehensive means that it
captures everything that happens
during the session.
And passive means that it lets us
focus on administering the session
instead of capturing it.
The cons though,
are that it's intrusive, it's difficult
to analyze, and it's screenless.
Intrusive means that many participants
are uncomfortable being videotaped.
It creates oppression knowing
that every question or
every mistake is going to captured and
analyzed by researchers later.
Video is also very difficult to analyze.
It requires a person to come later and
watch every minute of video, usually
several times, in order to code and
pull out what was actually
relevant in that session.
And video recording often has difficulty
capturing interactions on-screen.
We can film what a person is doing
on a keyboard or with a mouse, but
it is difficult to then see how that
translates to on-screen actions.
Now some of these issues
can be resolved, of course.
We can do video capture on the screen
synchronize it with a video recording.
But if we're dealing with children,
or at risk populations, or
with some delicate subject matter,
the intrusiveness can be overwhelming.
And if we want to do a lot
of complex sessions,
the difficulty in analyzing that
data can also be overwhelming.
For my dissertation work I captured
about 200 hours of video, and
that's probably why it took
me an extra year to graduate.
It takes a lot of time to
go through all that video.
So instead we can also
focus on note-taking.
The benefits of note-taking are that
it's very cheap, it's not intrusive, and
it is analyzable.
It's cheap because we don't have to
buy expensive cameras or equipment,
we just have our pens and papers or
our laptops, or anything like that.
And can just do it using equipment
we already have available to us.
It's not intrusive, in that it only
captures what we decide to capture.
If a participant is uncomfortable asking
questions or makes a silly mistake with
the interface, we don't necessarily
have to capture that, and that can make
the participant feel a little bit
more comfortable being themselves.
And it's a lot easier to analyze notes.
You can scroll through and
read the notes on a one hour
session in only a few minutes.
But analyzing that same session in
video is certainly going to take at
least an hour, if not more,
to watch it more than once.
But but
of course there are draw backs too.
Taking those can be a very slow process,
meaning that we
can't keep up with the dynamic
interactions that we're evaluating.
It's also manual which means that
we actually have to focus on
actively taking notes, which gets in
the way of administering the session.
If you're going to use note taking,
you probably want to actually
have two people involved.
One person running the session,
and one person taking notes.
And finally,
it's limited in what it captures.
It might not capture
some of the movements or
the motions that a person does when
interacting with an interface.
It doesn't capture how long
they hesitate before deciding
what to do next.
We can write all that down of course,
but
we're going to run into the limitation
of how fast we can take notes.
It would be nearly impossible to
simultaneously take notes on what
questions the user is asking, how
long they're taking to do things, and
what kind of mistakes they're making.
Especially if we're also responsible for
administering the session at the same.
A third approach if we're
designing software,
is to actually log the behavior
inside the software.
This is in some ways,
the best of both worlds.
Like video capture,
it's automatic and passive, but
like note taking, it's analyzable.
Because it's run to the system itself,
it automatically captures everything
that it knows how to capture, and
it does so without our active invention.
But it likely does so in a data or
text format, that we can then either
analyze manually by reading through it,
or even with some more complicated
data analytics methods.
So in some ways, it captures the pros
from both note-taking and video capture.
But it also has its drawbacks as well.
Especially, it's very limited.
We can only capture those things
that are actually expressed
inside the software.
Things like the questions that
a participant asks wouldn't naturally be
captured by software logging.
Similarly, it only captures
a narrow slice of the interaction.
It only captures what the user
actually does on the screen.
It doesn't capture how long
they look at something.
We might be able to infer that
by looking at the time between
interactions, but it's difficult to
know if that hesitation was because they
couldn't decide what to do, or
because someone was making noise
outside, or something else was going on.
And finally,
it's also very tech sensitive.
We really have to have
a working prototype,
in order to use software logging.
But remember,
many of our prototypes dont' work yet.
You can't do software logging on a paper
prototype, or a card prototype, or
a Wizard of Oz prototype.
This only really works once we've
reached a certain level of fidelity with
our interfaces.
So in selecting a way to capture
your qualitative evaluation,
ask yourself, will the subjects find
being captured on camera intrusive?
Do I need to capture
what happens on screen?
How difficult will this
data be to analyze?
It's tempting, especially for
novices, to focus on just capturing as
much as possible during the session.
But during the session is when you can
capture data in a way that's going to
make your analysis easier.
So think about the analysis
that you want to do,
when deciding how to
capture your sessions.