One of the most exciting application areas for
HCI is in helping people with special needs.
Computing can help us compensate for disability, injuries, aging.
Think of a robotic prosthetic for example.
Of course, part of that is engineering,
part of it is neuroscience.
But it's also important to understand how the person intends to
use such a limb and the tasks they need to perform.
That's HCI intersecting with robotics.
Or take another example from some work done here at Georgia Tech by Bruce Walker.
How do you communicate data to a blind person?
We've talked about information visualization,
but if it's a visualization,
it's leaving out a significant portion of the population.
So, Dr. Walker Sonification Lab works in communicating data using sound.
A lot of the emerging areas of HCI technology could have
extraordinary significance to people with special needs.
Imagine virtual reality for people suffering from some form of paralysis,
or imagine using artificial intelligence with
context-aware computing to create an autonomous wheelchair.
These are projects would only target a small portion of the population.
But the impact of that portion would be absolutely indescribable.