Here are five quick tips for conducting successful evaluations.
Number one, run pilot studies.
Recruiting participants is hard.
You want to make sure that once you start working with real users,
you're ready to gather really useful data.
So, try it your experiment with friends or family or co-workers
before trying it out with real users to
iron out the kinks in your design and your directions.
Number two, focus on feedback.
It's tempting in qualitative evaluations to spend
too much time trying to teach this one user.
If the user criticizes an element of the prototype,
you don't need to explain to them the rationale.
Your goal is to get feedback to design the next interface,
not to just teach this one current user.
Number three, use questions when users get stuck.
That way, you get some information on why they're stuck, and what they're thinking.
Those questions can also be used to guide users to how they
should use it to make the session seem less instructional.
Number four, tell users what to do,
but not how to do it.
This doesn't always apply,
but most often we want to design interfaces that users
can use without any real instruction whatsoever.
So, in performing qualitative evaluation,
give them instruction on what to accomplish,
but let them try to figure out how to do it.
If they try to do it differently than what you expect,
then you know how to design the next interface.
Number five, capture satisfaction.
Sometimes, we can get so distracted by whether or not users can use
our interface that we forget to ask them whether or not they like using our interface.
So, make sure to capture user satisfaction in your qualitative evaluation.