In an empirical evaluation,
we're trying to evaluate something formal,
and most often that means something numeric.
It could be something explicitly numeric like what layout of buttons
leads to more purchases or what gestures are most efficient to use.
There could also be some interpretation involved though like
counting errors or summarizing survey responses.
The overall goal though is to come to the something verifiable and conclusive.
In industry, this is often useful in comparing designs or in demonstrating improvement.
In research though, this is even more important,
because this is how we build
new theories of how people think when they're using interfaces.
If we wanted to prove, for example,
that gestural interaction has a tougher learning curve than voice interaction,
or that an audio interface is just as usable as a visual one,
we would need to do empirical evaluation between the interfaces.
Now, most empirical evaluations are going to be comparisons.
We can do quantitative analysis without doing comparisons,
but it usually isn't necessary.
The biggest benefit of quantitative analysis is
the ability to help us perform objective comparisons.
So, with empirical evaluation,
our overall question is usually,
how can we show that there is a difference between these designs?