When we do qualitative evaluations,
we effectively just bring in participants one at a time or maybe in groups,
go through a certain interview protocol or script,
and then move them along.
Empirical evaluation is different though.
Here, we have multiple conditions which we call treatments.
These treatments could be different interfaces,
different designs, different colors,
whatever we're interested in investigating.
Our goal here is to investigate the comparison between
the treatments and end up with a conclusion about how they are different.
However, we have to be careful to make sure that the differences that we observe
really are due to differences between the treatments and not due to other factors.
For example, imagine we're testing the difference between two logos,
and we want to know what works better, orange or teal.
However, we also make one a circle and the other one a triangle.
In the end, we wouldn't be able to comment on orange versus teal.
We can only comment on orange circle versus teal triangle.
To make a judgement about the color,
we need to make sure that the color is the only thing that we're comparing.
Of course, this example right here sound a little bit silly.
In practice though, differences can be more subtle.
If you're testing between different layouts,
you might missed that one loads a bit faster or that one uses prettier images,
and that could actually account for any differences that you observe.
Once we've designed the treatments,
it's time to design the experiment itself.
Our first question is,
what do the participants do?
Does each participant participate in one treatment or both?
If each participant only participates in one treatment,
then our next step is pretty easy.
We split the participants randomly into two groups,
and one by one, they each go through their treatment.
At the end, we have the data from participants in
one group to comparative data from participants in the other group.
This is a between subjects design,
we're comparing the data from one group to the other group.
There's a second option though,
we can also do a within subjects experiment.
With a within subjects experiment,
each participant experiences both treatments.
However, a major lurking variable could potentially be,
which treatment each participant sees first?
So, we still have to randomly assign participants to treatment groups.
But instead of assigning participants to which treatment they are receiving,
we're randomly assigning them to what order they'll receive the treatments in.
That way, if the order of the participants received the treatments in matters,
we'll see it in our data.
Within subject is beneficial because it allows us to gather
twice as much data if our participant pool is limited.
Here, each interface would be used by 16 participants instead of just eight.
It also allows us to do within subjects comparison,
seeing how each individual participant was affected,
instead of the groups as a whole.
That can help us identify some more subtle effects,
like, if different people have different strengths.
However, within subjects requires more of our subjects time,
which can be a big problem if the treatments are themselves pretty long.
Throughout this example, we've also glossed over important detail.
Random assignment.
Random assignment to treatment helps us control for other biases.
Imagine if all the smartest participants or all the women
were all placed in one group and all receive the same treatment,
that would clearly affect our results.
That's why we randomly assign people to groups.
Now, that might sound obvious,
but imagine if you're treatment involves a physical setup,
it would be tempting to run the first eight participants on
one setup and a second eight participants on the other,
so you don't have to switch back and forth between them.
But what if that means that
all the more punctual participants were in the first condition,
or what if you got better at administering the experiment during the first condition?
So that participants in the second condition had a generally smoother experience.
All of these looking variables are controlled in part,
by random assignment to groups.