Let's pretend this is a reaction time study because that gives us some nice numeric data.
We're curious, what color should be used to alert
a driver in a car that they're starting to leave their lane?
We run half of them with orange,
and half of them with green in a between subjects design.
As a result, they've generated some data.
These are each participant's reaction times.
Our goal is to compare this data and decide which is better.
So, how do we do that? Well, we might just average it.
So, it looks like the orange is smaller than the green, right?
So, the orange is better, and not so fast, no pun intended.
These numbers are very close.
It's entirely possible this difference arose just by random chance.
They're not likely going to be exactly equal in any trial.
The question is are they different enough to conclude that they're really different?
In fact, in this case, they definitely are if you run the numbers.
The process for actually doing this rigorously is called hypothesis testing.
Whenever we're trying to prove something,
we initially hypothesized that the opposite is true.
So, if we're trying to prove that one of these options is better than the other,
we initially hypothesized that actually, they are equal.
That's the null hypothesis.
It's the hypothesis that we accept if we can't find
sufficient data to support the alternative hypothesis.
So, we want to see if this difference is big enough to
accept the alternative hypothesis instead of the null hypothesis.
We generally accept the alternative hypothesis if there's less than
a five percent chance that the difference could have arisen by random chance.
In that case, we say that the difference is statistically significant.
So, here, there's probably
a pretty good chance that this difference could arise by random chance,
not because orange is actually any better than green.
But imagine if the data changed.
Imagine if these were our observations from green instead of the ones before.
Our average has gone up considerably from 0.3 to 0.44.
Here, it's unlikely for this difference to
be based only on random chance. It's still possible.
It's just far less likely.
This is the general process of hypothesis testing.
Assuming that things are the same and seeing if
the data is sufficient to prove that they're different.