Because the only goal here is for you to be able to identify what test to use and when,
we've put together this little chart to serve as kind of a cheat sheet.
Here, you can look up your independent variable,
your dependent variable and your number of treatments and see what test is recommended.
So, if you've gathered some categorical ordinal data,
with three or more treatments,
I'd probably want to use a Chi-squared test.
Now of course, you'll also notice that this isn't exhaustive.
There are a lot of combinations of
independent and dependent variables you could have that aren't covered here.
For example, we never talked about how you do
a binomial test with three or more treatments.
You might also have tests for the independent variables interval or ratio
but your deep in the variable is still nominal or ordinal or something else.
So, there are a lot of things out there in
the statistical community that aren't covered here.
But these tests and these combinations of variables,
tend to be the ones that we encounter most often in HCI.
Even there, this is probably overkill.
A Chi-squared test, a T-test and
the occasional ANOVA will probably last you your entire career.
At least for the types of analyses that we usually care about.