Predictive evaluation is evaluation
we can do without actual users.
Now, in user centered design that's not
ideal, but predictive evaluation can be
more efficient and
accessible than actual user evaluation.
So it's all right to use it as
part of a rapid feedback process.
It lets keep the user in mind,
even we we're not bringing
users into the conversation.
The important thing is to make
sure we're using it appropriately.
Predictive evaluation shouldn't be used
where we could be doing qualitative or
empirical evaluation.
It should only be used where we wouldn't
otherwise be doing any evaluation.
Effectively, it's better than nothing.