When we talk about design principles,
we talked about several heuristics and guidelines we use in designing interfaces.
The first method for predictive evaluation is simply to hand
our interface and these guidelines to a few experts to evaluate.
This is called heuristic evaluation.
Each individual evaluator inspects the interface alone,
and identifies places where the interface violates some heuristic.
We might sit with an expert while they perform
the evaluation or they might generate our report.
Heuristics are useful because they give us
small snapshots into the way people might think about our interfaces.
If we take these heuristics to an extreme though,
we could go so far as to develop models of the way people think about our interfaces.
During our need-finding exercises,
we developed models of our users tasks.
In model-based evaluation, we take these models and
trace through it in the context of the interface that we designed.
So, let's use a Gomez model for example,
just we computed a Gomez model for what users data in some context,
we can also compute a Gomez model for what they will do in our new interface.
Then, we can compare these models side-by-side to see how
our interface changes the task and evaluate whether a deficiency.
So here, the classical way of disabling
an alarm was to use a keypad mountain near the door.
We could use this Gomez model to evaluate whether or not
the new keychain interface was actually more efficient than the keypad interface.
We can also use the profiles of users that we
developed to evaluate whether the new design meets each criteria.
For example, imagine if we identified this model as
applying to users with low motivation to use this interface?
Maybe it's people doing purchases that they have to do for work,
as opposed to just shopping at their leisure.
We can use that to inform our evaluation of
whether or not the interface relies on high user motivation.
If we find that the interface requires users to be
more personally driven or to keep more in working memory,
then we might find that the users will fail if
they don't have high motivation to use the interface,
and then we can revise it accordingly.
If we take model-based evaluation to an extreme though,
we can actually get to the point of simulation-based evaluation.
At that point, we might construct
an artificially intelligent agent that
interacts with our interface in the way that a human would.
Melody Ivory and Marti Hearst actually did some research on this back in 2001,
on The State of the Art In Automating Usability Evaluation of User Interfaces.
That seems like an amazing undertaking given
how flexible and varied user interfaces can actually be.
Can we really evaluate them automatically?
More recently, work has even been done to create even more human-like models of users,
like some work done by the Human-Centered Design Group
at the Institute for Information Technology in Germany.
Developing that agent is an enormous task on it's own,
but if we're working on a big long-term project like
Facebook or in a high-stakes environment like air traffic control,
having a simulation of a human that we can run hundreds of thousands of
times on different interface prototypes would be extremely useful.