In this lesson, we've covered three
different types of evaluation.
Qualitative, empirical, and predictive.
Each method has its advantages and
disadvantages.
Let's start to wrap this lesson
up by exploring those advantages
with an exercise.
Here are the methods that we've covered.
And here are some potential advantages.
For each row, mark the column
to which that advantage applies.
Note that again,
these might be somewhat relative, so
your answer will probably
differ a bit from ours.
You can go ahead and
skip to the exercise if you don't
want to hear me read these.
Our advantages are,
does not require any actual users,
identifies provable advantages.
Informs ongoing design decisions,
investigates the participants
thought process.
Provides generalizable conclusions, and
draws conclusions from
actual participants.