Here would be my answers
to this exercise.
These are a little bit more objective
than some of our exercises in the past.
First, if it does not require any actual
users, predictive evaluation is the only
evaluation we can do without involving
users in the evaluation process.
That's both its biggest strength and
its biggest weakness.
For identifying provable advantages,
only empirical evaluation can reliably
generate generalizable conclusions,
generalizable advantages, because it's
the only one who does it numerically.
As far as informing ongoing
design decisions is concerned,
that's definitely the case for
qualitative and predictive evaluation.
I've left it unmarked for empirical
evaluation simply because we usually do
this towards the end of
our design life cycle,
although we also know that the design
life cycle never really ends.
So eventually,
empirical evaluation could be used
to inform ongoing design decisions.
It's just not involved in the earlier
cycles though the design life cycle.
As far as investing the participant's
thought process, again,
empirical evaluation
doesn't really do that.
It only accesses participants
performance numerically.
Qualitative evaluation definitely does
this, because it actually asks users
to think out lout and
describe their thought process.
And really, predictive evaluation tries
to investigate the participant's thought
process, just in a lower overhead,
or lower cost kind of way.
It does so by having experts
in usability design simulate
the participant's thought process, and
comment on it from the perspective
of some preset heuristics.
Similar to how only empirical evaluation
can identify provable advantages,
it's also the only one that can
provide generalizable conclusions,
again because it uses numbers.
And finally, qualitative and
empirical evaluations both draw
conclusions from actual participants.
This is the inverse of predictive
evaluations, lack of requirement for
actual users.