To succeed in HCI,
you need a good evaluation plan.
In industries like healthcare and education,
that is initially going to involve getting some time with
experts outside the real contexts of the task.
That's bringing doctors, bringing in nurses,
bringing in patients, and
exploring their thoughts and the prototypes that you've designed.
In some places like education,
you might be able to evaluate with real users even before the interface is ready.
But in others like healthcare,
the sticks are high enough that you'll only want real users using
the interface when you're certain of its effectiveness and reliability.
In some emerging areas that we find in multiple questions in evaluation,
take on virtual reality for example,
most people you encounter haven't used virtual reality before.
There's going to be a learning curve.
How are you going to determine whether the learning curve is acceptable or not?
If the user runs into difficulties,
how can you tell if those come from your interface,
or if they're part of the fundamental VR learning experience?
So, take a moment to brainstorm
your evaluation approach for your chosen application area.
What kinds of evaluations would you choose, and why?