The content we've covered so far was developed over the course
of several decades of research in HCI in human factors,
and it's all still applicable today as well.
At the same time, new technologies and
new areas call for new principals and new workflows,
and specifically, the advent of the Internet ushered in new methods for HCI.
Many software developers now adopt an agile workflow which emphasizes earlier delivery,
more continuous improvement, and rapid feedback cycles.
For those of us here in HCI.
That's actually really exciting.
We love feedback cycles.
We love building them for our users,
and we love engaging in them ourselves.
It's also a scary prospect, though.
We've discussed long prototyping processes that move from paper to wireframes
to live demos involving lots of users in slow qualitative methodologies,
and those things are still very valuable.
But, nowadays, sometimes we just want to build
something really fast and get it in front of real users.
So, in this lesson, we'll talk about how we might use
agile development methods to engage in quicker feedback cycles.