Here would be my answers.
The two areas that I think are good candidates,
for an agile development process are the two that use
existing devices and don't have high stakes associated with them.
In both these cases, rolling out updates wouldn't be terribly difficult,
and we haven't lost a whole lot by initially having a product that has some bugs in it.
A camera interface for any MOOC recording would be
a good candidate if the camera environment was easier to program for.
The programming for a camera isn't like programming for
an App Store or for a desktop environment.
I actually don't even know how you go about it.
So, for us, a camera interface for aiding MOOC recording
probably wouldn't be a great candidate because we don't have access to that platform.
Remember, our goal is to get products in front of real users as soon as possible.
Now, of course, that all changes if we're actually working for a camera company,
and we do have access to that platform.
The second one is more fundamental though,
a tool for helping doctors visualize patient information in surgery.
There are really high-stakes behind that.
If you visualize something in a way that's a little bit misleading, someone could die.
So, you probably don't want to take an agile development process for that.
For a wearable device for mobile keyboard entry,
wearable devices are expensive to produce.
When you are actually producing the physical device,
you want to be sure it's going to work pretty well.
Similarly, devices are easy to update the way software is.
So, wearable devices is probably not a good candidate for an agile development process.
Finally, a navigation app for the console of an electric car,
I said isn't a good candidate,
although you might disagree.
Personally, I would say that the stakes are high enough for navigation app,
that you probably want to be pretty sure that you're going to
have a good product before you roll it out to users.
It might take a wrong turn or end up in the wrong neighborhood or
missing appointment based on some mistakes that we make.
I would consider that sufficiently high stakes to avoid a faster development process.
Plus, not all electric cars are like Tesla.
Some of them actually have to have you bring the car
to the factory or to the repair shop to get an update.
So, the cost of rolling out updates can be more significant there as well.