So when should you consider using
these more agile methodologies?
Lots of software development
theorists have explored this space.
Boehm and Turner specifically
suggest that agile development
can only be used in
certain circumstances.
First, they say, it must be
an environment with low criticality.
By it's nature,
agile development means letting
the users do some of the testing.
So you don't want to use it
in environments where bugs or
poor usability are going to
lead to major repercussions.
Healthcare or financial investing
wouldn't be great places for
agile development, generally speaking.
Although there have been efforts to
create standards that would allow
the methodology to apply, without
compromising security and safety.
But for things like smartphone games and
social media apps,
the criticality is sufficiently low.
Second, it should really be a place
where requirements change often.
One of the benefits of an agile
process is they allow teams to adjust
quickly to changing expectations or
needs.
A thermostat, for example, doesn't
change it's requirements very often.
A site like Udacity though,
is constantly adjusting to new
student interests or student needs.
Now these two components apply to
the types of problems we're working on.
If we're working on an interface that
would lend itself to a more agile
process, we also must set up the team
to work well within an agile process.
That means small teams that
are comfortable with change.
As opposed to large teams
that thrive on order.
So generally, agile processes
can be good in some cases
with the right people,
but poor in many others.