Does the area of
HCI on which you chose to focus lend itself naturally to agile development?
There are a lot of questions to ask in that area.
Are you working in a high-stakes area like health care or autonomous vehicles?
What's the cost of failure?
If it's high, you might want to avoid agile development.
After all, it's built in large part around learning from the real failures of real users.
If that's a user unfairly failing to reach
the next level of the game, that's probably fine.
If that's a doctor entering the wrong dosage of
a medication into a new interface, that's not fine.
You also need to think of development costs.
Agile development relies on being able to get a product
up and out the door quickly and change it frequently.
If any part of your design is reliant on the hardware,
then agile development presents challenges.
It might be easy to roll out a software update to improve a car screen interface,
but you can't download a car to fix a hardware problem.
Now, take a moment and think about whether agile development would
be right for the area of application that you chose.