In this lesson, we've covered a small glimpse of how
HCI can work in a more agile development environment.
In many ways, they're a nice match.
Both emphasized feedback cycles,
both emphasize getting user feedback,
and both emphasize rapid changes.
But while HCI traditionally has done these behind the scenes before reaching real users,
Agile emphasizes doing these live.
Now, it's important to note I've only provided
a narrow glimpse into what Agile development is all about.
I've discussed how HCI matches with the theory and the goals of Agile development.
But Agile is a more complex suite of workflows and stake holders.
I really recommend reading more about it before you try to take an Agile approach to HCI,
or before you try to integrate interaction design into
an existing Agile team as you do though,
I think you'll notice that there can be a really nice compatibility between the two.