Throughout this unit, we've used
the running example of designing an audio book app that would let
people who are exercising interact with books and
all the ways you or I might while we're sitting and reading.
That means being able to leave bookmarks,
take notes, and so on.
We discussed two in our foundational needfinding,
going to a park and observing people exercising.
We've talked also about doing interviews and surveys to find out
more targeted information about what people wanted and needed.
Then based on that, we brainstormed a whole lot of alternatives.
We thought about those alternatives in terms of different scenarios
and personas to settle on those with the most potential.
Then, we took those alternatives and we prototyped a few of them.
Specifically, we constructed Wizard of Oz prototypes for voice and gesture interfaces,
and paper prototypes for on-screen interfaces.
Then, we put those in front of our users.
Well, a user in my case,
but you would use more users.
We got some initial feedback.
So, at the end of one iteration of the design life-cycle,
we have three different low-fidelity prototypes,
each with some feedback on how effectively they work.
But as you can tell, we're not done yet. We don't have an app.
So, what's next? Next, we go through another iteration of the design lifecycle.