We take the results of our initial iteration through
the design lifecycle and use the results to return to the need-finding process.
Now, that's not to say we need to redo everything from scratch.
But our prototypes and evaluation have now increased our understanding of the problem.
There are things we learn by prototyping and evaluating about the task itself.
In this case, we could have learned that even for exercises with our hands free,
gestures are still tough because they're moving around so much.
The evaluation process may have also given us
new questions we want to ask users to understand the task better.
So, for example, Maureen could have mentioned that she needed the ability to rewind.
We might want to know how common a problem is that.
So, in many ways, synthesizing our experiences with
the evaluation is our next need-finding process.
So, then, we move on to design alternative stage.
Again, that doesn't mean we start from scratch and come up with all new ideas.
Here it means expanding on our current ideas, flushing them out of it,
and brainstorming them in the context of
those personas and scenarios that we used previously.
We might also come up with whole new ideas here based on
our first iteration, then more prototyping.
At this point, we might discover that as we
try to increase the fidelity of some of our prototypes,
the technology or the resource is just aren't quite there yet.
For example, while the gesture interface might've been promising,
in the Wizard of Oz prototype, we could've done for that,
we don't yet have the technology to recognize gestures that way on the go,
or we might have found that the expense related to the prototype is unfeasible,
or we could have realized that the prototype would
require violating some of our other user needs.
So, for example, we could do gesture recognition if we
had users hold a physical device that could recognize certain gestures,
but that might be too expensive to produce or it might
conflict with our audiences need for a hands-free system.
So, we move on with the prototypes that we can build,
with the goal of getting to the feedback stage as quickly as possible.
For our voice recognition,
instead of trying to build a full voice recognition system,
maybe we just build a system that can recognize very simplistic voice commands.
Instead of recognizing words,
maybe it just recognizes the number of utterances if that's easier to build.
For the screen, maybe we build
a wireframe prototype that moves between different screens on a phone,
but we don't connect it to a real system.
We still have someone run alongside
the exerciser and play the book according to their commands.
That way, we focus on usability instead of things like
integration with audiobook apps or voice-to-text transcription,
things that take a lot of work to get right and might end up
unnecessary if we find that the prototype isn't actually useful,
and then we evaluate again.
This time, we probably get a little bit more objective.
We still want data on the qualitative user experience,
but we also want data on things like how long does it take the user to perform
the desired actions in the interface or
what prevents them from working with the interface.
Imagine that we found, for instance,
that for many exercisers,
they go through places that are too loud for voice commands to work,
or we could have found,
that the time it takes to pull out the interface and
interact is just too distracting and limiting.
That information is once again useful to our ongoing iteration.
At the end of that process,
we again have some higher fidelity prototypes,
but no product yet.
So, we go again.