So, that's the end, right?
We went through a few iterations of the design lifecycle,
we got iteratively more high-fidelity and rigorous with our evaluation.
Finally, we have a design we like.
So, we implement it,
we submit it to the App Store and we sit back while the money roles in, not exactly.
Now instead of having a handful of users we bring in to use our interface,
we have hundreds of users using it in ways we never expected,
and now the cycle begins again.
We have data we're automatically collecting through either usage tracking or error logs.
We have user reviews or the feedback that they submit.
So we jumped back into need-finding using the data we now have available to us.
We might find more subtle needs like
the need for more control over rewinding and fast-forwarding.
We might move on and prototype things like a command
for back five seconds or back 15 seconds.
We might uncover more novel new needs as well,
we find that there might be
a significant contingent of people using the interface while driving.
It's similar in that it's another place where people's hands and eyes are occupied,
but it has its own unique needs as well
like the ability to run alongside a navigation app.
So, the process starts again.
This time with live users data and in general,
it never really ends.
Nowadays, you very rarely see interfaces or apps or programs or
websites that are intentionally put up once and never changed.
That might happen because designers got busy or the company went out of business,
but it's rarely a one-off deployment by design.
As the design evolves over time with real data,
you'll start to see some nested feedback cycles as well.
Week to week small editions give way to
month-to-month updates and year to year reinventions.
In many ways, your interface becomes like a child.
You watch it grow up,
and take on a life of its own.