At a minimum, user-centered design advocates
involving users throughout the process through surveys,
and interviews, and evaluations,
and more things that we've already talked about.
However, user-centered design can be taken to
even greater extremes through a number of approaches beyond what we've covered.
One is called participatory design.
In participatory design, all the stakeholders,
including the users themselves,
are involved as part of the design team.
They aren't just a source of data.
They're actually members working on the design team,
working on the problem.
That allows the user perspective to be pretty omnipresent throughout the design process.
Now, of course, there's still a danger there.
Generally, we are not our user.
But in participatory design,
one of the designers is the user,
but they're not the only user.
So, it's a great way to get a user's perspective,
but we must also be careful not to overrepresent that one person's view.
A second approach is action research.
Action research is a methodology that addresses
an immediate problem and researches it by trying to simultaneously solve it.
Data gathered on the success of the approaches and used to
inform the understanding of the problem and future approaches.
Most importantly, like participatory design,
action research is undertaken by the actual users.
For example, a teacher might engage in action research by trying
a new activity in his classroom and reflecting on the results,
or a manager might use action research by trying
a new evaluation system with her employees and noting the changes.
A third approach is design-based research.
Design-based research is similar to action research
but it can be done by outside practitioners as well.
It's especially common in learning sciences research.
In design-based research, designers create
interventions based on their current understanding of the theory and the problem,
and they use the success of those interventions
to improve our understanding of the theory or the problem.
For example, if we believed a certain intersection
had a lot of jaywalkers because the signs have poor visibility,
we might interview people at the intersection for their thoughts,
or we could create a solution that assumes that we're correct,
and then use it to evaluate whether or not we actually were correct.
If we create a more clearly visible sign and it fixes the problem,
then it suggests that our initial theory was correct.
Now, in all of these approaches,
notice iteration still plays a strong role.
We never try out one design and stop.
We run through the process,
create a design, try it out,
iterate, and improve on it.
Interface design is never really done.
It just gets better and better as time goes on
while also adjusting to new trends and new technologies.