The year that I'm recording this is what many have described as;
the year that virtual reality finally hits the mainstream.
By the time you watch this,
you'll probably be able to assess whether or not that was true,
so come back in time and let me know.
Virtual reality is an entire new classification of interaction and
visualization and we're definitely still at
the beginning of figuring out what we can do with these new tools.
You could be one of the ones who figures out the best way to resolve
motion sickness or how to give proper feedback on gestural interactions.
A lot of the press around virtual reality has been around
video games but that's definitely not the only application.
Tourism, commerce, art, education,
virtual reality has applications to dozens of spaces.
For example, there's a lab in Michigan that's using virtual reality to treat phobias.
They're creating a safe space where people can
very authentically and realistically confront their fears.
The possible applications of virtual reality are really staggering,
so I'd encourage you to check them out as you go through this class.