Ubiquitous computing refers to the trend towards embedding
computing power in more and more everyday objects.
You might also hear it referred to as pervasive computing.
It's deeply related to the emerging idea of an Internet of Things.
A few years ago, you wouldn't have found computers,
and refrigerators, and wristwatches,
but as microprocessors became cheaper,
and as the world became increasingly interconnected,
computers are becoming more and more ubiquitous.
Modern HCI means thinking about whether someone might use
a computer while they're driving a car or going on a run.
It means figuring out how to build smart devices
that also some of the cognitive load from the user,
like refrigerators that track their own contents and
deliver advice to the users right at the right time.
This push for increasing pervasiveness has also led to the rise of wearable technologies.
Exercise monitors are probably
the most common examples of this but smartwatches, Google Glass,
augmented reality headsets, even things like advanced hearing aids and
robotic prosthetic limbs are all examples of wearable technology.
This push carries us in the areas usually reserved for
human factors engineering and industrial design,
which exemplifies the increasing role of HCI in the design of new products.