One of the biggest trends of the information age is the incredible availability of data.
Scientists and researchers use data science and
machine learning to look at lots of data and draw conclusions.
But often times, these conclusions are only useful if we
can turn around and communicate them to ordinary people.
That's where Information Visualization comes in.
Now, at first glance you might not think of data visualization as an example of HCI.
After all, I could draw data visualization on a napkin,
and print in a newspaper,
and there's no computer involved anywhere in that process.
But computers give us a powerful way to re-represent data in complex,
animated, and interactive ways.
We'll put links to some excellent examples in the notes.
Now, what's particularly notable about data visualization in HCI,
is the degree with which it fits
perfectly with our methodologies for designing good interfaces.
One goal of a good interface is to match
the user's mental model to the reality of the task at hand in
the same way the goal of information visualization is to match
the reader's mental model of the phenomenon to the reality of it.
So, the same principles we discussed for designing good representations,
apply directly to designing good visualizations.
After all, a visualization is just a representation of data.