CSCW stands for computer-supported cooperative work.
The field is just what the name says.
How do we use computers to support people working together?
You're watching this course online,
so I'll tell the experienced as closely.
Maybe you've worked on a group project with a geographically distributed group.
Maybe you've had a job working remotely.
Distributed teams are one example of CSCW in action, but there are others.
The community often breaks things down to two dimensions, time and place.
We can think of design as whether or not we're designing for the users in
the same time and place or users at different times and in different places.
This course is an example of designing for different time and different place.
You're watching this long after I've recorded it,
likely from far away from our studio.
Workplace chat utilities, like Slack and HipChat,
would be examples of same time, different place.
They allow people to communicate instantly across space,
mimicking the real-time office experience.
Now, imagine a kiosk at a museum that asks visitors
to enter their location to create a map of where everyone comes from.
That would be different time, same place.
Everyone uses the interface at the same place, but across time.
Even when we're in the same time and place,
computers can still support cooperation.
In fact, right now, a man is running our camera,
Ben's running the teleprompter,
and I'm standing up here talking at you.
These different computers are supporting us and cooperating to create this course.
So, we can often think of CSCW as mediating
cooperation across traditional geographic or temporal borders,
but it can also help us with co-located simultaneous cooperation.