A lot of current efforts in healthcare
are about processing the massive
quantities of data that
are recorded everyday.
But in order to make that data useful,
it has to connect to real
people at some point.
Maybe it's equipping doctors with tools
to more easily visually evaluate and
compare different diagnoses.
Maybe it's giving patients the tools
necessary to monitor their own health
and treatment options.
Maybe that's information
visualization so
patients can understand how certain
decisions affect their well-being.
Maybe it's context aware computing that
can detect when patients are about to do
something they probably shouldn't do.
There are also numerous applications of
HCI to personal health like Fitbit for
exercise monitoring or
MyFitnessPal for tracking your diet.
Those interfaces succeed if
they're easily usable for users.
Ideally, they'd be almost invisible.
But perhaps the most fascinating
upcoming intersection of HCI and
health care is in virtual reality.
Virtual reality exercise programs
are already pretty common to make living
an active lifestyle more fun, but
what about virtual reality for therapy?
That's actually already happening.
We can use virtual reality to
help people confront fears and
anxieties in a safe, but
highly authentic place.
Healthcare in general is concerned
with the health of humans.
And computers are pretty commonly
used in modern healthcare.
So the applications of human
computer interaction to healthcare
are really huge.