We started the first unit by discussing feedback cycles.
Feedback cycles, as we discussed,
are ubiquitous in basically all areas of life.
They're how we learn and adapt to our environments,
and they're also how we learn and adapt to the interfaces available to us.
We then described the two parts of feedback cycles.
Gulfs of execution covered how users go from personal goals to external actions,
and gulfs of evaluation covered how the users then evaluated
whether or not the results of those actions met their original goals.
We can describe a lot of HCI as designing ways to bridge these two gulfs,
helping users more easily accomplish their goals,
and helping users more quickly identify when their goals have been accomplished.