We're discussing human computer interaction and that
means we have to understand the human portion of the equation.
So, we also took a crash course toward some basic psychology.
We broke the human down into three systems: perception,
cognition and the motor system.
With perception, we covered the strengths and limitations of the visual,
auditory and kinesthetic senses.
We discussed how each of them can be useful for different kinds of information.
Then, we discussed some of the limitations to human cognition.
We focused a lot on memory,
how many things we can store at a time and how things can be stored more permanently.
We also discussed the notion of cognitive load.
We focused especially on how we should use
our interfaces to reduce the user's cognitive load.
Finally, we discussed the limitations of the human motor system,
especially how those limitations change with
age or in the presence of certain distractions.
We're designing for humans,
so these limitations and advantages are key to how we design our interfaces.