Human-computer interaction has a long and rich history,
initially drawn from human factors engineering before becoming a field of its own.
During that history, it's developed lots of
principles and heuristics for how to design good interfaces,
lots and lots and lots in fact,
literally thousands of principles.
In this lesson, we covered 15 of the most significant ones,
drawn from four sets of design principles.
We covered the principles of Don Norman, Jakob Nielsen,
Larry Constantine, Lucy Lockwood and the Center for Universal Design.
Among these, I would probably argue that the most significant principles to
remember where affordances, mappings, and constraints.
Affordances are parts of the interface that by their very design,
tell the user what they should do.
A good mapping then tells the user what the effect of that interaction will likely be,
and then constraints ensure that the user only chooses to do the correct things.
With those three combined,
as well as the other heuristics that we covered,
we can create interfaces that vanish between the user and the task very quickly.