Every one of our users has some mental understanding of
their task as well as where our interface fits into that task.
We call that their mental model.
They use that mental model to simulate and predict the effects of certain actions,
that's why we call this the predictor model of the user.
Our goal is for the user's mental model to match
the reality of the task in the interface.
To accomplish that, we try to design
representations with clear mappings to the underlying task.
That's how we can ensure that the user's mental model of
the system is both accurate and useful.
We discussed here mistakes which are errors that occur based on inaccurate mental models,
and we discussed slips which are errors that occur despite accurate mental models.
We also talked about a couple of the challenges that can
arise in trying to help users build accurate mental models.
One of those was called expert blind spot,
that occurs when we lose sight of
our own expertise and we forget what it's like to be a novice.
The other was learned helplessness,
which is when users learn that they have
no real ability to accomplish their goals because of a broken feedback cycle.
In designing representations that lead to accurate mental models,
we need to make sure to avoid both of these problems.