We've discussed repeatedly that HCI is in large part about understanding tasks.
As designers, we designed tasks that feature interfaces,
not just interfaces alone.
To accomplish that, it's important to have
a very clear understanding of the task for which we're designing.
So toward that end, we discussed task analysis.
Task analyses are ways of breaking down tasks
into formal workflows to aid the design process.
So, we covered two general kinds of task analyses.
We talked about information processor models like the GOMS model,
which focuses on the user's goals, operators, and methods.
Those are primarily concerned with what we can observe.
We also talked about cognitive task analysis which tried to get inside
the user's head so we can understand the user's thought process during the task as well.
Both of these approaches are valuable to designing good tasks with usable interfaces.