The Design Principles unit of the course cover the fundamental principles
and ideas developed over decades of work in this space,
but we can't create good interfaces just by applying old principles to new problems.
Those old principles can help us make progress much faster,
but to design good interfaces,
we have to involve the user.
That's perhaps the most important principle of HCI, user-centered design.
User-centered design advocated keeping the user at
the heart of all of our design activities.
For us, that isn't just the person using the tool,
but it's also all the people affected by the tool's very existence.
So, to keep the user in mind,
we use an iterative design life cycle that focuses on
getting feedback from the user early and often.
The methods of that life cycle were the core of the Methods unit of this course.