The first stage of the design life cycle was need-finding.
Need-finding was how he developed a keen understanding of the needs of our users.
One of the biggest mistakes a designer can make is assuming they already
understand the user and the task before ever interacting with them.
There are several questions about the user we need to
answer before we're ready to start designing.
So, to get a good understanding of the user and the task,
we discuss several methods.
We might start with methods that have little direct interaction with the users,
like watching them in the wild or trying out the task ourselves.
We might use those to inform
some more targeted need-finding exercises like interviews and focus groups and surveys.
By combining multiple need-finding approaches,
we can build a strong model of the user and
the task that will help us design usable interfaces.