The goal of the design lifecycle is to get frequent user feedback
or to put it differently to frequently evaluate our interface ideas.
Frequent rapid feedback cycles are important for users of our interface,
but they're are also important to us as designers of interfaces.
So, that is where evaluation comes into play.
Once we've designed an interface whether it's just an idea
in our head or a full-fledged working version.
It's time to evaluate it with users.
Early on, that may be
qualitative evaluation to get the full picture of the user experience.
Later on, that might be empirical evaluation to
more formally capture the results of the interface.
Along the way, we might also employ predictive evaluation
to try to anticipate how users will react to our designs.
These methods are the foundation of user-centered design.
Design that features frequent user evaluation of our ideas.