Traditional HCI can be a slow deliberate process but by
constant interaction with users as we slowly ramp up the fidelity of our prototypes.
In the past, that was because every phase of the process was very expensive,
from development to distribution,
to evaluation, to updating.
But now, in some contexts those steps have become much much cheaper.
Some web development can be done by simple drag and drop interfaces.
We can now distribute applications to millions of users essentially for free.
We can then pull back enormous quantities of live data from
them and push updates to all of them in a real time.
Given all that, sometimes it might be more prudent to
particularly working the versions quickly to start getting real user data faster.
So, we also discussed agile methods
for development while keeping an eye on the design life cycle.
These methods aren't appropriate for all areas,
especially those with high cost of failure but for
many places they can really increase the iteration speed of our design lifecycle.