[MUSIC]
For this portion of our conversation
about human computer interaction,
we're going to talk about some
established principals that we'd
uncovered after decades of
designing user interfaces.
We want to understand the fundamental
building blocks of HCI, and
separately we'll talk about how
to build on those foundations to
do new research and new development.
To get started, though,
let's first define some of the
overarching ideas of design principles.
In this lesson, we're going to talk
about the way we focus on users and
tasks in HCI, not on tools and
interfaces on their own.
We're going to talk about
the role of the interface and
how it mediates between user and
the task.
We're going to discuss different views
on the user's role in the system.
And we're going to talk about user
experience more generally and
how it exists at several
different levels.
Along the way, we'll tackle some
design challenges, reflect on our own
experiences, and try to apply what we
learn to the broader field of HCI.