One of the famous models for communicating is,
tell them what you're going to tell them,
tell them, then tell them what you told them.
That's what we've tried to do here at several different levels of abstraction.
At the beginning of the course, we told you the overall structure of the course.
Within each unit, we outlined the content of that unit.
Within each lesson, we previewed the content of that particular lesson,
and then we delivered the content.
Then, we summarized each lesson,
and we summarized each unit.
Now, we've summarized the course as a whole.
So, we're done now, right? Not quite.
There are two other useful things to cover,
the closely related fields to HCI and where you might want to go next.