At the beginning of our conversations,
we talked about how HCI is part of a broader hierarchy of fields.
It draws a lot from human factors engineering, and in fact,
in many ways, it's human factors engineering applied specifically to software.
It also has numerous subfields,
like user interface design,
user experience design, computer-supported cooperative work, and more.
In this lesson, we want to let you know where
you might want to go next in your exploration of HCI,
in terms of subject matter.
Note that these are different from the areas of application of HCI.
When we talk about things like virtual reality or educational technology,
we're describing fields to which HCI applies.
Here, we're talking about HCI subfields themselves.