When we described mental models,
we were actually briefly touching on
a deep body of literature from the cognitive science field.
Cognitive science is the general study of human thought,
mental organization, and memory.
Now, cognitive science isn't a subfield of HCI,
but HCI informs a good portion of cognitive science research.
That's because HCI gives us a way to explore aspects of human cognition.
We can design interfaces that assume humans think or process in a certain way,
and we can use the results of those interfaces to further develop our theories.
In this way, HCI is a probe into
human thought that informs the development of cognitive science,
and cognitive science, in turn,
gives us theories on human abilities that inform the interfaces that we design.
So, if you're interested in studying people more closely using HCI as a probe or a tool,
we'll give you some more resources to explore.