When we discussed feedback cycles,
we mentioned that the user experience applies not only
at the individual level but also at the group level.
Distributed cognition too was interested in
how interactions between people can be mediated by
interfaces and how the output and knowledge of
those interactions can't be attributed narrowly to one particular part of the system,
but rather to the system as a whole.
The ubiquity of human interaction and
the potential of computers to mediate interactions between
people gives rise to field that investigate collaboration across interfaces.
These fields ask questions like: how can computers be
used to allow people to collaborate across distance and across time,
and how can computers be used to enhance the collaboration
of people working together at the same place at the same time?
These fields look at how computers can support things
like cooperative work in collaborative learning.
For example, how does Wikipedia enable people across
enormous variations in location and time to work together to capture knowledge?
Or how do online courses allow teachers and
students to interact and learn asynchronously across distances?
Or how can computers be used to facilitate conversations between people
with different backgrounds and expertises and even languages?
These are pretty well-developed fields.
So, if you'd like to learn more,
we'll put some more information in the notes below.