At the heart of Human Computer
Interaction is the idea that users
use interfaces to accomplish some task.
In general, that interface wouldn't
actually have to be technological.
This cycle exists for things like
using pencils to write things or
using a steering wheel to drive a car.
But in HCI, we're going to focus
on interfaces that are in some way
computational or computerized.
What's most important here though is
our focus on the interaction between
the user and
the task though the interface,
not just the interaction between
the user and the interface itself.
We're designing interfaces, sure, but
to design a good interface, we need to
understand both the users goals and
the tasks they're trying to accomplish.
Understanding the task
is really important.
One of the mistakes many
novice designers make,
is jumping too quickly to the interface,
without understanding the task.
For example,
think about designing a new thermostat.
If you focus on the interface,
the thermostat itself, you're going to
focus on things like the placement of
the buttons or the layout of the screen,
on whether or not the user can actually
read what's there, and things like that.
And those are all important questions.
But the task is controlling
the temperature in an area.
When you think about the task
rather than just the interface,
you think of things like nest,
which is a device that tries to learn
from its user and act autonomously.
That's more than just an interface for
controlling whether the heat or
the air conditioning is on.
That's an interface for controlling
the temperature in your house.
By focusing on the task
instead of just the interface,
we can come up with more revolutionary
designs like the Nest rather than just
iterative improvements to the same
thermostats we've been using for years.