To close out, my work is at the intersection of artificial intelligence,
human-computer interaction, and education.
My research is largely on how to use AI to create valuable learning experiences.
Setting aside the education part for a second, though,
there's a rich interaction between artificial intelligence and
human-computer interaction in the form of what we call intelligent user interfaces.
This field looks at how we can apply AI techniques to
adapting user interfaces to their users.
Now, an infamous example of this is Clippy,
the Microsoft Office assistant.
He tried to infer what you're working on and give you in-context feedback on it.
Intelligent user interfaces have come a long way since then, though.
Google Now, for example,
is consistently trying to learn from your
routine and give you information when you need it.
One of my favorite experiences with
intelligent user interfaces came from the interaction between Google Maps,
Gmail, and Google Calendar.
Google Calendar had automatically imported
a restaurant reservation I had made from Gmail along with the location of the restaurant.
Then, Google Maps, knowing where I was,
detected that there was unusual traffic between me and the reservation,
and it buzz me to let me know when to leave to arrive on time.
I hadn't checked traffic, but I was on time for
my reservation because of the intelligence of that user interface.
It knew what I needed to know and when I needed to know it.
So, if you'd like to hear more about the overlap between artificial intelligence,
human-computer interaction, and intelligent user interfaces,
we'll put some information in the notes below.