The quickest way to get more involved in HCI if you're at Georgia Tech,
is to see about joining a professor's research team.
On the Georgia Tech HCI faculty listing,
you'll find listings for every HCI faculty member along with their research interests.
Find someone who's working on the same kinds of things that you want to work on,
and see if they'd let you join one of their ongoing research projects.
Professors are extremely busy people,
but one of the things I love about Georgia Tech is the school's focus on
fostering student education and involvement in addition to fostering quality research.
So, it's quite likely that you'll find someone willing to
let you join up and prove that you can contribute.
Let's check our list of what kind of projects are going on.
Near research projects are coming up all the time,
and new faculty are joining every year,
that's why I'm not listing names of specific projects.
But if any of these domains are interesting to you,
check out the HCI faculty websites,
and see if there's anything to which you'd like to contribute.