HCI is a popular topic and emerging MOOCs as well.
So if you're looking to continue your HCI education in
a slightly more formal way but don't want to shell out the money for a formal degree,
there are a lot of great places you can start.
First, interactiondesign.org is a treasure trove of HCI information.
It has a fantastic free open access body of literature to study independently,
including additional information on many topics we've covered throughout this course.
The site also runs quite a few of its own closed courses as well.
For more traditional MOOCs,
Udacity has free courses on HCI as applies to product design
and mobile app design as well as a MOOC by Don Norman based on his famous book,
Design of Everyday Things.
Over at edX.org, MIT has released a series of
MOOCs targeting user experiences in mobile app development.
The University of Michigan has an X series on UX research and Shanghai University has
a course on user experience design with a special emphasis on human factors and culture.
On Coursera, Scott Klemmer one of the most prominent HCI researchers,
has a specialization entitled, Interaction Design.
The University of Minnesota also has a specialization
on UI design that covers a lot of the same topics
that we covered here developed in part by another Georgia Tech along [inaudible].
The University of London also has a specialization on responsive web design.
Georgia Tech is planning on a specialization on
human computer interaction as well that might be live by the time you see this.
That's all just core HCI courses.
All of these providers and more have courses on
applied areas of HCI like video game design,
educational technology, virtual reality and more.
Most of these courses are available for free to watch.
Note also that new MOOCs are coming online all the time,
so there are quite likely a lot that I haven't mentioned here.
So, check out Udacity,
checkout edX, checkout Coursera, checkout FutureLearn.
Also Checkout classcentral.com for a list of MOOCs
across several different platforms or just google "HCI MOOC".
This space is so new and fast-paced that by the time you view this video,
half the MOOCs I've mentioned might be gone
and twice as many new ones may have been created.
We'll try to keep an updated list of available courses in the notes below.