If you want to take this a step further though,
you might get an actual Master's in Computer Science, specializing in HCI.
Now if you're a Georgia Tech student watching this,
you might already be working towards a Master's in CS,
and you might be wondering if the HCI specialization is available online.
Now right now while I'm recording this it's not,
but I'll pause for a second so Amanda can let us know if that's changed.
If you're an on-campus student watching this,
or if you're just watching the open MOOC,
then you might want to look into an MS and CS with a focus on HCI.
Most MS, CS programs I've seen have an HCI specialization,
or at least an HCI focus.
The specialization lets you go far deeper into the field
taking several classes on topics like core HCI,
User Interface Design, Educational Technology,
Mixed Reality Design, Information Visualization and more.
We'll gather a list of schools with MS,
CS programs with HCI specializations and provide it in the notes below.