If you already have a strong background in CS,
you might want to go all the way to getting a master's specifically in HCI.
These programs aren't as common as MSCS Programs with HCI specializations,
but many universities do have them including Georgia Tech, Carnegie Mellon,
University of Washington, the University of Maryland,
Iowa State University, and the Rochester Institute of Technology.
I myself completed the MS-HCI program here at Georgia Tech,
before starting my PhD.
In focusing an entire master's degree in HCI,
you'll find you have even more time to spend getting into
the relationship between HCI and some other fields.
At Georgia Tech for example,
the MS-HCI program has specializations in interactive computing,
psychology, industrial design and digital media.
That allows the flexibility to focus on different areas of HCI like,
how to integrate with physical devices in industrial design,
and how it helps us understand human cognition in psychology.
Most masters programs in HCI that I've seen are also heavily project focused,
Carnegie Mellon for example,
provides sponsored capstone projects from industry,
and every student in
Georgia Tech's MS-HCI program completes a six credit hour independent project.
So, if you're really set on moving forward with a career in HCI,
a dedicated masters in the field is a great way to move forward.