Finally, the highest level of educational achievement in HCI is likely a PhD,
specifically in HCI or similar field.
Here at Georgia Tech and at schools like Clemson and Maryland,
that's a PhD in Human-Centered Computing which is actually what my PhD was in.
Other schools have PhDs in similar fields, Carnegie-Mellon,
Iowa State University, IUPUI,
and others have PhD programs in HCI specifically.
Pursuing a PhD in HCI or HCC lets you take
a deep dive into how humans and computers interact in our modern world.
You might dive deep into artificial intelligence,
and cognitive science using AI agents to reflect on how humans think.
You might delve into learning sciences and technology studying
the intersection between computers and education in depth.
You might focus on social computing and
how online communities function or how social media is changing our society,
or you might stick closer to the core of HCI
and focus on how people make sense of new technologies.
You might answer questions like,
"How do we give immediate feedback on motion controls?"
Or, "How do we adapt a user interface to the user's mood?"
There are enormous questions to answer.
I'm excited to see some of you move on to change the world in very profound ways.