No matter what you do next,
I hope you've enjoyed this foray into the world of human-computer interaction.
If you in this course feeling like you actually know less than when you started,
then that's perfectly fine.
My goal was not only to teach you about HCI,
but also to help you understand how big this community is.
I look forward to seeing you all go further in
community and make a difference in the world.
To close, I have to give a special thank you to Georgia Tech for creating
this fantastic online masters program in which I'm developing this course.
I'd also like to thank the HCI faculty at Georgia Tech
for letting me be the one to record this and bring it to you.
Most of all, I'd like to thank Amanda and Morgan,
my partners in creating this course for
being totally responsible for how amazing it's looked.
I like to think this isn't just a course about human-computer interaction,
but it's also an example of human-computer interactions,
humans using computers to teach about HCI in new and engaging ways.
Thank you for watching.