The ultimate goal of design in HCI is to
create interfaces that are both useful
and useable.
Useful means that the interface
allows the user to achieve some task,
but usefulness is a pretty low bar.
For example, a map is useful in finding
your way from one place to another, but
it isn't the most useable
thing in the world.
You have to keep track of where you are,
you have to plot your own route.
And you have to do all of
this while driving the car.
So before GPS navigation, people would
often manually write down the turns
before they actually started driving
somewhere that they hadn't been before.
So our big concern is usability.
That's where we get things
like navigation apps.
Notice how we have to focus on
understanding the task when we're
performing design.
If we set out to design a better map.
We probably wouldn't have ended
up with a navigation app.
It was through understanding the task of
navigation itself that we realized we
could offload a lot of the cognitive
load of navigation onto the interface,
closing the loop between the user and
the task of navigation.