To better understand how we might use these three views of the user,
let's see how we might apply them to a design challenge.
So, here we have the address entry screen on Tesla's Model S. At the top,
we have the text box that the user is entering text into.
Below, we have some results.
At the bottom, we have the keyboard that they actually use to enter their text.
Let's imagine we're trying to redesign it such that the user can enter
the address of their target destination more
quickly so that they can get on with navigation.
With the processor model,
we're strictly looking at the user's observable behavior.
So, we might construct a controlled study where we bring participants in,
give them addresses to enter and different interfaces to use,
and time them on different versions.
Whichever interface has the fastest times
would be the interface we might want to go with.
There are some benefits to using this model.
One big one is that we might actually be able to use existing data for this.
If we assume that every time a user brings up the search bar,
they're going to input an address and navigate to,
we can look back and look how long does it usually
take from opening that search bar to access starting navigation.
We might be able to do that on an absolutely massive quantity of data.
Another benefit of this is it enables objective comparisons.
That means we can compare this text entry screen to
a voice system or some other way of inputting addresses to
understand how different interfaces entirely or different modes
of interaction entirely can have different efficiencies associated with them.
Most importantly, those comparisons are objective.
There's no real interpretation involved in saying that it takes an average
of 5.2 seconds to go from entering an address to starting navigation.
That's just a descriptive statistic.
However, there are some pretty major drawbacks as well.
When we're employing the processor model,
we don't see the reason for the differences that we observe.
We have no real basis to understand why one interface performs better than the other.
We also can't differentiate by expertise.
Usually, when we're using the processor model,
we're working with expert users,
and we're not really worried about what they're thinking about.
For novices though, it's very difficult for
the processor model to understand what a novice finds confusing or misleading.
Most generally, the processor model is usually
good for optimization but not for redesign.
If we're making small changes like the size of
buttons or the responsiveness of the screen,
then it can help us compare and understand which interface is performing better.
But if we're going to try a comprehensive new redesign,
the processor model isn't very helpful.
It might be good for evaluating that new redesign once we've created it,
but it doesn't give us very much input on what we should include in that redesign.
If we shift to the predictor model,
then we're going to actually start asking our users for input.
We could bring them in for interviews,
conduct focus groups, send out surveys.
We can also show them prototypes for new interfaces and
have them describe their thought process while trying to interact with them.
We might find some simple changes that we wouldn't have stumbled upon otherwise.
For example, we might find that users find
a certain icon to be misleading compared to its real meaning.
We might also find some information about why users
choose different interfaces at different times.
For example, users might prefer the voice interface while
driving but this text interface while they're parked.
So, the big advantage here is that we get
a more complete picture of the user's interaction with the interface.
We get to ask them why they do certain things,
or what they're thinking about, or why they made certain choices.
Additionally, this model lets us target different levels of expertise.
We can bring in novices who've never seen
the interface before and say, "Take a look at this.
What do you think you should do next?"
But we could also bring in experts and have them reflect on how some new interface
might make it more or less efficient to accomplish what they want to accomplish.
But again, there are drawbacks.
One big drawback is that the analysis of this can be very expensive.
We're not looking at numbers and conducting a little statistical tests.
We're often looking at plain text transcripts of
interviews or plain text responses to surveys.
Analyzing those requires a lot of human attention and a lot of effort.
Even then, that analysis can be subject to biases.
If the person analyzing that data has
some suspicions about what they think the better interface would be,
they're very likely to imbue their analysis with
those biases and only focus on data that confirms what they already think was true.
So, we have to make sure that they control for those biases.
Additionally, when we're using the predictor model,
we're still usually ignoring the broader interaction context.
We're usually looking at the person in the interface,
but not the real authentic environment in which they usually use that interface.
For this interface, that could be a problem because we might have an interface
that works very well when it has the full user attention.
But it's significantly harder to use when the user is, for instance, driving.
For example, if we were only testing a new interface in a lab setting,
we might have a feature that hides what the user has been searching for if
they haven't entered any new text or made a selection in the past five seconds.
In a lab setting, that's probably fine because our users are
generally only focused on the task that we're giving them,
which is entering some address into that search bar.
But if they're actually out driving,
they might start entering an address at one red light,
had light turn green and want to pause,
and continue entering it at the next red light.
If it disappears after five seconds,
that's not really aware of the way they're using it in the real environment.
So, that's where the participant model comes in.
With a participant model,
we view the interface and the user in the context in which they actually interact.
We want to look at the user in the interface as participants in some broader activity,
the broader activity of driving,
not just as a user interacting with one interface.
Now, the benefit of this should be pretty obvious.
It evaluates the interaction in context.
We can understand things like the driver is distracted or they're
going to do things in different batches as it come to different red lights.
We also capture an authentic representation of the user's level of attention.
If the user is going to be distracted, for example,
we'll see that when we analyze the activity
and the authentic contexts in which it takes place.
But unsurprisingly, there are also drawbacks to this approach to.
Just as the predictor model suggested evaluations that were difficult to analyze,
the participant model emphasizes evaluations that can actually be difficult to perform.
To evaluate this interface in the authentic contexts in which it's used,
we need to actually go right along with participants.
That's a lot harder to do than just sending out a survey
or bring people into our controlled lab environment.
It also means we need to have real functional interfaces.
We can't have a person driving a car and keep holding up
some prototype next to them while they're actually trying to drive.
We need these interfaces to actually be
designed and implemented to work in that real context.
So, it's hard to use this model when we're just getting started with a new design task.
Finally, using the participant model means that we're
exposing ourselves to a lot of uncontrollable variables.
The more that's going on in the environment,
the harder it is to zoom in and focus only on the impact of our designs.
Now, hopefully you'll notice that the pros of some
of these models address to cons of others.
The processor model, for example,
doesn't give us much insight into what novices are thinking.
But the predictor model is particularly good at targeting novices.
To predict a model makes it difficult to conduct real objective comparisons.
That's exactly what the processor model is good for.
Neither the processor nor the predictor model take into consideration context,
but that's what we get when we consider the participant model.
But it doesn't isolate variables very well.
It's subject to interference from things that we can't control.
But the processor model is very good at isolating those variables.
So the major takeaway here is it will likely use
all of these different models at different times and in different contexts.
The data we gather from one might inform what we do with another.
We might start with a participant model or we
just ride around with users watching what they do.
Based on that, we might observe that they spend a lot of time
fumbling around a return to the same few locations.
So, we might redesign an interface to include some kind of
bookmarking system and present it to users in interviews.
There, they might tell us they like that design,
but further note, they don't need a long list of bookmarks.
They really only need work and home.
So based on that, we might then design an interface where
a simple swipe takes him to work or to home depending on where they are right now.
In fact, that's how that Tesla navigation screen works.
If you just swipe across to navigate button,
it'll automatically take you to work if you're at home,
or home if you're at work.
Then, finally, we might test it with the processor model to see just how much
more efficiently that new interface allows users to put in their destination.
The results of each design phase inform the next,
and different phases call for different types of evaluation,
which echoed the different models of the user.