[MUSIC]
Good design,
a GPS system that warns you 20 seconds
before you need to make a turn.
>> In 1,000 feet, turn left.
>> Bad design,
a GPS system that warns you two seconds
before you need to make a turn.
>> Turn left now, hurry.
[SOUND]
>> It sounds funny, but which view you
take on the user can have a huge impact
on the success of the interface.
If you view the user just as a sensory
processor, you might think that we only
need to alert them a second
before the upcoming turn because,
after all, human reaction
time is less than a second.
If you view the user as a predictor,
you understand they need time to slow
the car down and actually make the turn.
So they might need a few more seconds
to execute the action of turning
before being alerted they need to turn.
And if you view the user as
a participant, you'll understand this is
happening while they're going 50 miles
down the road with a screaming toddler
in the backseat, trying to merge
with the driver on a cell phone and
the other one eating a cheeseburger.
So it would probably be a good idea to
give them a few or more reminders before
the turn and plenty of time
to get in the right position.