For me, we have a system at
Udacity we use to record hours for
those of us that work on
some contract projects.
It asks us to enter the number of hours
of the day we spend on each of a number
of different types of work.
The problem is that,
that assumes something closely
resembling the processor model.
A computer can easily track how
long different processes take.
But for me, checking the amount of
time spent on different tasks can be
basically impossible.
Checking my e-mails involves switching
between five different tasks a minute.
How am I suppose to track that?
The system doesn't take into
consideration a realistic view
of my role in the system.
Something more similar to
the predictor view would be, well,
the classroom you're viewing this in.
Surrounding this video are a visual
organization of the lesson's content,
a meter measuring your
progress through the video,
representations of
the video's transcript.
These are all meant to equip you with
the knowledge to predict what's coming
next.
This classroom takes
a predictor view of the user.
It offloads some of the cognitive
load onto the interface
allowing you to focus on the material.
For the third view I personally would
consider my alarm clock an example.
I use an alarm clock app called Sleep.
It monitors my sleep cycles,
rings at the optimal time and
tracks my sleep patterns
to make recommendations.
It understand its role as part of a
broader system needed to help me sleep.
It goes far beyond just interaction
between me and an interface.
It integrates into the entire system.