By my definition, user experience design
is attempting to create systems that
dictate how the user
will experience them.
Preferably that the user will
experience them positively.
User experience in general, though,
is a phenomenon that emerges
out of the interactions between
humans and tasks via interfaces.
We might attempt to
design that experience.
But whether we design it or not,
there is a user experience.
It's kind of like the weather,
there's never no weather,
there's never no user experience.
It might be a bad experience if
we don't design it very well.
But there's always some user experience
going on and it emerges as a result of
the human's interactions with
the task via the interface.
But user experience also goes
beyond this simple interaction.
It touches on the emotional,
personal, and
more experiential elements
of the relationship.
We can build this by
expanding our understanding
of the scope of the user experience.
For just a particular individual, this
is based on things like the individual's
age, sex, or race, personal experiences,
gender, expectations for
the interface, and more.
It goes beyond just designing
an interface to help with a task.
It touches on whether the individual
feels like the interface was
designed for them.
It examines whether they're frustrated
by the interface or joyous about it.
Those are all parts of
this user experience.
We can take this further and talk about
user experience at a group level.
We can start to think about how
interfaces lead to different user
experiences among social or work groups.
For example, I've known that school
reunions seem to be much less important
to people who've graduated
within the past 15 years.
And I hypothesize it's
because Facebook and
email have played such significant
roles in keeping people in touch.
It's fundamentally changed
the social to group user experience.
Those effects can then scope all
the way up to the societal level.
Sometimes these are unintended.
For example, I doubt that the creators
of Twitter, foresaw when they created
their tool, how it would play a
significant role in big societal changes
like the Arab spring or,
sometimes these might be intentional.
For example, it was a significant change
when Facebook added new relationship
statuses to its profiles to
reflect things like civil unions.
That simultaneously reflected
something that was already changing at
the societal level.
But it also participated
in that change and
helped normalize those
kinds of relationships.
And that then relates back to
the individual by making sure
the interface is designed such that
each individual feels like it's actually
designed with them in mind.
The options are there for
them to feel like they're properly
represented within the system.
These are all components of
the general user experience
that we need to think about
as we design interfaces.