One of the most exciting parts of
HCI is it's incredible ubiquity.
Computers are all around us and
we interact with them everyday.
It's exciting to think about
designing the types of tools and
interfaces we spend so much time dealing
with, but there's a danger here too.
Because we're all humans
interacting with computers,
we think we're experts at
human-computer interaction.
But that's not the case.
We might be experts at interacting with
computers, but that doesn't make us
experts at designing interactions
between other humans and computers.
We're like professional athletes or
world-class scientists.
Just because we're experts doesn't mean
we know how to help other people also
become experts.
In my experience,
many people look at HCI like this.
The red dot represents
what they know and
the black circle represents what
they think there's to know.
They know there's probably somethings
they don't know yet, but they're
already pretty at it, and it wouldn't
be too hard to become an expert.
After studying HCI for a bit though,
they look more like this.
You can see that they've
increased what they know but
their perception of what there
is to know has grown even more.
That's the journey we'll
be taking together.
You'll learn to do work in HCI,
but perhaps more importantly,
you'll learn how complex and
large the field of HCI is.
Your knowledge will increase,
but yet you might exit the class
less confident in your HCI
ability than when you started.
You're taking the first
step into a larger world.