In this lesson, we've covered some of the basic things you need to
understand before we start talking about design principles.
We covered the idea that interfaces mediate between users and tasks,
and the best interfaces are those that let the user spend
as much time thinking about the task as possible.
We covered the idea of usability and how you have to
keep in mind the efficiency and user satisfaction of the interface.
We covered three views of the user and how
those different views affect how we define usability and evaluation.
We covered how the user experience does not exist just at the user
level but also at group and even societal levels.