Feedback cycles are incredibly
ubiquitous, whether or
not there's a computational
interface involved.
Everything from reading to driving
a car to interacting with other people
could be an example of
a feedback cycle in action.
They're how we learn everything, from
how to walk to how to solve a Rubik's
cube to how to take the third order
partial derivative of a function.
I assume, I've never done that.
We do something, we see the result, and
we adjust what we do
the next time accordingly.
You may have even seen other
examples of this before, too.
If you've taken Ashok's and
mine knowledge-based AI class,
we talk about how agents are constantly
interacting with, learning from, and
affecting the world around them.
That's a feedback cycle.
If you've taken cyber
physical systems course,
you've seen this this without
human involved at all,
as a system can autonomously read
input and react accordingly.
Under some definitions, some people
would even call this the artificial
intelligence, specifically because it
mimics what a human actually does.
They act in the world and
they evaluate the result.
In fact, if you look at some of the
definitions of intelligence out there,
you'll find that many people actually
define feedback cycles as the hallmark
of intelligent behavior.
Or they might define intelligence
as abilities that must be
gained through feedback cycles.
Colvin's definition, for example,
involves adjusting to one's environment,
which means acting in it and
then evaluating the results.
Dearborn's definition of learning or
profiting by experience
is exactly this as well.
You do something and experience
the results, and learn from it.
Adaptive behavior in general
can be considered an example of
a feedback cycle.
Behavior means acting in the world.
And adapting means
processing the results and
changing your behavior accordingly.
And most generally, Schank's definition
is clearly an ability gained through
feedback cycles, getting better over
time based on evaluation of the results
of one's actions in the world.
And Schank's general definition, getting
better over time, is clearly something
that can happen as a result of
participation in a feedback cycle.
We find that nearly all of HCI can
be interpreted in some ways as
an application of feedback cycles,
whether between a person and
a task, a person and
an interface, or systems comprised of
multiple people and multiple interfaces.