In our feedback cycle diagram, we have
on the left, some user and on the right,
some task or system.
The user puts some input into
the system through the interface and
the system communicates some output back
to the user again through the interface.
Incumbent on this are two
general challenges,
the user's interaction with
the task through the interface and
the task's return to the user
of the output via the interface.
The first is called
the Gulf of execution.
The Gulf of execution can be defined
as how do I know what I can do.
The user has some goals.
How do they figure out how to
make those goals a reality?
How do they figure out
what actions to take
to make the state of the system
match their goal state?
This is the Gulf of execution.
How hard is it to do in
the interface what is necessary
to accomplish the users' goals?
Or alternatively, what's
the difference between what the user
thinks they should have to do and
what they actually have to do.
Now there are a number
of components of this.
The first component, they need to be
able to identify what their goal is
in the context of the system.
There might be a mismatch between
their own understanding and
the system's structure.
Think of transitioning from an
old-fashioned VCR to a more modern DVR
or from a DVR to watching
things on-demand.
The user needs to think of their goal
in terms of their current system.
Second, they need to be able to
identify the actions necessary
to accomplish their goals.
Now that they know what their goal is in
the context of the system, they need to
identify the actions that it will
take to make that goal a reality.
And third,
once I've identified those actions,
they need to actually execute
the actions within the interface.
Again, imagine someone who's learning
to use an on demand video interface,
when they're used to using
things like VCRs and DVRs.
Their goal hasn't changed.
They want to watch some
program that's already aired.
But in the context of a VCR or
a DVR, their intention might
be to record that program.
In the context of an on
demand video interface,
their intentions instead are to call up
the existing version of that program.
That's a mismatch between what
they think their goal is and
what their goal is in
the context of this new system.
But once they understand what the goal
means in their current system,
they now need to know how
to pull up that program.
They need to know how to
navigate the menus and
find the program that they want to
watch and then start it playing.
And then once they know what to do,
they need to actually execute
that series of button presses.
For example, they might know
what actions to perform but
they might not know where to find them.
That would present a difficulty
in executing those actions.
So the gulf of execution takes the user
from understanding their own goals
to understanding their goals
in the context of the system,
to understanding the actions
necessary to realize those goals,
to actually executing those actions.
And each of these presents
some difficulties.