Let's take a simple example
of the gulf of execution.
I'm making my lunch, I have my
bowl of chili in the microwave.
My goal is simple, I want to heat it up.
How hard is that?
Well, typically when I've
been cooking in the past,
cooking is defined in terms of
the amount of time it takes.
So, in the context of this system, I
specify my intent as to microwave it for
one minute.
Now what are the actions
necessary to do so?
I press Time Cook to enter
the time-cooking mode, I enter the time,
one minute, and I press Start.
I didn't press Start just now,
but I would press Start.
I specified my intent,
microwave for one minute.
I specified my actions, pressing
the right sequence of buttons, and
I executed those actions.
Could we make this better?
There were a lot of button presses
to microwave for just one minute.
If we think that's a common behavior,
we might be able to make it simpler.
Instead of pressing Time Cook one,
zero, zero and Start,
I might just press one and wait.
Watch.
[NOISE] So I've narrowed the gulf of
execution by shrinking the number
of actions required, but
I may have enlarged it by making it more
difficult to identify
the actions required.
When I look at the microwave,
Time Cook gives me an idea
of what that button does.
So if I'm a novice at this, I can
discover how to accomplish my goal.
That's good for the gulf of execution.
It's easier to look at the button and
figure out what to do than to have to go
look, read a manual, or anything
like that and find out on your own.
But once you know that all
you have to do is press one,
that's much easier to execute.
That's something nice about this
interface, it caters to both novices and
experts, there's a hard and discoverable
way and a short and visible way.
But let's rewind all the way back
to the goal I set up initially,
my goal was to heat up my chili.
I specified my intent in terms of the
system as microwaving it for one minute.
But was that the right thing to do?
After one minute, my chili might not be
hot enough, this microwave actually has
an automatic reheat function that
senses the food's temperature and
stops when the time seems right.
So the best bridge over the gulf of
execution might also involve helping me
reframe my intention.
Instead of going to microwave for one
minute, it might encourage me to reframe
this as simply heating until ready and
letting the microwave do the rest.