In Don Norman's Design of Everyday Things,
he provides a different way of looking at the same information.
This diagram puts a greater emphasis on what the user is doing at each of these stages.
The user is setting a goal,
and then planning, and specifying,
and performing, and then perceiving,
and interpreting, and comparing.
This diagram also changes our terminology a bit and with good reason.
We see a bridge of execution and a bridge of evaluation.
The reason for that is these behaviors specifically
bridge the gulf between the goal and the world.
They're what the user has to do to make the world match their goal,
and then confirm that the world now does match their goal.
Norman uses these stages to introduce seven questions
that we should ask ourselves when we're designing interfaces.
First, how easily can one determine the function of the device?
In other words, how easily can one tell that this device can accomplish that goal?
Second, how easily can one tell what actions are possible to do with the device?
Third, how easily can the user determine the mapping from
their intent to the actual movements or actions they need to take with the device?
So, in planning to figuring out what they can
do with specifying to figuring out what they should do.
Then finally, how easily can the user actually
perform the physical movements associated with that plan?
After they've done these three stages,
something has happened in the world,
and they're ready to see if they can perceive what has changed.
So, then we ask, how easily can the user perceive or tell what state the system is in?
This is the raw information that they're getting out of the system.
Then how easily can they tell if the system is in the desired state,
or how easily can they interpret what they perceived?
Then finally, how easily can the user determine the mapping from state to interpretation?
In other words, how easily can the user compare what
they interpreted as happening to what they wanted to happen?
You'll notice that these match our stages from earlier.
Norman also makes it even more clear by describing this
specifically in terms of what the user is thinking.
The user starts by thinking,
"What do I want to do?"
Then they consider, "What are the alternatives for accomplishing it?"
Then they specify, "What can I do to actually perform one of those alternatives?"
Then they ask, "How do I do that?"
Once they've done it, they ask, "What happened?
What does that mean? Is that okay?"
I like this phrasing because it makes the distinction
between interpreting and comparing a little easier.
Interpreting is just about understanding what happened.
Comparing involves going back to the original goal that the user had.
Norman also further articulates this by breaking the process
into phases that span both execution and evaluation.
Closest to the world, he has the visceral phase which is
the actual physical activity or the raw perceptions.
Above that, he has the behavioral layer,
which is where we're actually specifying what behaviors to
do or interpreting the outcome of those behaviors.
Then at the top level, there's a reflective phase,
which is thinking about the problem and planning our solution,
or comparing the results to our original goal.
If we change his vocabulary a little bit,
we might describe this lowest level as raw reaction,
the middle level as deliberation,
and the top level as metacognition,
thinking about the goal,
thinking about the problem solving process,
thinking about what we did and what happened.
If we rewrite these phases with this vocabulary,
we start to get at a diagram you might recognize if you've taken knowledge-based AI.
If you haven't, here's a little teaser for what you'll see if you do.