Before cars had push button starts,
this is where you inserted
the key to turn on the ignition.
Why?
I have no idea.
But I do know that now,
the start button can be placed in
any number of different locations.
So why do we put it where
we've always put it?
Well, the reason is, that's where
the driver expects it to be placed.
We help them across the gulf of
execution by designing a system that's
consistent with their expectations
about how it should work.
It makes it easier for them to translate
their intentions into actions.
Now, other times we might violate this
principle because of some other benefits
we hope to gain.
But generally speaking,
when all else is equal,
we want to stay consistent with the way
users expect our systems to work.