First, let's start by comparing HCI to the broader field of human factors.
Human factors is interested in designing interactions
between people and products, systems or devices.
That should sound familiar. We're interested in
designing the interactions between people and computers,
but computers are themselves products or systems.
But human factors is interested in non-computing parts of this as well.
Let's take an example. I have
a pretty new electric car which means there are tons of computers all over it.
From an HCI perspective,
I might be interested in visualizing the data on
the dashboard or helping the driver control the radio.
Human factors is interested not only in how I
interact with the computerized parts of the car,
but the non computerized parts as well.
It's interested in things like the height of the steering wheel,
the size of the mirrors, or the position of the chair.
It's interested in designing the entire environment,
not just the electronic elements.
But that means it's interested in a lot of
the same human characteristics that we care about,
like how people perceive the world and their own expectations about it.
So, many of the principles we'll discuss in
this class come from human factors engineering,
applied more narrowly to computerized systems.
But the exciting thing is that as computers become more and more ubiquitous,
the number of application areas for HCI is growing.
Twenty years ago, a car might not have been an application of HCI.
Ten years ago, a wristwatch would have been more about industrial design than HCI.
Within only the past couple years,
things like shower heads and refrigerators
has started to become truly computerized devices.
As computers integrate themselves into more and more of our devices,
the gap between human-computer interaction and human factors engineering is shrinking.
As computers become more and more ubiquitous,
there's coming a time when pretty much every single thing on
your car will actually be run through a computer. Don't believe me?
Check out the inside of Tesla's Model S. When you look at the console of a Tesla,
almost everything you see is a giant computer.
Cars have become computers on wheels,
watches have become computers on wristbands,
car keys have become computers on key chains.
Computers are everywhere, and so HCI is everywhere.