Lately I've encountered
another interesting example of
feedback cycles in action.
You may have actually
seen this before as well.
They're the new credit card readers.
My wife sells arts and
crafts at local events, and so
she has these Square readers that
can scan credit cards on her phone.
One version lets you swipe, and the new
version lets you insert the card.
So let's check this out real quick.
With the swipe version you just
insert the card and pull it through,
just like a traditional card reader.
The problem is there's typically no
feedback on whether you're swiping
correctly.
And what's more is you can
be wrong in both directions.
You can be both too fast or too slow.
So you may have had a time when you were
trying to swipe a credit card on some
kind of reader, and you kept doing it
more and more slowly and deliberately,
thinking that the problem was that
you had done it too fast originally.
And then you discover that you've
actually been going too slowly all along
and your slowing down was
actually counterproductive.
There's no feedback here and
the space and acceptable input
is bounded on both sides.
You have to go above one speed and
below another speed.
But now credit card readers
are moving to this model where
you just insert the card.
You try, at least.
In terms of feedback cycles,
in what ways is this actually better?