First, in terms of
the gulf of execution,
the insertion method is actually
physically easier to do.
While you can be both too fast and
too slow with the sliding method,
you can't push it too far in
with the insertion method.
So you know if there's an error,
it's because the card isn't
far enough into the reader.
And second, there's rich feedback
with the insertion method.
It doesn't even have to come from
the screen telling you that you didn't
do it correctly.
You feel the card stop when it's
far enough into the reader.
You have immediate physical feedback on
whether you're putting it in the right
place, and whether you've actually put
it far enough in, rather than delayed
feedback asking you to try again
after some kind of waiting period.