So, using the insertion method
is significantly easier.
However, the insertion method
introduces a new problem.
With the sliding method, I never had to
actually physically let go of my card,
so there was little chance of
me walking away without it.
With the insertion method,
I insert the card and I wait.
I'm not used to having to remember to
retrieve my card from the card reader.
Now this isn't quite as big a deal with
these new portable readers, but for
the mounted ones you see in stores
it can be far more problematic.
So how can we build some feedback
into the system to make sure people
remember their cards
when they walk away?