The problem is that we're not
focused on the right task.
Our task shouldn't be to swipe a credit
card, or insert a credit card, or
anything like that.
Our task should be how to most
easily pay for purchases.
And possibly the easiest way to do that
would be to design a system that lets
you just tap your phone against the
reader, this reader actually does that.
That way, we can use the thing that
people have on them at all times.
Now maybe that's isn't
the best option for
various other reasons, but the important
thing is we need to focus on what we're
really trying to accomplish.
Not just how we've done it in the past.
We can make incremental improvements
just sliding or swiping or
inserting a credit card all we want.
But we should always keep our
eyes on the underlying task
that the user needs to accomplish.