Today, we've talked about, arguably,
the most fundamental concept of human-computer interaction, feedback cycles.
We describe feedback cycles for our purposes as the exchange of input
and output between a user and a system to accomplish some goal.
We discussed feedback cycles' incredible ubiquity in other fields and discussions.
We talked about gulf of execution,
the distance between knowing what they want to accomplish and
actually executing the steps necessary to accomplish it.
We talked about gulf of evaluation,
the distance between making some change in
the system and evaluating whether or not the goal was accomplished.
We introduced the seven questions we need to ask ourselves to bridge those gulfs.
Now that we understand these goals,
our next goal is to understand methods for crossing them.