[MUSIC]
Today we'll talk about two
applications of good feedback cycles.
Direct manipulation and
invisible interfaces.
Direct manipulation is the principle
that the user should feel as much as
possible like they're directly
controlling the object of their task.
So for example, if you're trying
to enlarge an image on your phone,
it might be better to be able
to drag it with your fingers
rather than tapping a button that says,
zoom in.
That way you're really interacting
directly with the photo.
New technologies like touch
screens are making it more and
more possible to feel like we're
directly manipulating something,
even when there's
an interface in the way.
At their best,
the interface actually disappears,
which is what we mean by
an invisible interface.
With an invisible interface
the user has to spend no time
thinking about the interface
that they're using.
All their time is dedicated to thinking
about the task that they're performing.