For many years,
human-computer interaction was
largely about user interface design.
The earliest innovations in HCI were the
creation of things like the light pen,
the first computer mouse,
which allow for
flexible interaction
with things on screen.
But the focus was
squarely on the screen.
And so, we developed many principles
about how to design things nicely
for a screen.
We borrowed from the magazine and print
industries and identify the value of
grids in displaying content and guiding
the users eyes around our interfaces.
We created laws that govern
how difficult it is for
users to select what
they want on screen.
We examined for example whether it's
easier to select a menu on a Mac,
where the menus are always
at the top of the screen.
Or on a PC, where they're grouped
with the individual window.
We develop techniques for
helping interfaces adapt to different
screen sizes and we develop methods for
rapidly prototyping user interfaces
using pen and paper or wire frames.
Through this rich history,
UI design really became its
own well defined field.
In fact,
many of the concepts we'll cover in HCI
were originally developed in
the context of UI design.
But in HCI, we're interested in
things that go beyond the user's
interaction with a single screen.
Technically, you an cover that in UI
design as well, but traditionally most
of the UI design classes I see
focus on on-screen interaction.
In HCI, we'll talk about the more
general methods that apply to
any interface.