Our goal is to narrow
the gulf of execution and
the gulf of evaluation
as much as possible.
And arguably the ultimate form of this
is something called direct manipulation.
Now today direct manipulation is
a very common interaction style.
But in the history of HCI it was
a revolutionary new approach.
Now to understand direct manipulation,
let's talk about the desktop metaphor.
The files and folders on your computer
are meant to mimic physical files and
folders on a desktop.
So, here are on my physical desktop,
I have some files.
What do I do if I want to move them?
Well, I pick them up and I move them.
What do I do if I want
to put them in a folder?
I pick them up and
put them in the folder.
I'm physically moving the files from
where they are to where
I want them to be.
If files and folders on a computer
are meant to mimic files and
folders on a physical desk, then
shouldn't the act of moving them also
mimic the real world
action of moving them?
Wouldn't it narrow the gulf execution to
leverage that real world experience and
that real world expectation?