Files and folders on my computer
are meant to mimic files and
folders on my physical desk.
So we ideally want the action of
moving them around on my computer to
mimic the action of moving them
around on my physical desk.
But it wasn't always like this.
Before graphical user
interfaces were common,
we moved files around using
command line interfaces like this.
The folder structure is still
the same on the operating system.
But instead of visualizing
it as folders and icons,
I'm interacting with
a text-based command line.
To view the files,
I might need to type a command like ls,
which I just have to remember.
If I don't remember that command,
I don't have much recourse to go find
out what I'm supposed to be doing.
To move a file,
I need to type something like this.
I have to type the command,
the file I want to move,
and the folder I want to move it to.
Again, if I forget the name of that
command, or the order of the parameters
to provide, there's not a whole
lot I can to to recover from that.
I need to run off to Google and
find out what the correct
order of the commands was.
Which is actually what I did before
filming this video because I don't
actually use the terminal very often.
Then when I execute that command,
there's not a lot of feedback to let me
know if it actually executed correctly.
I might need to change
folders to find out.
There I see the files present in
that folder but I had to go and
look manually.
There's nothing really
natural about this.
Now don't get me wrong, once you know
how to interact with this interface,
it's very efficient to use.
But when you're a novice at it, when
you've never used it before, this is
completely unlike the task of managing
physical files on your real desk.
Then, the computer mouse came along.
And with it came the ability to
move a mouse around the screen.
Equipped with this,
my action in moving files and
folders becomes much more direct.
I can actually just click
the file I want to move and
drag it into the new folder.
I get instant feedback by the fact
that the file disappeared as soon as I
dragged it over.
And there was a sound effect that you
may or may not have been able to hear.
So now instead of typing in some cryptic
command that I just have to be able
remember, I can just click on
the file I want to move, and
physically drag it to the folder
in which I want to have it.
That's a very natural interaction,
it mimics what I do on my physical desk.
Moving the mouse around is a lot better
than having to type in those commands,
but the gulf of execution and evaluation
are still present, especially for
some novice users.
There's still some interpretation that
has to happen to understand that when I
move my hand a little left on the mouse,
the cursor on screen will
move to the left as well.
And while clicking feels
kind of like grabbing,
there's still some interpretation there.
It's more direct than the command line,
but there's still a gap.
The modern touchscreens made direct
manipulation more direct than ever.
Let's say I want to put an icon
into a folder on my screen.
How do I do it?
I hold down the icon, and
I drag it to the screen.
The fact that if I wanted to
move something around my desk,
I would have to hold it down,
means that this is almost
entirely direct manipulation.
I don't need any prior knowledge to
attempt to do what feels natural for
moving that icon into that folder.
That gives us a nice,
general heuristic to keep in mind.
How do we help the user interact most
closely with the target of their task?
How do we make it so they're
manipulating it as directly as possible?