The seminal paper on direct manipulation interfaces came out in 1985,
co-authored by Edwin Hutchins,
James Hollan, and Don Norman.
We'll talk a lot more about Hutchins and Norman later in our conversations.
Hutchins coauthored the foundational paper on Distributed Cognition,
and Norman created one of the most accepted set of
design principles in his seminal book Design of Everyday Things.
But in 1985, direct manipulation was starting to become a more common design strategy.
Hutchins, Hollan, and Norman identified two aspects of directness.
The first was distance.
Distance is the distance between the users goals and the system itself.
This is the idea of goals of execution and
evaluation that we talk about in the context of feedback cycles.
They write that, "The feeling of directness is inversely proportional to
the amount of cognitive effort it takes to manipulate and evaluate the system."
In other words, the greater the cognitive load required to use the system,
the less direct to the interaction with the system actually feels.
The authors break distance in the two components.
Semantic distance and articulatory distance.
Semantic distance refers to the difference between
the users goals and their expression in the system.
In other words, it's how hard it is to know what to do.
Articulatory distance is the distance between that expression and its execution.
In other words, it's how hard it is to actually do what you know to do.
You might notice that semantic distance encompasses
our identify intentions and identify actions parts of our gulf of execution,
and articulatory distance comprises that execute actions phase.
This is brought together here in figure six from this paper. Yeah, there we go.
The user starts with some goals,
and translates those goals into the intentions in the context of the interface.
They then translate those intentions into the form of the input,
the actions, and execute those actions.
The system then does something,
and gives back some form of output.
The user then interprets the form of that output to discern the meaning of that output,
and then evaluates whether or not that meaning matches their goals.
So to take an example,
when I brought up this figure,
I needed to rotate the paper to display it correctly, that was my goal.
I translated that goal into the context of the application,
a rotate option that was probably hidden somewhere.
I then identified the action,
which was pressing the rotate button,
and I executed that action.
The system then did something and returned the output to me.
The output specifically was the paper turned
upside down instead of turning the way I wanted it.
That was the form of the output.
I then interpreted that form to discern the meaning that it had rotated at the wrong way.
I evaluated that my goals weren't accomplished,
and now I knew what to do next.
I then pressed the button two more times to rotate it twice again,
and the system then return that output to me.
I interpreted the form of that output to mean that the figure was now right-side up,
and I evaluated that that matched my initial goals.
You might be able to see that this cycle is happening
constantly whenever you're interacting with the computational interface.
You could think of it in terms of broad tasks like searching a document for some keyword,
or you could think of it in terms of each individual little tasks
like interacting with the menus and pulling up the right prompts.
But distance is only one component of direct manipulation.
It's possible to have interfaces with very little distance that
nonetheless are not examples of this kind of direct interaction.
Everything we've talked about so far is true of feedback cycles in general,
not just of direct manipulation.
That's why the second component of this is direct engagement.
What sets direct manipulation apart is the second component.
The authors of the paper write that,
"The systems that best exemplify direct manipulation,
all give the qualitative feeling that one is directly
engaged with control of the objects not with the programs,
not with the computer, but with the semantic objects of our goals and intentions."
If we're moving files, we should be physically moving the representation of the files.
If we're playing a game we should be directly controlling our characters.
If we're navigating channels,
we should be specifically selecting clear representations of the channels that we want.
And that's what takes a general good feedback cycle,
and makes it an instance of direct manipulation.
We can shorten the gulf of execution and
evaluation in a number of ways without direct manipulation,
but direct manipulation is a powerful method for shortening that distance.