Virtual reality right now is making some incredible strides in facilitating
direct manipulation in places where it just hasn't been possible before.
Traditionally, when designers are designing stuff in 3D,
they are forced to use a 2D interface,
that translation from 2D to 3D really gets in
the way of directly manipulating whatever is being designed.
Through virtual reality though,
designers are able to view what they're designing in
3D as if it's in the room there with them.
They can rotate it around with
the same hand motions you'd use to rotate a physical object.
They can physically move around the object to get different angles on it.
So, virtual reality is allowing us to bring the principle of
direct manipulation to tasks it hasn't been able to touch before,
but there's still a lot of work to do.
Gesture interfaces like those used in virtual reality struggle with some feedback issues.
We aimed to make the user feel like they're physically manipulating the artifact.
When you're working with something with your hands,
it pushes back against you.
How do we recreate that in virtual reality?