When I was writing the script for
this exact video,
I was interrupted by a text
message from a friend of mine.
And in the reply I was writing,
I wanted to include a smiley face.
We know that using emojis and emoticons
tends to humanize textual communication.
On my phone, the interface for inserting
an emoji is to tap an icon to bring up
a list of all the emojis and
then select the one that you want.
When I'm reacting to
someone in conversation,
I'm not mentally scrolling through
a list of all my possible emotions and
then choosing the one that corresponds.
I'm just reacting naturally.
Why can't my phone capture that?
Instead of having to select
smiling from a list of emotions,
maybe my phone could just have a button
to insert the emotion corresponding to
my current facial expression.
So to wink, I would just wink.
To frown, I would just frown.
It wouldn't be possible to capture
every possible face, but for
some of the most commonly used ones,
it might be more efficient.