There may be no better example of
the power of direct manipulation than
watching a baby use an interface.
Let's watch my daughter, Lucy,
try and use her Kindle Fire tablet.
My daughter Lucy is 18 months old, yet
when I give her an interface that uses
direct manipulation,
she's able to use it.
She wouldn't be able to use a keyboard
or a mouse yet, but because she's
directly interacting with the things
on the screen, she can use it.
Actually, there might be an even better
example of direct manipulation in
action.
There are games made for
tablet computers for cats.
Yes, cats can use tablet computers
when they use direct manipulation.