Now there's some room for
disagreement here, but
I think these five seem
to be pretty cut and dry.
We can think about whether or
not these are direct manipulation by
considering whether or not what we're
doing to the touchpad is what we'd
like to do to the screen itself.
For clicking, I would consider that
direct manipulation because just as we
press directly on the screen we're
pressing directly on a touchpad.
Right-clicking though,
the two finger tap, doesn't really
exemplify direct manipulation, because
there's nothing natural about using
two fingers to bring up a context menu
as opposed to using one to click.
We have to kind of learn that behavior.
Scrolling makes sense because with
scrolling it's like I'm physically
pulling the page up and
down to see different portions of it.
The two finger tap for zooming in and
out a little bit though isn't
really direct manipulation,
because there's no real clear reason
that needs to zoom in, zoom out.
Pinching on the other hand though,
makes sense.
Because it's as if I'm
physically grabbing the page and
shrinking and enlarging it.
So some of these I would say are pretty
good examples of direct manipulation.
While others are things that
we kind of have learn to do.