The Mac Touchpad has some interesting
examples of how you can make indirect
manipulation feel more direct.
For example, if I swipe from the right
to the left on the touchpad with two
fingers, it pulls up this notification
center over on the right.
This feels direct because
the notification center popped up in
the same place on the screen
that I swiped on the touchpad.
The touchpad is almost like
a miniature version of the screen.
But they could have placed
a notification center anywhere and
used any kind of
interaction to pull it up.
This isn't like scrolling where there is
something fundamental about the content
that demands a certain
kind of interaction.
They could have designed
this however they wanted.
But by placing the notification
center there and
using that interaction to pull it up,
it feels more direct.
Now, animation can also
help us accomplish this.
On the Touchpad, I can clear the windows
off my desktop by kind of spreading out
my fingers on the touchpad, and
the animation shows them
going off to the side.
And while that's kind of
like clearing off your desk,
I'd argue it's not close enough to feel
direct except that the animation on
screen mimics that action as well.
The windows could have faded away or
they could have just
slid to the bottom and
still accomplish the same function
of hiding what's on my desktop.
But the animation they chose
reinforces that interaction.
It makes it feel more direct.
The same thing actually applies with
Launchpad, which we bring up with
the opposite function by
pinching our fingers together.
The animation looks kind of like
we're pulling back a little bit or
zooming out and
we see the launch pad come into view,
just as the gesture is similar
to zooming out on the screen.
So direct manipulation isn't just
about designing interactions that
feel like you're directly
manipulating the interface.
It's also about designing
interfaces that lend themselves to
interactions that feel more direct.