We've reached the end of our HCI course.
To close things off, let's briefly recap what we've covered.
The purpose of this lesson isn't just to give you an inventory of the course content.
The real reason for this lesson is to give us
an excuse to have this cool inception effect over here.
No, really, it's to repeat
all that content again to load it into your working memory one more time.
After all, we know that the more often you load some content into short-term memory,
the more strongly it remains in long-term memory.
That was a principal we learned in the lesson on human abilities,
and it covers where we start and end
every lesson by repeating the material that we covered.
Each repeat loads it into your short-term memory one more time, further solidifying it.
So, to close this course,
we'll do this one more time.
Although we hope, you'll come back again and again
and watch some of the material whenever you need a refresher.