When we're doing research in HCI,
we have access to some pretty sensitive personal data about our participants.
There are huge ethical considerations about privacy and coercion,
that we have to keep in mind when participating in the design lifecycle.
So, we discussed the role of institutional review board,
or IRB for university research.
They oversee studies and make sure we're preserving our participants rights.
They also make sure that the benefits of our research outweigh the risks,
and as part of that they help ensure our methods our sound enough,
to have benefits in the first place.
We also discussed how industry doesn't have the same kind of oversight.
But some companies have partnered with universities to participate in their IRBs.
While other companies have formed their own internal IRBs.
All of this is driven by the need to preserve the rights of our users,
that's a key part of user-centered design.