Once we have a solid understanding of the user and the task,
we want to start brainstorming possible designs.
The important thing here is to make sure we don't get fixated on one idea too early.
That's sort of tunnel vision,
risks missing lots of fantastic ideas.
So, we want to make sure to engage in a well-defined brainstorming process.
I personally recommend that we start with individual brainstorming,
and then set up a group brainstorming session that
ensures that everyone's individual ideas gets heard.
From there, we propose some different ideas on how to
explore those design alternatives through methods like personas,
and scenarios, and timelines.
Our end goal here was to arrive at a set of
designs worth moving on to the prototyping stage.