In user-centered design, our goal is to get user feedback early and often.
So, once we have some design alternatives,
our goal is to get them in front of users as quickly as possible.
That's the prototyping stage where we take
those design alternatives and build prototypes we can show to actual users.
Now at first, this prototypes might be very low fidelity.
We might start just by describing our ideas or drawing them on paper.
Those are verbal or paper prototypes.
We want to keep our designs easy to revise.
We might even revise them live while working with users.
As we get more and more feedback,
we build higher fidelity prototypes to explore more detailed questions about our designs.
We might use wireframes or set up live simulated demos.
At every stage of the process,
we design our prototypes in a way to get
the user's feedback and inform the next iteration of our design life cycle.