Our first unit was the unit on design principles.
To start that unit off, we'd began by investigating the process of identifying a task.
We discussed how a task is not just the actions that a user performs,
but it's the combination of their motivations,
and their goals, and their context, and so on.
We emphasized that we're not just interface designers,
we are task designers.
We design tasks and then we create interfaces that make those tasks possible.
We then explored three views on the user's role in a particular task.
We might view them as an information processor,
like another computer in the system.
We might view them as a predictor, or interpreter,
someone operating a mental model of the system.
We might view them as a participant,
someone working in a larger context beyond just our interface.
And then, finally, we discussed how the views we take inform the designs we create.