We then moved on to direct manipulation,
which was one way to create interfaces with very short goals of execution and evaluation.
Direct manipulation involved creating interfaces where the user felt like
they were directly interacting with the object of the task.
Instead of typing commands or selecting operators,
they would more physically participate with the interface.
The goal of this, and really of any good interface design,
was to create interfaces that become invisible.
Invisible interfaces are those that allow the user to focus
completely on the task instead of on the interface.
We noted that nearly any interface can become
invisible when the user has enough practice and expertise,
but our goal is to create interfaces that vanish sooner by good design.