Earlier, we discussed the idea of cognitive load.
Cognitive load was the principle that humans have a set amount of cognitive resources,
and if there are overloaded and their performance suffers and they get frustrated.
So, how do we reduce the user's cognitive load?
Well, we can make the task easier, sure,
but we can also add to their cognitive resources.
That's the principle of distributed cognition.
The interactions of humans and artifacts together
have more cognitive resources in individuals acting alone.
Devices and interfaces can exhibit cognitive properties like
memory and reasoning offloading those needs from the user.
We also discussed three related theories: social cognition,
situated action, and activity theory.
All three of these put a strong emphasis on
the context of a task whether it be the physical context,
the social context or the societal context.