This conflict between more
processor-oriented and
more predictor-oriented models
of the user actually gets at
the core of an old battle in psychology
between behaviorism and cognitivism.
Behaviorism emphasized things
that could be observed.
We can see what input
a person is receiving.
We can see the output they're producing.
And that might be all we need to
understand the design of things.
Cognitivism, on the other hand,
suggests we can and
should get into the mind of what
people are actually thinking and
how systems like memory and
learning and perception actually work.
So take a moment and
reflect on what you think about this.
When designing interfaces,
how much attention should you devote to
observable goals, operators and methods?
And how much do you devote to
understanding internal thought
processes, like cognition,
learning, and memory?