You can probably guess my bias on
this issue, given that I've already
badmouthed the processor model and
I also teach cognitive systems.
So I'm generally going to prefer
methods that focus on cognition.
I think it's important to note here
though that both approaches have
significant value.
The GOMS model and
its emphasis on identifying goals and
operators is actually
very useful in HCI.
Because it forces us to very clearly and
deliberately identify user goals and
the sequence of actions
that accomplish them.
We can get so caught up in user
experiences that we forget the user
experience is born out
of individual operators.
So while I wouldn't advocate focusing
solely on the user as some kind of input
output information processor, there's
value in defining the user's operation
as clearly and
specifically as we define a computer's.