Cognitive task analysis is not really a single method,
but it's more of a type of method for
approaching the evaluation of how people complete tasks.
Performing a cognitive task analysis involves a number of
different techniques and methods that we'll discuss
more when we discuss the design lifecycle.
For right now though, we're interested in
what kinds of information we're trying to gather,
not how we're gathering it.
Cognitive task analyses are especially concerned with
understanding the underlying thought processing performing a task,
not just what we can see but specifically what we can't see.
There are a lot of different methods for performing
cognitive task analyses but most methods follow a particular common sequence.
First, we want to collect some preliminary knowledge.
While we as interface designers don't need to become experts in a field,
we need a good bit of familiarity with it.
So, we might observe people performing the task for example.
In navigation, we might just watch someone driving and using a GPS.
Our second step is to identify knowledge representations.
In other words, what kinds of things does a user need to know to complete their task?
Note that we're not yet concerned with the actual knowledge they have,
only the types or structures of the knowledge that they have.
For example, we want to know,
does this task involves a series of steps to do in a certain order?
Does it involve a collection of tasks to check off in any order?
Does it involve a web of knowledge to memorize?
For navigation, for example,
we would identify that the structure of the knowledge is a sequence of
actions and order as well as knowledge of things to monitor as we go.
In the third stage,
we actually want to populate those knowledge representations.
This is the stage where we start to recognize what the user actually knows.
With navigation for example,
they know to start the GPS,
to enter an address and to obey the turns while
monitoring traffic and speed and things like that.
During this stage, we identify all the specific actions they take,
the knowledge they must have in mind to take those actions,
the interruptions that can change their thought processes,
the equipment involved and the sensory experience of the user.
We do this by applying focused knowledge elicitation methods.
In other words, we get users to tell us what's
going on in their heads or what's going on in their environment or
sometimes we do things that help us understand parts of the task that
the user isn't even themselves aware of.
Then we analyze and verify the data we acquired.
Part of that is just confirming with the people we
observe that our understanding is correct.
We might watch them do something and infer it for
one reason when in reality it's for a very different reason.
So, we want to present to our users our results and make sure
that they agree with our understanding of their task.
Then we attempt to formalize it into structures that can be
compared and summarized across multiple data gathering methods.
Finally, we format our results for the intended application.
We need to take those results and format them in
a way that's useful for interface design.
We want to develop models that show what the user was thinking,
feeling and remembering at any given time and make those relationships really explicit.
The result might look something like this.
Here we see a very high level model of the process of driving to a destination.
What's interesting to note is that these tasks in
the middle are highly cognitive rather than observable.
If I had no knowledge about driving and I sat in the passenger seat watching the driver,
I might never know that they're monitoring their route progress or
keeping an eye on their dashboard for how much fuel they have left.
If you have kids, you may have experienced this personally actually.
Two kids sitting in the backseat,
mommy or daddy are just sitting in
the driver seat just like they're sitting in the passenger seat.
They don't have a full understanding of the fact that you have
a much higher cognitive load and you're
doing a lot more things while you're driving then they are.
That's because what you're doing is not observable. It's all in your head.
So, to get at these things,
I might have the user to think out loud about what they're doing, while they're doing it.
I might have them tell me what they're thinking while they're driving the car.
That would give me some insights into these cognitive elements of the task.