Cognitive task analysis advocates building models of
human reasoning and decision-making in complex tasks.
However, a challenge presented here is that very often,
large tasks are actually composed of many multiple smaller tasks.
We can see this plainly present in our cognitive model of driving.
These tasks are so high level,
that it's almost useful to describe driving in these terms.
Each part can be broken down into various sub-tasks,
like iteratively checking all the cars around you,
or periodically checking how long it is until next turn needs to be made.
What's more, these smaller tasks could then be used in different contexts.
Route monitoring, for example,
isn't only useful when driving a car,
it might be useful while running or biking or while riding as a passenger.
Traffic monitoring might be something that autonomous vehicles might do,
not just the human user.
So, the analysis of a task in a particular context could be useful in designing
interfaces for other contexts if we break the analysis down into sub-tasks.
So, let's take a simple example of this.
Here is a somewhat simple model of the act of buying something online.
Notice that a lot of the tasks involved here are
general to anyone shopping on any website and yet,
every website needs to provide all of these functions.
As a side note, notice also the interesting analogy going on with the top two.
Online, there is no cart or checkout station,
but we borrowed those to help the user understand
the shopping process online and how similar it is to shopping in a store.
Now, anyway, if we treat this cognitive task analysis more hierarchically,
we can start to see a well-defined sub-task around this checkout process.
Every online vendor I've ever encountered has these steps in its checkout process.
Now, because this is so well-defined,
we can actually leverage existing tools,
like existing payment widgets or something like PayPal.
This hierarchical task analysis helps us understand
what tools might already be available to accomplish certain portions of our task,
or how we might design certain things to
transfer between different tasks and different contexts.
Hierarchical task analysis also lets the designers of the site abstract over
this part of the process and focus more on what might make their particular site unique.
This kind of task analysis is so common that you generally will find tasks and
sub-tasks whenever you're looking at the results of a cognitive task analysis.
So, it's important to remember the strengths supplied by this hierarchy,
abstracting out unnecessary details for a certain level of abstraction,
modularizing designs or principles,
so they can be transferred between different tasks or different contexts,
and organizing the cognitive task analysis in
a way that makes it easier to understand and reason over.
Last, it's really important to note that
the cognitive and hierarchical task analyses that
we've shown here are extremely simplistic,
mostly, honestly because of the limited screen real estate.
When you're creating a real cognitive models,
you'll likely have several levels of abstraction,
several different states, and
additional annotating information like what the user has to keep in mind,
or how they might be feeling at a certain stage in the analysis.
We'll put some examples of some good thorough models in the notes.