What we saw here was
that to get inside and
disable the alarm, there was a sequence
of actions that had to be completed,
but some of them could be
completed in different orders.
If she used the keypad, she had to first
unlock the door and then open the door.
Then she could either disable the alarm
on the keypad or close the door.
And after closing the door,
she could re-lock the door,
though she could also do that
before disarming the alarm.
So there's some choices there.
With the keychain, the sequence of tasks
related to the door remain the same, but
she had the option of disarming
the alarm before even entering.
However, that required
remembering to do so.
When using the keypad, she didn't have
to remember because the alarm beeps at
her until she turns it off.
But she has to remember the key code.
Performing these cognitive task analyses
gives us the information necessary to
evaluate different approaches and
look for areas of improvement.
For example, if she can disable
the alarm just by pressing the keychain
button, why does she
need to press it at all?
Why doesn't it just detect that she's
coming in with a keychain in her pocket?