Just like Goms models, cognitive task
analysis also have some strength and
some weaknesses.
One strength is that they
emphasize mental processes.
Unlike the Goms model,
cognitive task analysis puts an emphasis
on what goes on inside the users head.
It's thus much better equipped to
understand how experts think and work.
The information it generated is
also formal enough to be used for
interface design, for comparison
in mode alternatives and more.
There are disadvantages though.
One, cogni-task analysis are incredibly
time-consuming to perform.
They involve talking to
multiple experts for
extended period of time,
then systematically analyzing the data.
A second weakness is that cogni-task
analysis risk deemphasizing context.
In zooming in on the individual's
own thought processes,
cogni-task analysis risks deemphasizing
details that are out in the world.
Like the role of
physical capabilities or
interactions amongst different people,
or different artifacts.
And third,
like Goms models, cogni-task analysis
also isn't well suited to novices.
It's well suited to expert users who
have very strong models of the way
they work and clearly understand
their own mental thought processes.
But they're not very well suited for
novice users who are still trying
to learn how to use an interface.