GOMS and cognitive tasks analysis
are just two of the many alternatives to
understanding how users approach tasks.
More in line with the human
information processor models,
there exist models like KLM,
TLM, and MHP,
which capture even finer grain actions
for estimating performance speed.
There are other extensions to GOMS as
well that add things like sub goals, or
other ways of expressing content
like CPM-GOMS and NGOMSL.
CPM-GOMS focuses on parallel tasks,
while NGOMSL
provides a natural language interface
for interacting with GOMS models.
More on the lines of cognitive models,
there exists other methods
as well like CDM, TKS, CFM,
Applied Cognitive Task Analyses, and
Skill-Based Cognitive Task Analyses.
CDM puts a focus on places
where critical decisions occur.
TKS focuses on the nature
of humans' knowledge.
CFM focuses on complexity.
ACTA and Skill-Based CTA are two ways of
gathering the information necessary
to create a cognitive model.
There also exists other frameworks
more common in other disciplines, for
example, production systems are common
to an artificial intelligence.
But they're intended to model cognitive
systems the same way these cognitive
models do.
So we can apply production
systems here as well and
attempt to prescribe rules for
users to follow.