Today, we've talked at length about two general methods for approaching task analysis.
One, the GOMS family of approaches tries to distill tasks down to their goals,
operators, methods, and selection rules.
The other, cognitive task analysis
aimed to get into the head of the user and understand what they're thinking,
feeling, and remembering at every stage of the task.
When we discussed design life-cycles,
we focused a bit on how to fill these miles with information.
But our focus there is on the methods for gathering
the information rather than the structure of the information itself.
So, it's important to keep these methods in mind when we talk about that.