Gomes models are human
information processor models.
This method largely assumes the human
is an input output machine,
and it doesn't get too much into
the internal reasoning of the human.
Instead, it distills their reasoning
into things that can be described
explicitly like goals and methods.
Some would argue, myself included,
that human reasoning is actually too
nuanced and complex to be so simplified.
They, or we,
advocate other models to get more into
what goes on inside the user's head.
That's where cognitive
task analysis comes in.
Cognitive task analysis is another way
of examining tasks, but it puts a much
higher emphasis on things like memory,
attention, and cognitive load.
Thus, cognitive task analysis adopts
more of the predictor view of
the human's role in the system.