[MUSIC]
In 1980, Langdon Winner published
a highly influential essay in which he
ask, do artifacts have politics?
In other words, do technical
devices have political qualities?
And the answer is yes.
All toasters are democrats.
Thermostats, as you might expect,
are members of labor party.
And pretty surprisingly automobiles
are actually green party members.
Okay, I'm kidding.
That's not what we mean when we
ask if artifacts have politics.
Here, when we say politics we mean
whether artifacts can personify specific
forms of authority or power,
whether for good or bad.
What we're referring to is the fact
that artifacts are interfaces we design,
change the world around us, just the way
politicians or business interests do.
Sometimes that's by design, we might
design interfaces not for usability,
or research, but
to create change in the world.
Other times that social change happens
in ways we didn't anticipate, we design
interfaces that are used and affect
the world in ways we never anticipated.
So in this lesson, we're going to
talk about two dimensions of this,
designing for change and anticipating
the change from our designs.
We'll also touch on a field that
explores these issues more deeply
called Value-Sensitive Design.