In HCI, we describe the idea of
interfaces becoming invisible.
Some of that is a useability principle,
but it also applies more broadly
to the way that interfaces integrate
themselves into our everyday lives.
And if our interfaces are going
to integrate into people's lives,
then they need to share the same
values as those individuals as well.
This connects to the field
of value sensitive design.
The Value Sensitive Design Lab at the
University of Washington defines this
idea by saying, value sensitive
design seeks to provide theory and
method to account for
human values in a principled and
systematic manner throughout
the design process.
In this way, value sensitive design
is another dimension to consider when
designing interfaces.
Not only is an interface useful
in accomplishing a task and
not only is it usable by the user, but
is it consistent with their values?
One of the most well-developed
application areas of value sensitive
design is privacy by design.
Privacy is a value, and
privacy by design has aimed to preserve
that value in the design of systems.
It's possible to design
useful usable interfaces
that don't take privacy
into account anywhere.
That's what makes an examination of
user's values an extra dimension
of interface design.