Here are five tips for incorporating value sensitive design into your interfaces.
Number one, start early.
Identify the values you want to account for early in
the design process and check on them throughout the design process.
The nature of value sensitive design is that it might have
significant connections not just to the design of the interface,
but to the very core of the task you're trying to support.
Number two, know your users.
I know, I say this a lot.
But in order to design with values in mind,
you need to know your user's values.
Certain values are incompatible with
one another or at least present challenges for one another.
Privacy as a value is in some ways in conflict with a value of record-keeping.
To know what to design,
you need to know your user's values.
Number three, consider both direct and indirect stakeholders.
We usually think about direct stakeholders.
Those are the people that actually use the system that we create.
Value sensitive design encourages us to think about indirect stakeholders as well.
Those are people who do not use the system but who are nonetheless affected by it.
When you're designing the internal system for use by a bank for example,
it's used by bank employees,
but bank customers are likely to be impacted by the design.
Number four, brainstorm the interface's possibilities.
Think not only about how your design system to be used but how it could be used.
If you wanted to make a system that made it easier for
employees to track their hours for example,
consider whether it could be used by employers to find unjust cause for termination.
Number five, choose carefully between supporting values and prescribing values.
Designing for change is about prescribing changes in values.
But that doesn't mean we should try to prescribe values for everyone.
At the same time,
there are certain values held in the world that we
would like to change with our interfaces if
possible with regard to issues like gender equality or economic justice.
Be careful and be deliberate about when you choose to support
existing values and when you choose to try to change them with your interfaces.