We've talked a good bit about how
technology and interfaces can affect
politics and culture and society,
but we wouldn't be telling the whole
story if we didn't close by noting
the alternate relationship as well.
Political relationships and
motivations can often have an enormous
impact on the design of technology.
>From Bijker's book Of Bicycles,
Bakelites, and Bulbs, the bulbs part
refers to the battle of the design of
the first flourescent lightbulb in 1938.
General Electric created a new
kind of light that was far more
energy efficient.
The power companies were afraid that
this would reduce power consumption and
cut into their profits.
After a long drawn out battle involving
the Anti Trust Division of the US
government and the US Department of War,
the fluorescent bulbs that were
ultimately sold were not as good as they
technologically could be in order to
preserve others' business interests.
That issue is more
prevalent today than ever.
More and more, we see compatibility
between devices and usage policies for
technologies determined not by
what's technologically possible but
by what satisfies political or
business needs.
So here's an example.
To keep up with everything that I like
to watch on TV I have five different
subscriptions.
I have cable TV, I have Hulu,
I have Amazon Prime, I have Netflix and
I have an HBO subscription on
top of my cable subscription.
And that's not to mention
things that I watch for
free on their own apps like Conan or
anything on YouTube.
And you might think wouldn't
it be awesome to just have
one experience that could navigate
among everything I want to watch.
And it would be awesome, and there's
no technological reason against it.
But there's a complicated web
of ownership and licensing and
intellectual property agreements that
determine the way that technology works.
Technology changes society but
society changes technology too.