In this lesson, we've discussed the different ways in which interfaces
interact with existing power structures or political motivations.
We looked at how interfaces can have
negative repercussions either by design or by happenstance.
We looked more optimistically at how interfaces can
be powerful tools for equality and justice in the world,
whether intentionally or accidentally.
We also looked at how it's important to keep in mind
different cultures values while designing interfaces.
Now, notice how all of these perspectives hearken back to the idea that
user experience exists not only in individuals and groups, but in societies.