The most influential paper on the inner play between
artifacts and politics came from Langdon Winner in 1980.
The paper describes numerous ways in which technologies, interfaces,
and other artifacts demonstrate political qualities, demonstrate political motivations.
For example, he opens by noting the belief that nuclear power can only be
used in a totalitarian society because of the inherent danger of the technology.
Solar power on the other hand,
pushes society towards a more distributed and egalitarian structure.
But of course, we understand that nuclear power isn't on its own authoritarian.
It has no consciousness.
It can't take political power.
Winner is proposing that the push for certain technologies
carries with it certain necessary political adjustments.
That's part of what it means to suggest that artifacts have politics.
In the paper, Winner outlines two distinct ways in which artifacts can be political.
One type is inherently political technologies.
These are technologies that due to their very design,
are only compatible with certain political structures.
Certain technologies like nuclear power,
whether due to complexity,
or safety, or resources,
require considerable top-down organization.
Those lend themselves to authoritarian power structures.
Others like solar power, someone might argue,
are only possible in a more distributed and egalitarian society.
So, these technologies by their very nature,
dictate the need for certain political structures.
The other type he discusses are technical arrangements as forms of order.
Technologies can be used to achieve changes to social order when used in the correct way.
The technology itself has no inherent political leanings like nuclear or solar power,
but it's used in a particular context for
a particular purpose can nonetheless accomplish some political goals.
Winner uses the example of a factory in Chicago in the 1880s,
they replaced the workers with automated machines that produced
inferior goods as a way of busting up the Union.
The new technology was actually inferior,
but it was used to serve a political purpose.
So, according to Winner, artifacts may have two kinds of politics;
they may be inherently political,
in that they're only compatible with certain forms of political order,
or they may be used to achieve political motives,
even though they have no inherent politics on their own.