Let's start with the bad news.
The ability of interfaces to
change behavior can be abused.
We're not just talking about places
where people put explicit barriers
up like blocking certain people
from accessing their content.
There are instances where people
create seemingly normal designs with
underlying political motivations.
Winner describes one such instance in
his essay Do Artifacts Have Politics?
Robert Moses was an influential city
planner working in New York City,
in the early 1900s.
As part of his role,
he oversaw the construction of many
beautiful parks on Long Island.
He also oversaw
the construction of parkways,
roads to bring the people
of New York to these parks.
That's actually where
the word parkway comes from.
But something unfortunate happened.
The bridges along these parkways were
too low for buses to pass under them.
As a result, public transportation
couldn't really run easily to his parks.
And as a result of that,
only people wealthy enough to own
cars were able to visit his parks.
What an unfortunate coincidence, right?
The evidence shows it's anything but
coincidence.
Moses intentionally constructed
those bridges to be too low for
buses to pass under.
As a way of keeping poor people
from visiting his parks.
His political motivations
directly informed the design of
the infrastructure and
the design of the infrastructure
had profound social implications.
This is an example of winners
technology as a form of social order.
The bridges could have been taller.
There's nothing inherently
political about those bridges.
It was the way that they were used that
accomplished this political motivation.
As an interesting aside, I learned
recently that the design of Central Park
inside New York City was an example
of the exact opposite dynamic.
The designers were encouraged to put in
places where only carriages could access
so affluent people would have
somewhere to go away from poor people.
But the designers specifically made
the entire park accessible to everyone.
It's not to hard to imagine things kind
of like that happening today either.
One of the arguments from proponents
of Net neutrality is that without it,
companies can set up fast lanes that
prioritize their own content or
worse severely diminished
content of their competitors or
content critical of the company.