We can design for
positive social changes well though.
This goes beyond just encouraging people
to be nice or banning bad behavior.
Interfaces can be designed that'll
lead to positive social change through
natural interaction with the system.
One example of this that I like is
Facebook's ubiquitous Like button.
For years, many people have argued for
a Dislike button to
compliment the Like button.
Facebook has stuck with
the Like button though,
because by its design,
it only supports positive interactions.
It dodges cyberbullying,
it dodges negativity.
For usability purposes, it's a weakness
because there are interactions
I can't have naturally
in this interface.
But this specific part of
the Like button wasn't
designed with usability in mind.
More recently, Facebook has added to
the like button with five new emotions,
love, haha, wow, sad and angry.
Even with these five
new emotions though,
the overall connotation
is still positive.
For three of them, it's obvious why.
Love, haha and
wow are more positive emotions.
Sad and angry are negative emotions,
but used in this context,
they take on more of
a sympathetic connotation.
If someone is ranting about
getting into a car accident,
it seems to weird to like that.
But if you react with
this angry emoticon,
then you're basically saying
you're angry on their behalf.
It might be possible to use this for
the more negative connotation like if
someone said they like a political
candidate and you react angrily,
then you could be opposing
their political view.
But in the majority of cases,
these are still going to be used in
a way that fosters positive interaction.
So it seems that this interface
was designed to foster
positive social interactions online.
At the expense of usability,
it would come with supporting
all social interactions online.
This also doesn't have to be
strictly about dictating change, but
it can also be about supporting change.
For example, until a few years ago,
Facebook had a more limited
set of relationship options.
They had married, engaged,
in a relationship, single and
it's complicated.
As it's target audience went from
being college students to everyone,
they also added separated,
divorced and widowed.
But it was a couple of years after that
that they then added in a civil union
and in a domestic partnership.
Adding these concepts didn't magically
create these social constructs,
they existed legally before
Facebook added them here.
But adding them here supported
an ongoing societal trend and
gave them some validity.
And made people for whom these were the
accurate relationship labels feel like
they really were part of
Facebook's target audience,
they were part of modern culture.
That an accurate representation of their
relationship status was available on
this drop down meant they could
accurately portray who they were on
their Facebook profile.
The same can be said for the more recent
trend to expand Facebook's gender
options to allow people to
put in a custom gender.
This supports a diverse group of
people feeling as if the interface
is designed with them in mind.
Which in turn supports society's
general movement towards acceptance.