Let's tackle Change by Design by
designing something for Morgan.
So Morgan has a desk job.
That means she spends
a lot of her time sitting.
However, for health reasons, it's best
for her to get up once per hour and
walk around just for a few minutes.
There are a lot of way we could tackle
this by physically changing the design
of her environment to a standing desk or
by giving her an app that directly
reminds her or rewards her for
moving around.
But let's try to do something
a little bit more subtle.
So let's design something for Morgan's
smartphone that gets to move around for
a couple minutes every hour without
directly reminding her to walk around or
rewarding her for doing so.