A third view on the user is to look
at the user as a participant in some
environment.
That means we're not just interested
in what's going on inside their head.
We're also interested in what's going
on around them at the same time,
like what other tasks or
interfaces they're using, or
what other people they're
interacting with.
We want to understand for example,
what's competing for their attention?
What are their available
cognitive resources?
What's the importance of the task
relative to everything else that's
going on?
So if we take this view, then our
interface must fit with the context.
It's not enough that the user is able
to physically use the system and
knows how to use the system.
They must be able to actually interact
with the system in the context
where they need it.
And because context is so
important here,
we evaluate it with in situ studies.
We can't simply look at the user and
the interface in a vacuum.
We have to actually view and
evaluate them in the real world
using the interface in whatever
context is most relevant.
If we're evaluating a new GPS
application, for example,
we need to actually go out and
look at it in the context of real
drivers driving on real roads.
The information we get from them
using the app in our lab setting
isn't as useful as understanding how
they're going to actually use it
out in the real world.
These are in situ studies,
which are studies of the interface and
the user within the real
complete context of the task.