So, where did these different views of the user come from?
To find out, we actually need to trace HCI back to its roots in psychology.
The processor view of the user goes back to the behaviorist school of psychology.
Behaviorism was the dominant school of thought in
psychology throughout the late 19th century.
It aimed to provide a systematic way of
investigating behaviors in humans and in other animals.
It was largely established by John B.
Watson who was a psychologist at Columbia University.
He insisted that psychology focus only on observable behavior and not on introspection.
John B. Watson himself was responsible for
the "Little Albert" experiment that you might be familiar with.
In that experiment, a little boy was conditioned to be afraid
of rabbits as they were repeatedly paired with loud noises.
You might be familiar with some of the other big names in behaviorism as well,
such as Pavlov with his dogs and Skinner with his rats.
Pavlov discovered the idea of classical conditioning where he could condition a dog to
salivate at the sound of a bell by repeatedly pairing those two stimuli together.
Skinner went step further with operant conditioning and
conditioned rats to actually demonstrate a learned behavior.
They would press a button to receive food.
The important takeaway here is that Behaviorism
focuses only on observable behaviors and outcomes.
It attempts to understand behavior by looking only at behavior,
not at the cognition that underlies behavior,
and thus it has the name, "Behaviorism."
In HCI, this means looking at what designs create
the right behaviors without paying a whole lot of attention as to why.
If we view the user as a processor,
that our design process focuses on testing observable behaviors.
The predictor view of the user goes back to
the next major school of thought in psychology,
Cognitivism, or Cognitive psychology or Cognitive science.
While Behaviorism was only concerned with what we could observe,
Cognitivism is concerned with what goes on inside the mind.
Now, this covers a lot,
things like perception, attention,
memory, creativity, these all occur inside the user's mind.
Cognitivism started out more as a philosophical endeavor.
Philosophers like Rene Descartes and Immanuel Kant touched on questions
like whether knowledge is inborn or developed solely by experience,
whether or not people are blank slates when they're
born or if they're born with some kind of innate knowledge.
But it wasn't until the cognitive revolution of the 1950s that
Cognitivism really emerged as a foil to Behaviorism.
At that time, it was such a radical departure than in many places,
you still see Cognitive science classified
as a completely different field from psychology.
What's particularly interesting is that this shift came about in large part due to
the work of scientists working in artificial intelligence and computer science,
as well as neuroscience and linguistics and some other areas that were applicable to
psychology but weren't inside or weren't subsets of psychology.
Some of the big names in Cognitivism are the linguist,
Noam Chomsky, the psychologist,
Susan Carey, and the computer scientists,
John McCarthy, Marvin Minsky,
Allen Newell, and Herbert Simon.
Many of these might be names you're familiar with if you've read about classical AI.
These are some of the biggest names in classical AI thinking.
Those early efforts in classical AI were specifically
trying to create computers that could think like humans.
In order to create a computer that could think like a human,
we had to understand how a human thought.
Now, for us here in HCI,
the key here is that we care about what the user is thinking.
We call this the predictor model of the user because predicting is a mental process,
and we want to know what the user is predicting.
We ask questions like,
what do they predict the outcome of that action will be?
What do they predict is the right action to take?
Notice here, the user is doing the predicting, not the interface.
We want to get inside the user's head and
understand how they predict the interface will behave.
That's the core of the predictor model.
Now, while Behaviorism and Cognitivism are
well-established schools of thought in psychology,
the participant view is a little more nascent.
It resembles the functionalism view of psychology,
which emphasizes examining mental behaviors in the context of broader environments.
It also resembles system psychology which
emphasizes human behavior within complex systems.
But in both places, the coupling between the participant view in
these schools of thought is little less well-defined.
In our work, the participant view largely comes out of
original research in HCI and human factors engineering.
The important thing here is that while the processor and predictor views
emphasize only the interaction of some user and some interface,
the participant view also looks at the interaction of
both within the context of a larger system.
It cares about the environment in which the user and the interface are situated.
So, this model views the user and the interface as
participants within a larger complex cognitive system.
Some of the major names in this area are Edwin Hutchins,
who pioneered the idea of distributed cognition.
We'll talk about him more when we talk about distributed cognition in a few lessons.
Lucy Suchman also introduced the idea of situated action models,
which argue that we can't disentangle
behavior from the environment in which it takes place.
Gavriel Salomon was an educational psychologist who focused in large part on how
learning happens in the context of culturally provided tools and implements,
and Bonnie Nardi introduced the complimentary idea of activity theory into
this general idea of analyzing a user and
an interface as participants in some larger activity.
So, anytime you're looking beyond just the user and the interface,
you're likely employing the participant view in some way.
But like I said, we'll talk about this a lot more when
we reach our lesson on distributed cognition.
Now, this has been a super quick recap of
these three major schools of thought in both psychology and in HCI.
There are actually entire classes available to focus
exclusively on each of these or even on subparts of each of these.
So, if you'd like to learn more,
you should check out some of the links that we'll provide below.