As a processor, we might simply look
at what information is communicated to
Morgan, when, and how.
As a predictor, we might look
instead at how the interface
meshes with Morgan's needs with regard
to this task, how easy it is to access,
how easy the commands are to perform,
and so on.
As a participant, we might look at
the broader interactions between this
interface and Morgan's other tasks and
social activities.
You might look at how increased access
to books changes her life in other ways.
But really, this challenge is
too big to address this quickly.
So instead, let's return to this
challenge throughout our conversations,
and use it as a running dialogue to
explore HCI principles and methods.