Here are five quick tips for identifying a user task.
Number one: watch real users.
Instead of just speculating or brainstorming,
get out there and watch real users performing in the area in which you're interested.
Number two: talk to them.
You don't have to just watch them.
Recruit some participants to come perform the task and talk their way through it.
Find out what they're thinking, what their goals are, what their motives are.
Number three: start small.
Start by looking at the individual little interactions.
It's tempting to come in believing you already understand the task,
but if you do, you'll interpret everything you see in terms of what you already believe.
Instead, start by looking at the smallest operators a user performs.
Number four: abstract up.
Working from those small observations try to
abstract up to an understanding of the tasks that they're trying to complete.
Keep asking why they're performing
these actions until you get beyond the scope of your design.
For example, what is Morgan doing? Swiping her credit card.
Why? To make a purchase.
Why? To acquire some goods.
Why? To repair her car.
Somewhere in that sequence is likely the task for which we want to design.
Number five: you are not your user.
Even if you yourself perform the task for which you're designing,
you're not designing for you.
You're designing for everyone that performs that task.
So, leave behind your own previous experiences and preconceived notions about it.
These five quick tips come up a lot in the methods unit of HCI.
HCI research methods are largely about understanding users,
their motivations, and their tasks.
So we'll talk much more about this later but it's good to keep in mind now.