Throughout this unit, I repeatedly ask you to revisit the area
of HCI you chose to keep in mind throughout our conversations.
Now, take a second,
and try to pull all those things together.
You've thought about how your chosen area applies
to each of the models of the humans role.
How it applies to various different design guidelines,
and how it interacts with society and culture as a whole.
How does moving through those different levels
changed the kinds of designs you have in mind.
Are you building up from low-level interactions to high-level effects?
Are you starting at the top with the desired outcome and
working your way down to the individual operations?
There are no right or wrong answers here.
The important thing is reflecting on your own reasoning process.