In looking at human-computer
interaction, it's important that we
understand the role that we expect the
human to play in this overall system.
Let's talk about three different
possible types of roles the human can
play, processor, predictor,
and participant.
First, we might think of the human
as being nothing more than a sensory
processor.
They take input in and
they spit output out.
They're kind of like another
computer in the system,
just one that we can't
see the inside of.
If we are designing with this role in
mind then our main concern is that
the interface fit within
known human limits.
These are things like
what humans can sense,
what they can store in memory, and what
they can physically do in the world.
In this case, usability means that
the interface is physically usable.
User can see all the colors,
touch all the buttons, and so on.
With this model,
we evaluate our interfaces
with quantitative experiments.
That means we take numeric measurements
on how quickly the user can complete
some task or how quickly they might
react to some incoming stimulus.
Now, as you might have guessed,
the processor view is not the one we'll
generally take when we
talk about good design.
Instead, we'll probably divide our time
pretty equally between the other two
perspectives.