A second way of viewing the human
is to view them as a predictor.
Here, we care deeply about the human's
knowledge, experience, expectations, and
their thought process.
That's why we call them the predictor.
We want them to be able to predict
what will happen in the world
as a result of some action they take.
So we want them to be able
to map input to output.
And that means getting
inside their head.
Understanding what they're thinking,
what they're seeing,
what they're feeling when they're
interacting with some task.
If we're taking this perspective,
then the interface must
fit with what humans know.
It must fit with their knowledge.
It must help the user learn what
they don't already know and
efficiently leverage what
they do already know.
And toward that end,
we evaluate these kind of interfaces
with qualitative studies.
These are often ex situ studies.
We might perform task analyses to see
where users are spending their time.
Or perform cognitive walk-throughs
to understand the user's thought
process throughout some task.
We can see pretty clearly that this view
gives us some advantages over viewing
the user simply as a sensory processor,
just as another computer in the system.
However, here we're still focusing
on one user and one task.
And sometimes that's useful.
But many times we want to look
even more broadly than that.
That's when we take
the third participant peel.