Hi, and welcome to Educational Technology.
My name is David Joyner, and I'm thrilled to bring you this course.
As you might guess, education is one of my favorite application areas of HCI.
In fact, as I'm recording this,
I've been teaching educational technology at Georgia Tech for about a year,
and a huge portion of designing
educational technology is really just straightforward HCI.
But education puts some unique twists on the HCI process.
Most fascinatingly, education is an area where you
might not always want to make things as easy as possible.
You might use HCI to introduce some desirable difficulties,
some learning experiences for students.
But it's important to ensure that the cognitive load students experienced
during a learning task is based on the material itself,
not based on trying to figure out our interfaces.
The worst thing you can do in HCI for education is raise
the student's cognitive load because they're too busy thinking
about your interface instead of the subject matter itself.
Lots of very noble efforts in designing technology for
education have failed due to poor HCI.
So, if you're interested in going in educational technology,
you'll find a lot of valuable lessons in human-computer interaction.