Classes on network security are often
most concerned with the algorithms and
encryption methods that must be
safeguarded to ensure secure
communications.
But the most secure communication
strategies in the world are weakened if
people just refuse to use them.
And historically, we've found people
have very little patience for
instances where security measures get
in the way of them doing their tasks.
For security to be useful
it has to be usable.
If it isn't usable,
people just won't use it.
XEI can increase the usability
of security in a number of ways.
For one, it can make those
actions simply easier to perform.
CAPTCHAs are forms that are meant
to ensure users are humans.
And they used to involve recognizing
letters in complex images, but
now they're often as
simple as a check-box.
The computer recognizes
human-like mouse movements and
uses that to evaluate
whether the user is a human.
That makes it much less frustrating to
participate in that security activity.
But HCI can also make security
more usable by visualizing and
communicating the need.
Many people get frustrated when systems
require passwords that meet certain
standards or complexity, but
that's because it seems arbitrary.
If the system instead expresses
to the user the rationale behind
the requirement, the requirement
can be much less frustrating.
I've even seen a password form that
treats password selection like a game
where you're ranked against others for
how difficult your password
would be to guess.
That's a way to incentivize
strong password selection
making security more usable.