Video games are one of
the purest examples of HCI.
They're actually a great place
to study HCI, because so
many of the topics we discuss are so
salient.
For example, we discussed the need for
logical mapping between actions and
effects.
A good game exemplifies that.
The actions that the user takes with
the controller should feel like they're
actually interacting
within the game world.
We discussed the power
of feedback cycles.
Video games are near constant feedback
cycles as the user performs actions,
evaluates the results and
adjust accordingly.
In fact, if you read through video
game reviews you'll find that
many of the criticisms are actually
criticisms of bad HCI.
The controls are tough to use,
it's hard to figure out what happened.
The penalty for
failure is too low or too high.
All of these are examples
of poor interface design.
In gaming though there's such a tight
connection between the task and
the interface.
Their frustrations with a task
can help us quickly identify
problems with the interface.