Because we're interested in
human-computer interaction,
we almost certainly will have
human-subject interaction.
So when it asks, will the research
involve direct interaction with human
subjects, we would click, yes.
That will bring us to a screen
where we describe our subjects and
the data we plan to collect from them.
First, they want to know how many
subjects we have and what genders.
They want to make sure that we're not
wasting participants' time if we're not
going to actually
analyze all their data.
And that we're being fair
to the different genders.
A common problem in early research was
over-representing male populations.
Second, they'll want to know if we're
targeting any vulnerable populations.
People that might not have the capacity
to give true informed consent.
If we do, we need to make special
accommodations to make sure they're
fully aware of their
rights as participants.
Third, they want the scientific
justification for
the number of subjects
to enroll in our study.
Like I said, they want to make sure that
we're not going to waste the time of
a bunch off participants and
then just throw their data out.
That wouldn't be very respectful for
our participants' time.
If we're doing statistical tests this
might be the number of participants
necessary to find a certain effect size,
which we'll talk about when we
talk about quantitative research.
If we're doing qualitative research,
this is usually a smaller number and
is more based on how many
different perspectives we need
to get a good picture of what
we're trying to analyze.
Alternatively, we might have external
limits on our number of participants.
For example,
if you're doing classroom research,
your maximum number of students is the
maximum number of students in the class.
Next, we state the inclusion and
exclusion criterion.
The inclusion criterion are,
who we specifically including,
who's our targeting audience?
The exclusion criterion are those
that we're specifically excluding.
Often times, one of these will just
be the inverse of the other, but
there may be times when we
need to be more specific.
For example, if we were doing research
on undergraduate computer science
education, our inclusion criteria
might be undergraduate students.
But our exclusion criteria would be
undergraduate students that have
previously taken
a computer science class.
As before, we can skip the questions,
for our purposes at least,
that are more based
on clinical research.
But at the bottom, we need to provide
the steps necessary to ensure additional
protection of the rights and
welfare of vulnerable populations.
For example,
if we're working with 10 year olds,
how do we make sure 10 year olds really
understand that they really do have
the right to opt out of this research?
We need to provide a plan for
that here if we're working
with a vulnerable population.
Finally, we also need to describe
our recruitment procedures.
How are we going to find our subjects?
First, we'll note what we'll say and
how we'll communicate with them here.
If we're using the Georgia Tech
subject pool, which is a system for
finding research subjects within
the Georgia Tech student body,
we'll indicate so here.
And last,
we'll note the kind of compensation
we plan to provide the participants.
Many times we won't compensate
our participants at all.
But if we're doing a bigger research
study that actually has some external
funding, it's pretty normal to give them
some sort of monetary compensation for
participation.
It's we're using the George Tech subject
pool, our compensation will often be
extra credit in a certain class,
very often a psychologist class.
Note that the recruitment
procedures are very important,
especially if you're doing something
like classroom research, where there
can be a very significant perception of
coercion to get people to participate.
If I, as an instructor,
am recruiting students in my own class
to participate in my research project,
I have to be very clear
that it won't come back to haunt them
if they choose not to participate.