Of the remaining fields the only
one we're likely interested in is
the data management questions.
The majority of the others cover
either clinical research or
biological research or
other things that we
hopefully won't touch on very much
in human computer interaction.
Unless the field has changed a lot by
the time you're listening to this.
Nonetheless though you should actually
peek into the items to make sure that
they don't apply to you if you're
filling out a protocol like this.
Under the Data Management section,
we'll want to describe how we
keep participants data safe.
That'll include descriptions
of the way we store it and
define information about participants.
And how we'll safeguard the data
itself through password protection or
encryption or anything like that.
Finally, there are always some
questions that we answer for
all studies even though they
generally won't apply to us.
Generally our studies won't
involve the Department of Defense,
generally they shouldn't
involve Radiation.
And one day I really kind of hope
they involve Nanotechnology but
we're probably not quite there yet.
So we'd mark no that there
is no DoD involvement.
Finally, at the bottom, there's a place
to upload some additional documents.
This is where we would supply things
like an interview script, a survey,
a recruitment script and other documents
that the IRB would want to see and
approve.
When we're done, we can click Save and
Continue Application.
On the next page, we can preview
everything on one flat screen,
and then check off at the end that
we have no conflicts of interest, or
report them, if we do.
Then we'll click Save & Continue again.
And for y'all, you would then submit
it to your primary investigator.
I am the primary investigator so
I see something a little bit different
here than what you would see.
After submission, we'll generally hear
back from IRB in about three weeks about
whether the study was accepted and
what changes need to be made if not.