Null and alternative hypotheses are common to all kinds of hypothesis tests.
The specific kind of hypothesis tests you conduct however,
depends on the kind of data that you have.
Recall when we first started talking about quantitative data,
we discussed four general kinds: Nominal,
ordinal, interval and ratio.
What kinds of hypothesis tests we use will depend on what kind of data we've collected.
Note that my goal here isn't for you to know off
the top of your head how to do each of these tests.
Instead, I want you to know when to use each kind of test.
So, you can go and look it up when needed.
I've used all these kind of tests before and I
can't remember off the top my head how to do any of them.
But I know when to go look up which test and that's the most important thing for now.
For nominal data, we generally want to do something called a Chi-squared test.
A Chi-squared test checks to see if the distribution of values to
a number of buckets is the same across two conditions.
For all of these, I'm going to use a series of examples
inspired by comparison that I did recently
between my online undergraduate course and in traditional undergraduate course.
So for example, one of my questions was,
does the distribution of majors
differ between the online section and the traditional section?
Here our independent variable would be a pair of categories.
For me it's online and traditional,
and our dependent variable will be
the distribution among some other set of categories, here it's majors.
We always assume that the distributions are equal.
So, our alternative hypothesis would be the distributions are unequal.
Now, obviously the distributions are unequal in some ways.
There's a lot more students in traditional section.
That ratio isn't perfectly mirrored across all these categories.
Our question is, are these differences big
enough to assume that it's an actual difference between online and traditional?
Or, are the differences just a product of random noise?
If there are four times as many students in
the traditional section as the online section,
then we wouldn't expect exactly four times as
many computer science majors and exactly four times as many math majors.
But we also wouldn't expect the ratios to be way off either.
So, a Chi-squared test lets us test to see whether
distributions to this categories are comparable.
For ordinal data, we actually go with a very similar process.
Just like with nominal data,
we have our different categories as our independent variable and
our dependent variable is some distribution among a number of categories.
The difference here is that these categories are ranked.
What that means is we could actually use the exact same test.
We could use the Chi-squared test.
The weakness there is that the Chi-squared test isn't as
sensitive to systematic changes across these categories.
The Chi-squared test assumes all these different categories are independent.
We know though that if we see a small shift in all the categories from left to right,
that might actually be a significant difference between the two sections.
So, it's generally better to use what's called the Kolmogorov-Smirnov test.
It's very similar to the Chi-squared test but
it's sensitive to the fact that those categories are ordered.
Now that said, using the Chi-squared test isn't going to
hurt you with this kinda data and sometimes it can be easier to run.
There's also an alternative that more simply just test to see whether
it's likely that the medians of the two are different.
It's also not terribly uncommon to make the assumption
that these ordinal data categories are evenly spaced.
Now, remember when we talked about ordinal data and that
was exactly one of the weaknesses that we noted.
We noted that we can't know the difference between highly dissatisfied and dissatisfied,
is the same as the difference between dissatisfied and neutral.
Because we can't know that,
we're really not supposed to just average
these but in practice it's not uncommon for people to do so anyway.
In that case, we might just assign these categories numbers like one,
two, three, four and five,
multiply the number of observations by those numbers,
average them over the number of
actual respondents and see if there's a statistically significant difference.
It's not good to do that but if you
chose to do that you wouldn't be the first person ever to do so.
When we get to interval and ratio data,
the kinds of tests we use actually shift a good bit.
First, we really never treat interval and ratio data as different.
The fact that ratio data has a zero-point and interval data doesn't,
doesn't affect any of our statistical tests.
The statistical tests that we do for this kind of data are
always dependent on the average and the standard deviation.
The most common test is called the Student's t-test.
I'm not going to talk about it right now but I do recommend looking
up why it's called the Student's t-test.
It's kind of an interesting story.
For these are independent variable,
is the same as it's been in the past.
It's a category we're comparing between two different populations.
But our dependent variable is actually just the average of some kind of outcome.
We're not talking about distributions into subcategories but rather
just looking at a certain outcome for all participants in each category.
Our null hypothesis is that the outcomes are equal and
our alternative hypothesis is that the outcomes are unequal.
A t-test lets us pretty straightforwardly compare between the
two and see if the difference is actually statistically significant.
Again, we wouldn't expect the two numbers to have to be
exactly identical to say that the populations are not any different.
Here, an average of 10.2 compared to
9.9 probably isn't big enough to actually conclude that
the online section did any better than the traditional section especially when
the standard deviations are pretty significant fractions of those averages.
Don't worry though if you don't fully understand the math behind this,
you're really not supposed to right now.
For now all you really need to know is that the difference has to be big enough to
justify that one is actually different from the other and how big,
big enough actually is,
is dependent on how big that standard deviation is.
The bigger the standard deviation,
the bigger the difference needs to be.
Now it's also worth noting that we're only supposed to use
t-tests when the data distribution is normal.
That means it mirrors irregular bell-curve.
If it's not normal,
we're supposed to use things like
the Mann-Whitney-Wilcoxon test or the Kruskal-Wallis Test.
But those topics are kind of outside our scope.
Generally speaking, a Chi-squared test and a t-test will get you most of what you
need at least until we get to having three different levels of our independent variable.