Chi-squared tests and t-tests are probably the most commonly used tests in HCI.
However, there are some assumptions embedded in the ones we just looked at.
First, notice that we only ever had two levels to our independent variable.
We were only ever comparing online and traditional students.
For your work, that might mean only comparing two different interfaces.
What if we wanted to test three? How can we do that?
Imagine for example, I wanted to test
these two classes against a third class or flipped class.
Here we'd be testing the online section versus
the traditional section versus the flipped section, how would we do that?
You might be tempted to just test them in a pairwise fashion,
test online versus traditional,
traditional verse flipped and online verse flipped.
You use that to try to uncover any differences between pairs.
That's called repeated testing,
and the problem, is that it raises the likelihood of a type one error.
A type one error is also called a false positive,
and it's where we falsely reject the null hypothesis.
In other words, we falsely say that we have
enough data to conclude the alternative hypothesis.
Here that would mean, falsely concluding
that there is a difference when there isn't actually a difference.
The reason repeated testing raises likelihood of this,
is that remember we said that we reject the null hypothesis if there's
generally less than a five percent chance it could have occurred by random chance.
But if you do three different tests,
you raise the likelihood of one of them turning
up conclusive even though it really isn't.
Think of it like playing the lottery.
If I say you have a one in 20 chance of winning and you play 20 times,
you'll still win once.
That's because your overall odds of winning increased.
Performing multiple tests, raises our overall likelihood of finding a false positive.
So instead, what we need,
is a single test that can compare against all these different treatments at once.
Now fortunately, for ordinal or nominal data,
it's actually just the same test.
A chi-squared test can handle more than just two levels of our independent variable.
Our alternative tests change a little bit,
if we're dealing with more than two levels.
The weakness here, is if we do a Chi-squared test on all three of these levels at once,
all it will tell us is if there's any difference between any of the levels.
It doesn't tell us where the difference is.
So, if this chi-squared test shows that there is a difference,
we don't have any way of knowing,
is it the difference between the online and traditional,
online and flipped, traditional and flipped,
or is it a case where the flipped is different
from both the online and traditional or something like that.
So, generally what we do,
is we do an overall chi-squared tests on all of the levels,
and then we can follow up if that first test was
successful with a pairwise comparison between the conditions.
In that case, for basically concluding that we know there's
a difference before we actually do the repeated testing.
So, the overall odds of finding a false positive aren't changing.
For interval and ratio data though,
we need to use a different test altogether.
This test is called an analysis of variance or ANOVA.
A one-way ANOVA test,
let's us compare between three or more groups simultaneously.
Here, that means we could test between all three of our classes at the same time.
For you that can mean guessing between three or four interfaces at the same time.
With a two-way ANOVA, we could actually take this a step further.
We could have two dimensions of independent variables,
we could test online traditional and flipped
against upper class mean versus lower-class mean.
We could actually get it differences like,
do freshmen do better at online but sophomores do better in traditional.
The weakness though, is the same as the weakness with the chi-squared test,
and analysis of variance will tell us if there are differences,
but it won't tell us where the differences are.
Our approach to that is the same as it was with the chi-squared test as well.
If the analysis of variance indicates there's an overall difference,
then we can follow up with pairwise t-tests.
Notice though, there's still one assumption that's been
embedded in every single analysis we've talked about.
Our independent variables have always been categorical,
that's generally true for most of the tests we're going to do.
If we're testing one interface against another,
then those are our two categories.
If we're testing one body of people against another,
So, this isn't really a weakness or a challenge,
but there are cases where we want
our independent variable to be something non-categorical.
Mostly that happens when we want
our independent variable to be some interval or ratio data.
So, imagine for example I wanted to see if GPA was a good predictor of course grade.
GPA though is generally considered interval data,
we might consider it ratio data but it's usually discussed as interval data.
We could do this by breaking GPA down into categories.
Instead of this, we could average the course grades for anyone with a GPA from 3.5-4,
3-3.5, and so on.
Or we could leave the GPA is interval data,
and just do a direct analysis.
Generally, here we'd be doing a regression or
we would see how well one variable predicts another.
Most of our regressions are linear,
but we could also do a logistic regression,
a polynomial regression, and lots more.
Again, I'm getting outside the scope of our class.
Here, our null hypothesis is that the variables are unrelated,
and our alternative hypothesis is that they are related.
So, we need evidence that they're related before assuming that they are.
Here things get a little bit more complex as well,
because we're not quite as emphatic about how we
reject our null hypothesis and accept our alternative hypothesis.
Usually with regressions, we describe how well the two fit.
They might fit very well,
somewhat well, not well at all, and so on.
Before we move on, there's one last type of data I'd like to talk about,
and that's binomial data.
Binomial data is data with only two possible outcomes, like a coin flip.
For us we might have outcomes like success in a class.
In HCI, we might be curious which of
multiple interfaces allows users to succeeded a task with greater frequency.
Notice there that, success and failure are binary,
and that's what makes this binomial data.
What can be tricky here,
is that our data actually looks continuous,
it looks just like straightforward continuous ratio data.
Here we might say online students succeed 94.9 percent of the time,
in traditional students succeed 92.1 percent of the time,
and we might be tempted just to do a straightforward t-test on that.
But if you try to do the math,
you'll quickly find that it doesn't work.
A t-test requires a standard deviation,
and if every single student is either a one or a zero,
a success or a failure,
then you don't really have a standard deviation in the same way.
So instead, we have a specific tests that we use for
binomial data called a binomial test.
With a two sample binomial test,
we compare two different sets of trials,
each with a certain number of successes.
So, we can answer questions like;
does one lead to a greater ratio of successes than the other?
Alternatively, we can also do a one-sample binomial test.
That's where we compare only one set of trials to some arbitrary number. So, for example.
If we wanted to prove that a coin was unbalanced,
we would use a one-sample binomial test comparing it to a ratio of 50 percent.
You'll know that you want to use binomial data,
if the individual observations you're getting out of users are binary.
If you're only concerned with whether they succeeded or failed on
a particular task and if your data is
just a bunch of instances of successes and failures,
then you're using binomial data.
If the data you're getting out of your users is more complex
like multiple categories or continuous observations,
then you're probably looking at using a chi-squared test or
a t-test or any of the ones we talked about before.
Now, we've gone through a lot of tests and we've gone through them very quickly,
but remember our goal is just for you to know what test to use and when.
Once you've identified the appropriate test,
looking at how to do it and actually putting the data in,
is usually a much simpler task.