Here are five quick tips for doing empirical evaluations.
You can actually take entire classes on doing empirical evaluations,
but these tips should get you started.
Number one, control what you can,
document what you can't.
Try to make your treatments as identical as possible.
However, if there are systematic differences between them,
document and report that.
Number two, limit your variables.
It can be tempting to try to vary lots of
different things and monitor lots of other things,
but that just leads to noisy difficult data
that will probably generate some false conclusions.
Instead, focus on varying
only one or two things and monitor only a handful of things in response.
There's nothing at all wrong with only modifying
one variable and only monitoring one variable.
Number three, work backwards in designing your experiment.
A counter state that I've seen is just to
gather a bunch of data and figure out how to analyze it later.
That's messy, and it doesn't lead to very reliable conclusions.
Decide at the start what question you want to answer,
then decide the analysis you need to use,
and then decide the data that you need to gather.
Number four, script your analyses in advance.
Ronald Coase once said,
"If you torture the data long enough,
nature will always confess."
What the quote means is If we analyze and reanalyze data enough times,
we can always find conclusions,
but that doesn't mean that they're actually there.
So, decide in advance what analysis you'll do and do it.
If it doesn't give you the results that you want,
don't just keep reanalyzing that same data until it does.
Number five, pay attention to power.
Power refers to the size of the difference that a test can detect.
Generally, it's very dependent on how many participants you have.
If you want to detect only a small effect,
then you'll need a lot of participants.
If you only care about detecting a big effect,
you can usually get by with fewer.