There are a lot of ways
to evaluate interfaces.
So to organize our
discussion of evaluation,
I've broken these into three categories.
The first is qualitative evaluation.
This is where we want to get
qualitative feedback from users.
What do they like, what do they dislike,
what's easy, what's hard.
We'll get that information through some
methods very similar, in fact identical,
to our methods for need finding.
The second is empirical evaluation.
This is where we actually want to
do some controlled experiments and
evaluate the results quantitatively.
For that,
we need many more participants, and
we also want to make sure we addressed
the big qualitative feedback first.
The third is predictive evaluation.
Predictive evaluation is specifically
evaluation without users.
In user centered design,
this is obviously not our
favorite kind of evaluation.
Evaluation with real users
though is oftentimes slow and
its really expensive.
So it's useful for
us to have ways we can do some simple
evaluation on a day to day basis.
So we'll structure our discussion of
evaluation around these three general
categories.