The most common type of predictive evaluation you'll
encounter is most likely the cognitive walkthrough.
In a cognitive walkthrough,
we stepped through the process of interacting with an interface,
mentally simulating in each stage what the user is seeing and thinking and doing.
To do this, we start by constructing
specific tasks that can be completed within our prototype.
So I'm going to try this with the card prototype that I used with Morgan earlier.
I start with some goal in mind.
So right now, my goal might be to leave a note while listening.
I look at the interface and I try to imagine myself as a novice user.
Will they know what to do?
Well, here's a button that says View and Take Notes,
and if they want to take a note,
I think that's reasonable to assume that they would know to do that.
So I tap that button and what response do I get?
Well, that's when this screen will come up.
The system will pause playback first and then it will show me the note-taking screen,
and I go through the entire system like this,
predicting what actions the user will
take and noting the response of the system will give.
At every stage of the process,
I want to investigate this from the perspective of the gulfs of execution and evaluation.
Is it reasonable to expect the user to cross that gulf of execution?
Is the right action sufficiently obvious?
Is a response to the action,
the one the user would expect?
Now on the other side, is it reasonable to
expect the feedback to cross the gulf of evaluation?
Does the feedback show the user what happened?
Does the feedback confirm the user chose the right action?
Now, the weakness of cognitive walkthroughs is that we're the designers,
so it likely seems to us like the design is just fine.
After all, that's why we designed it that way.
But if you can sufficiently put yourself in the user's shoes,
you can start to uncover some really useful takeaways.
So, here for example,
from this cognitive walkthrough,
I've noticed that there isn't sufficient feedback
when the user has finished leaving a note.
The system just stops recording and resumes
playback which doesn't confirm that the note is received,
and right now that might be a minor issue since there's implicit feedback.
The only way that playback resumes is if the note is received,
but I'm also now realizing that it's quite likely that
users might start to leave notes and then decide to cancel them,
so they both need a cancel option,
and they need feedback to indicate whether the note was completed and saved or canceled.
I got all that feedback just out of this cognitive walkthrough of the interface as is.
So if you can put yourself in the novice's shoes well enough,
you can find some really good feedback without the difficulties of involving real users.