When we discussed the prototypes for our design for an audio book tool for exercisers,
we briefly showed the evaluation stage with Morgan actually using them.
Let's look at that in a little bit more depth though.
What were we evaluating?
At any stage of the process,
we could have been performing qualitative evaluation.
We asked Morgan how easy or hard things were to do,
how much he enjoyed using the interface,
and what her thought process was in interacting with certain prototypes.
We could have also performed some quantitative analyses.
When she used the card-based prototype for example,
we could have measured the amount of time it took her to decide what to do,
or counted the number of errors she committed.
We could do the same kind of thing with the Wizard of Oz Prototype as well.
We could call to Morgan commands like press play and place a bookmark,
and see how long it takes her to execute the commands,
or how many errors she commits along the way.
Between opportunities to work with Morgan though,
we might also use some predictive evaluation
to ensure that we keep her in mind while we're designing.
Our goal is to apply
multiple evaluation techniques to constantly center our designs around the user.
That's why evaluation is a foundation of user-centered design.
Just like we wanted to understand the user and the task before beginning to design,
we also want to understand how the user relates to
the design at every iteration of the design life-cycle.