In this lesson, we've discussed the basics of evaluation.
Evaluation is a massive topic to cover though.
You could take entire classes on evaluation.
Heck, you could take entire classes only on specific types of evaluation.
Our goal here has been to give you enough information
to know what to look into further and when.
We want you to understand when to use qualitative evaluation,
when to use empirical evaluation,
and when to use predictive evaluation.
We want you to understand within those categories,
what the different options are.
That way, when you're ready to begin evaluation,
you know what you should look into doing.