Before we begin, there's some vocabulary we need to cover to understand evaluation.
These things especially applied to the data that we gathered during evaluation.
While there are particularly relevant for gathering quantitative data,
they're useful in discussing or other kinds of data as well.
The first term is reliability.
Reliability refers to whether or not some assessment
of some phenomenon is consistent over time.
So for example, Amanda what time is it?
It's about 2:30.
Amanda what time is it? It's about 2:30.
Amanda, what time is it? It's 2:30.
Amanda is a very reliable assessment of the time.
Every time I asked, she gives me the same time.
We want that in an assessment measure.
We want it to be reliable across multiple trials.
Otherwise, its conclusions are random and just not very useful.
A second principle is validity.
Validity refers to how accurately and assessment measures reality.
An assessment could be completely reliable but completely inaccurate.
So for example, Amanda, what time is it?
Oh my goodness, it's 2:30!
Actually it's 1:30. Oh, shoot!
So while Amanda was a reliable timekeeper,
she wasn't a very valid one.
Her time wasn't correct even though it was consistent.
Validity is closely connected to a principle called generalizability.
Generalizability is the extent to which we can apply lessons we learned
in our evaluation to broader audiences of people.
So for example, we might find that the kinds of people that volunteer for
usability studies have different preferences than the regular user.
So the conclusions we find that those volunteers might
not be generalizable in measuring what we want
to measure.Finally one last term we want to know is to understand its precision.
Precision is a measurement of how specific some assessment is.
So for example, Amanda, what time is it?
Well apparently, it's 1:30.
Actually, it's 1:31. Come on!
But in this case, no one's really going to say that
Amanda was wrong in saying that it was 1:30.
She just wasn't as precise.
I could just as accurately say it's 1:31:27,
but that's probably more precision than we need.
As we describe the different kinds of data we can gather during evaluation,
keep these things in mind.
If we were to conduct the same procedure again,
how likely is it that we'd get the same results?
That's reliability. How accurately does our data actually
capture the real world phenomenon that we care about? That's validity.
To what extent can we apply these conclusions to people that weren't in the evaluation?
That's generalizability.
How specific are our conclusions and observations? That's precision.