Regardless of the type of evaluation
you're planning to perform, there's
a series of steps to perform to ensure
that the evaluation is actually useful.
First, we want to clearly define
the task that we're examining.
Depending on your place in the design
process this can be very large or
very small.
If we were designing Facebook, it can be
as simple as posting a status update, or
as complicated as navigating amongst and
using several different pages.
It could involve context and constraints
like taking notes while running, or
looking up a restaurant address
without touching the screen.
Whatever it is,
we want to start by clearly identifying
what task we're going to investigate.
Second, we want to define
our performance measures.
How are we going to evaluate
the user's performance?
Qualitatively, it could be
based on their spoken or
written feedback about the experience.
Quantitatively, we can measure
efficiency in certain activities or
count the number of mistakes.
Defining performance measures
helps us avoid confirmation bias.
It makes sure we don't just pick
out whatever observations or
data confirm our hypotheses, or
say that we have a good interface.
It forces us to look at it objectively.
Third, we develop the experiment.
How will we find user's performance
on the performance measures?
If we're looking qualitatively will
we have them think out loud while
they're using the tool?
Or will we have them do
a survey after they're done?
If we're looking quantitatively what
will we measure, what will we control,
and what will we vary?
This is also where we ask questions
about whether our assessment
measures are reliable and valid.
And whether the users we're
testing are generalizable.
Fourth, we recruit the participants.
As part of the ethics process, we make
sure we're recruiting participants
who are aware of their rights and
contributing willingly.
Then fifth, we do the experiment.
We have them walk-through what we
outline when we develop the experiment.
Sixth, we analyze the data.
We focus on what the data tells us
about our performance measures.
It's important that we stay close
to what we outlined initially.
It can be tempting to just look for
whatever supports are design but
we want to be impartial.
If we find some evidence that suggests
our interface is good in ways we didn't
anticipate, we can always do a follow
up experiment to test if we're right.
Seventh, we summarize the data
in a way that informs our on
going design process.
What did our data say was working?
What could be improved?
How can we take the results
of this experiment and
use it to then revise our interface?
The results of this experiment then
become part of our design life cycle.
We investigated user needs, develop
alternatives, made a prototype and
put the prototype in front of users.
To put the prototype in front of users,
we walked through this
experimental method.
We defined the task,
defined the performance measures,
developed the experiment,
recruited them, did the experiment,
analyzed our data and
summarized our data.
Based on the experience, we now have
the data necessary to develop a better
understanding of the user's needs, to
revisit our earlier design alternatives
and to either improve our prototypes
by increasing their fidelity or
by revising them based
on what we just learned.
Regardless of whether we're
doing qualitative, empirical, or
predictive evaluation,
these steps remain largely the same.
Those different types of evaluation just
fill in the experiment that we develop,
and they inform our performance measure,
data analysis, and summaries.