Qualitative evaluation involves getting qualitative feedback from the user.
There are a lot of qualitative questions we want to ask
throughout the design process. What did you like?
What did you dislike? What were you thinking while using this interface?
What was your goal when you took that particular action?
Now, if this sounds familiar,
it's because it should be.
The methods we use for qualitative evaluation are very
similar to the methods we used for need-finding: interviews,
think-aloud protocols, focus groups, surveys, post-event protocols.
We use those methods to get information about the task in the first place, and now,
we can use these techniques to get feedback on how our prototype changes the task.