The first stage of the design lifecycle is need-finding or requirements gathering.
This is the stage where we go and try to find out what the user really needs.
The biggest mistake that the designer can make is jumping to
the design process before understanding the user or the task.
We want to develop a deep understanding of the task they're trying to accomplish and why.
As we do this,
it's important to try to come in with as few preconceived notions as possible.
There's an old adage that says,
"When all you have is a hammer,
everything looks like a nail." This is similar.
If you come in having already decided what approach you want to take,
it's tempting to only see the problem in terms of the approach you've chosen.
So, we're going to go through a process that attempts to avoid
as many preconceived notions as possible.
We're going to start by defining some general questions we want to answer
throughout the data gathering process about who the user is,
what they're doing, and what they need.
Then, we'll go through several methods of generating answers to
those questions to gain a better understanding of the user.
Then, we'll talk about how to formalize the data we gather into
a shareable model of the task and a list of requirements for our ultimate interface.
Note that each of these tools could get a lesson on its own on how to do it.
So, we'll try to provide some additional resources to read
further on the tools you choose to use.