When we're trying to make iterative improvements,
one of the best places we can look is at the errors
users make with the tools that they currently have available.
We can fix those errors,
but we can also use those errors to understand a bit more about the user's mental model.
So, here's a common example of an error for me, which is slip.
I keep my email open in the window on the left.
I frequently forget that it's
my active window while I'm trying to type into one of the other windows,
and as a result, I'll hit a bunch of hotkeys in my email interface.
I'll tag random emails, delete random emails.
It's just kind of a mess.
Now, this is a slip because there's nothing wrong with my mental model of how this works.
I understand there's an active window and it's not selected.
The problem is that I can easily forget which window is active.
Mistakes, on the other hand, are places where my mental model is weak,
and for me, a place where that happens is when I'm using my Mac.
I'm used to PC where the maximize button always makes a window take up the entire screen.
I've honestly never fully understood the maximize button on a Mac.
Sometimes, it seems to work like a PC maximize button.
Sometimes, it just expands the window a bit,
but not to the entire screen.
Sometimes, it enters even like a full-screen mode hiding the top taskbar.
I make mistakes there because I don't have a strong mental model of how it works.
So, if you are watching me,
you could see me making these errors and you could ask me why I'm making them.
Why did I choose to do that if that was my goal?
That works for both discovering hacks and discovering errors.
Watch people performing their tasks and ask
them about why certain things happened the way that they do.
Discovering hacks and errors involves
a little bit more user interaction than just watching people out in the wild.
So, how about we do that if we're doing something
like creating an app that people are going to use in public?
Well, maybe we actually go up to people we see exercising out in public.
We can actually get approval to do that,
but that's going to be a little bit awkward and
the data we get might not always be great.
So, at this point, we might be better off
recruiting people to come in and describe their experiences.
People experience hacks and errors pretty consciously.
So, our best bet would likely be to target
local exercise groups or local areas where exercisers frequent,
and recruit people to come in for a short study.
Or maybe, we could recruit people to
participate in a study during their normal exercise routine,
taking notes on their experience or talking us through their thought process.
We can actually take that to an extreme and actually adapt something like
an apprenticeship approach where we actually train to become users.