A most targeted way of gather
information from users though is just to
talk to them.
One way of doing that might be to
bring them in for an interview.
So I'm sitting here with Morgan,
who's one of the potential users for
our audio book app
targeted at exercisers.
And we're especially interested in
the kinds of task you perform while
exercising and listening to
audio books at the same time.
So to start,
what kind of challenges do you run
into doing these two things at once?
>> I think the biggest challenge
is that it's hard to control it.
I have headphones that have a button
on them that can pause it and play.
But if I want to do anything else I
have to stop, pull up my phone and
unlock it just to rewind.
>> Yeah, that makes sense.
Thank you.
Interviews are useful ways to get at
with the user is thinking when they're
engaging in a task.
You can do interviews
one on one like this or
you can even do interviews in a group
with multiple users at the same time.
Those tend to take on
the form of focus groups,
where a number of people are all
talking together about some topic, and
you can use them to tease out
different kinds of information.
Focus groups can elicit some information
we don't get from this kind of
an interview, but they also present
the risk of overly convergent thinking.
People tend to kind of agree with other
instead of bringing in new ideas.
So they should really be used
in conjunction with interviews,
as well as other need
finding techniques.