Here are five quick tips for conducting effective interviews.
Now, we recommend reading more about this before you actually start interviewing people,
but these should get you started.
Number one, focus on the six W's when you're writing your questions,
who, what, where, when, why, and how.
Try to avoid questions that lend themselves to one word or yes or no answers,
those are better gathered via surveys.
Use your interview questions to ask open-ended semi-structured questions.
Number two, be aware of bias.
Look at how you're phrasing your questions and interactions and
make sure you're not predisposing the participant to certain views.
If you only smile when they say what you want them to say, for example,
your risk biasing them to agree with you.
Number three, listen.
Many novice interviewers get caught up in having a conversation with
a participant rather than gathering data from the participant.
Make sure the participant is doing the vast majority of
the talking and don't reveal anything that might predispose them to agree with you.
Number four, organize the interview.
Make sure to have an introduction phase,
some lighter questions to build trust,
and a summary at the end,
so the user understands the purpose of the questions.
Be ready to push the interview forward or pull it back on track.
Number five, practice.
Practice your questions on friends,
family, or research partners in advance.
Rehearse the entire interview.
Gathering subjects is tough,
so when you actually have them,
you want to make sure to get the most out of them.