Interviews are likely to be one of
the most common ways you gather data.
So let's run through some good and
bad interview questions real quick.
So here are six questions.
Which of these would make
good interview questions?
Mark the ones that would be good.
For the ones that would be bad,
briefly brainstorm a way to rewrite
the question to make it better.
You can go ahead and skip forward to the
exercise if you don't want to listen to
me read them out.
Number one, do you exercise?
Number two, how often do you exercise?
Number three, do you exercise for
health or for pleasure?
Number four, what, if anything do
you listen to while exercising?
Number five, what device do you use to
listen to something while exercising?
Number six, we're developing an app for
listening to audio
books while exercising.
Would that be interesting to you?