Think-aloud protocols are similar to
interviews in that we're asking users to
talk about their
perceptions of the task.
But with think-aloud,
we're asking them to actually do so
in the context of the task.
So instead of bringing Morgan in to
answer some questions about listening to
audiobooks while exercising,
I'll ask her to actually think
out loud while listening to
audiobooks and exercising.
If this was a different task
like something on a computer,
I could have her just come
into my lab and work on it.
But since this is out in the world,
what I might just do is give her a voice
recorder to record her thoughts while
she's out running and listening.
Now think aloud is very useful, because
it can help us get at users thoughts
that they forget when they are no
longer engaged in the task.
But it's also a bit dangerous by asking
people to think aloud about their task,
we encourage them to think
about it more deliberately and
that can change the way
they actually act.
So while it's useful to get an
understanding of what they are thinking,
we should check to see if there are
places where what they do differs when
thinking out loud about it.
We can do that with what's
called a post-event protocol,
which is largely the same,
except we wait to get the user's
thoughts until immediately
after the activity.
That way, the activity is still
fresh in their minds, but
the act of thinking about it shouldn't
affect their performance quite as much.