Most of the other methods for need
finding, like observation, interviewing,
apprenticeship, require
a significant amount of effort for
what is often relatively little data.
Or it's data from
a small number of users.
We might spend an entire hour
interviewing a single possible user or
an hour observing a small
number of users in the world.
The data we get from those interactions
is deep and thorough, but sometimes,
we also want broader data.
Sometimes, we just want to know how many
people encounter a certain difficulty or
engage in a certain task.
If we're designing an audio book app for
exercisers, for example.
Maybe we just want to know how
often those people exercises or
maybe we want to know what
kind of books they listen to.
At that point, a survey might be our
more appropriate means of need finding.
Surveys let us get a much larger
number of responses very quickly and
the questions can be
phrased objectively,
allowing for quicker interpretation.
And plus, with the Internet, they can
be administered asynchronously for
at a pretty low cost.
A few weeks ago, for example,
I came up with the idea for
a study on Friday morning.
And with the great cooperation from our
local IRB office, I was able to send out
the survey to potential participants
less than 24 hours later and
receive 150 responses within a week.
Now of course, the data I receive from
that isn't nearly as thorough as what I
would receive from interviewing
some of those participants.
But it's a powerful way of
getting a larger amount of data.
And it can be especially useful to
decide what to ask participants
during interviews or
during focus groups.