Surveys are used often in HCI because of their convenience,
but they're only useful if the questions are actually well-written.
Tips like "Be aware of bias" and "Test it out" are good pieces of general advice,
but there are also lots of
specific things that we can do to make our survey questions better.
So, in fact, there are six things I personally recommend in survey design: be clear,
be concise, be specific,
be expressive, be unbiased, and be usable.
Let's go through what these actually mean in practice.
Be clear means we want to make sure the user actually understands what we're asking.
So, if we're using a numeric scale,
for example, we don't want to just give them numbers.
We want to actually code those numbers with what they mean.
It's not uncommon to see some larger scales code only the first,
last, and middle number,
but it's always better to assign some kind of label to every single number,
and make sure they're parallel.
We wouldn't want some thing like highly dissatisfied,
dissatisfied, neutral, a little satisfied, and satisfied.
We also want to avoid overlapping ranges if we're asking about some range of numbers.
So, here we're asking, "How many times per week do you watch Hulu?"
So, if a user says they generally watch twice per week,
it's not clear whether they would choose 0-2 or 2-5.
Instead, we want to make sure the ranges don't overlap.
If we're in doubt on whether the user will actually understand our question,
we should provide some extra detail.
For example, if we were asking,
"Do you own a tablet computer?"
We might infer that not all our users really understand what a tablet computer is.
So, we'd go on to define and say it's
a computer with a touchscreen and detachable keyboard.
That improves the likelihood that the user actually understands what we're asking.
If we're asking about a frequency,
it's useful to timebox it.
So, for example, if we ask,
"How often do you exercise?"
Users might not fully understand what the difference
between rarely and occasionally is, for example.
Is rarely once a week,
once a month, once a year?
Is frequently everyday, five times a week?
So, instead, we probably want to ask a question like,
"In the past seven days,
how many times have you done this behavior?"
That's a much more objective question and a lot easier to answer.
Second, we want to be concise with our questions.
We always want to make sure to ask our questions in
plain language that the user can understand.
So, for example, instead of asking something like,
"What was the overall level of cleanliness that
you observed within the car that you rented?"
We'd ask, "How clean was the car?"
Now, it is worth noting that sometimes being concise and being clear are at odds.
Adding more detail inherently means being less concise.
So, it's a trade-off.
Use your best judgment to decide when adding more detail will be worth the trade-off.
Third, when asking questions,
we want to be specific.
We want to avoid questions that are on super-big ideas.
For example, "How satisfied were you with the interface?"
Well, there's a lot of elements of satisfaction with using an interface.
Asking about satisfaction with the interface as
a whole is such a big question that it's hard to answer.
Instead, we might ask a series of
smaller questions like how satisfied were you with how quickly
the interface responded to your commands or how
satisfied were you with how easily you could find the command you were looking for.
Part of this is avoiding what are called double-barrel questions.
A double-barrel question is a question that asks about two things at the same time.
So, for example, if we were asked,
"How satisfied are you with the speed and availability of your mobile connection?
What if a user were satisfied with the availability,
but not satisfied with the speed?"
How did they answer that question?
So, instead, we will break this up into two questions,
one asking about speed,
one asking about availability.
We also want to avoid questions that allows some internal conflict.
This is similar to avoiding questions about big ideas.
For example, how satisfied were you with your food?
Well, I might have been satisfied with the taste of it,
but not with the temperature of it or not the appearance of it.
So, instead, we break that down into smaller questions that each
address each individual component of satisfaction.
Four, we want to be expressive or really what they
should say is allow the user to be expressive,
but that would break my nice little symmetry over here.
We want to make sure to emphasize the user's opinions.
Sometimes users taking our surveys are hesitant to be very emphatic or very critical.
So, we want to make sure to emphasize in
the questions that we're looking for their opinions.
Instead of asking, "Is our subscription price too high?"
We might ask, "Do you feel our subscription price is too high,
too low, or about right?"
In the second version, a user could say too
high without feeling like they're being very combative.
Whenever possible, we want to use ranges instead of yes and no questions.
That allows the user to express more of the details about their individual answers.
So, instead of asking,
"Do you use social media? Yes or no?"
We might ask, "In the past seven days,
how much time have you spent on social media?"
This allows the user to express something more closely
resembling the complexity of their answer.
If we're asking about something with levels of frequency or levels of agreement,
we want to give lots of levels.
Simply saying how satisfied are you, dissatisfied,
or satisfied isn't enough to capture the full range of user opinions.
I generally recommend always using at least five,
so you can differentiate people who are highly satisfied,
which means I have no complaints from people who are satisfied,
which means I might have some complaints,
but overall, it's a positive experience.
That's actually a pretty useful distinction to arrive at.
When possible, it's also useful to allow users to make multiple selections.
For example, imagine we were asking,
"What social media platform do you use the most?"
Then we're losing something with those users who think
they use multiple platforms with equal frequency.
So, instead, why not let them choose more than one?
There might be some good reason why we want them to choose only one,
maybe some follow-up questions are based on that,
but a lot of times it may also be beneficial to allow them to select multiple answers.
For questions that are nominal or categorical,
it's often good to let them add new categories.
So, instead of just giving them six to choose from,
we could give them six to choose from,
but also a box to put in another one.
That allows them to express ideas that we didn't anticipate.
My fifth piece of advice is to be unbiased or to avoid bias wherever possible,
and that last question is actually a good example of that as well.
If we don't give them that other box,
then we're biasing them with only our pre-established selections.
Now, sometimes that's okay.
If we've done a lot of surveys in the past and found that
these are the only answers anyone ever puts in,
then it's okay to limit the space to only those.
Just remember, if you provide users categories and don't give them another box,
then you might be biasing them towards only those opinions that you anticipated.
But even if you provide another box,
you still risk some bias.
So, for example, if you ask,
"Why did you choose our service over our competitors?"
A user might look at these options and say, "Well,
now that you mention it,
I guess it was because of your good reputation."
But if you ask them this question without giving them options,
they may have given a different answer.
It was the act of reading these options that made them think,
"Maybe that's why I did that."
So, often it's good to actually leave these potentially open-ended questions open.
Let them just say in free text why they chose your service.
Now, again, if you've done the survey for
awhile and have a lot of these open-ended responses,
and you found that there's only really four or five answers that users ever put in,
then it's okay to distill those down to options.
In that case, you've done enough data analysis
to understand that these are really the only selections.
But if you aren't yet sure the full space of answers you might receive,
it can be better to leave it open-ended.
We also need to avoid leading questions.
This one is a little bit more obvious.
If we're asking for opinions on our new interface,
we don't want to say something like,
"Did our brand new AI-based interface generate better recommendations? Yes or no?"
Obviously, here we want the user to choose yes.
Instead, we should ask it in a more neutral fashion.
"How satisfied were you with the recommendations the interface generated?"
Similarly, we want to avoid loaded questions.
For example, "In the past seven days,
how much time have you wasted on social media?"
Asking the question like that is guaranteed to lower our estimates,
compared to, "In the past seven days,
how much time have you spent on social media?"
Finally, my last word of advice is to make your survey usable.
Now, a lot of this is actually going to come down to
the details of the survey platform that you choose,
but some of these are decisions that you can make as well.
For example, it's always good to provide a progress bar that lets the user know how
far along in the survey they actually are and adjust their expectations accordingly.
It's not uncommon for users to quit
surveys because they don't know how close they were to the end,
even though in reality,
they were only a few seconds away from the last question.
Along the same line,
it's good to make your page links consistent.
If you have a five-page survey,
you don't want one question on the first page,
and 50 on the second page,
and two on the third page.
If a user opens a second page and sees 50 questions,
they're going to naturally assume that the remaining pages also have 50 questions.
So, try to make them consistent to set
accurate expectations about how long the survey is going to take.
Third, order your questions logically.
There should be some natural flow to the order in which you ask different questions.
You don't want to go from a demographic question to a satisfaction question,
back to a demographic question.
You want to gather your questions into topics.
Ideally, they should take the user along
the thought process that you want them to engage in while answering your questions.
Fourth, at the end of the survey,
it's good to alert users about unanswered questions.
On the one hand, maybe the user didn't know they skipped the question.
This lets them know, so they can go back and answer.
But on the other hand, maybe they skipped that question intentionally,
maybe they weren't comfortable answering,
maybe they just don't have an answer,
maybe your space of answer options didn't capture what they thought.
So, you don't want to force them to go back and answer it,
but you also want to account for times when they may have accidentally skipped it.
So, let them know,
but don't force them to go back.
Finally, preview the survey yourself. This takes some discipline.
I have lots of surveys that I never previewed and later found out I
use check mark boxes instead of radio buttons for a particular question.
So, force yourself to actually preview
the survey and fill it out as if you were a real user.
Don't just scroll through it,
actually go through and answer each question.
So, that was quite a lot of information,
but I'm hoping the fact that most of the tips were pretty
practical will make it easy to apply.
When in doubt, remember,
you can always ask for feedback on your survey
questions before sending it out to actual participants.