So far we've discussed some of the more
common approaches that need finding.
Depending on your domain though, there
might be some other things you can do.
First, if you're designing for a task
for which interfaces already exist,
you might start by critiquing the
interfaces that already exist using some
of the evaluation methods that we'll
cover later in the evaluation lesson.
For example, if you're wanting to design
a new system for ordering takeout food,
you might evaluate the interfaces
of calling in an order,
ordering via mobile phone or
ordering via a website.
Second and similarly, [SOUND] if you're
trying to develop a tool to address
a problem that people that are already
addressing, you might go look at user
reviews and see what people already like
and dislike about existing products.
For example, there are dozens of
alarm clock apps out there, and
thousands of reviews.
If you want to design a new one,
you could start there to find out
what people need or
what their common complaints are.
Third, if you're working on a task that
already involves a lot of automatic
logging like web surfing, you could try
to get some logs of user interaction
that have already been generated.
For example, say you wanted to
build a browser that's better at
anticipating what the user
will want to open next.
You could grab datalogs and look for
trends both within and across users.
You can creative with your
data gathering methods.
The goal is to use a variety of
methods to paint a complete picture
of the user's task.