The needfinding exercises
that we've gone through so
far focus on the needs
of the exercisers.
What can they do with their hands,
what is the environment around them
like while exercising, and so on?
However, that's only half the picture
for this particular design.
Our ultimate goal is to bring
the experience of consuming books
to people that exercise,
which means we also need to understand
the task of book-reading on its own.
Now a problem space is
still around exercisers, so
we wouldn't go through the entire design
life cycle for book reading on its own.
We don't need to design or
prototype anything for them.
But if we're going to bring the full
book reading experience to people while
exercising, we need to
understand what that is.
So take a moment and
design an approach to needfinding for
people who are reading on their own.