We've noted that design is a life cycle
from needfinding to brainstorming design
alternatives to
prototyping to evaluation.
And then, back to needfinding
to continue the cycle again.
Needfinding on it's own though
can be a cycle by itself.
For example, we might use the results
of our naturalistic observation
to inform the questions we
asked during our interviews.
For example, imagine that we
noticed that very many joggers,
jog with only one earphone in.
That's a naturalistic observation, and
then in an interview, we might ask,
why do some of you jog
with only one earphone in?
And we might get the answer from
the interview that it's to listen for
cars or listen for
someone trying to get their attention
because they exercise in a busy area.
Now that we understand why they have
that behavior, maybe we develop a survey
to try and see how widespread that
behavior is, and ask, how many
of you need to worry about what's around
you when you're listening while driving?
If we notice in those surveys
a significant split in the number of
people who were concerned about that,
that might inform our next round
of naturalistic observation.
We might go out and look and see in what
environments are people only wearing
one headphone and in what
environments are they wearing both.
So in that way all of the different
kinds of need finding that we do
can inform our next round of
other kinds of need finding.
We can go through entire
cycles just of need finding
without ever going on to our design
alternatives or prototyping stages.
However, the prototyping and
evaluation that we do will then
become another input into this.
During our evaluation we might
discover things that will then inform
what we need to do next as far
as need finding is concerned.
Creating prototypes and evaluating
them gives us data on what works and
what doesn't.
And that might inform what we want to
observe to better understand the task
going forward.
That's the reason why the output
of evaluation is more needfinding.
It would be a mistake to do one
initial needfinding stage, and
then jump in to a back and forth
cycle of prototyping and evaluation.