In order to do some real need finding,
the first thing we need to do
is identify the problem space.
Where is the task occurring,
what else is going on, what are the
user's explicit and implicit needs?
We'll talk about some of the methods for
doing that in this lesson, but
before we get into those methods,
we want to understand the scope
of the space we're looking at.
So consider the difference
between these two actions.
[MUSIC]
Notice that in each of these, I'm doing
the same task, turning off the alarm.
But in the first scene we're focusing
very narrowly on the interaction between
the user and the interface.
In the latter,
we're taking into consideration
a broader view of the problem space.
We could zoom out even
further if we wanted to and
ask questions about Where and why people
need alarm systems in the first place.
That might lead us to designing
things like security systems for
dorm rooms or checking systems for
office buildings.
As we're going about need finding,
we want to make sure we're
taking the broad approach.
Understanding the entire problem
space in which we're interested,
not just focusing narrowly on the user's
interaction with a particular interface.
So in our exploration of methods for
need finding,
we're going to start with the most
authentic types of general observation,
then move through progressively more
targeted types of need finding.