Finally, the final step for need-finding
is to define our requirements.
These are the requirements that
our final interface must meet.
They should be specific and evaluatable,
and they can include some components
that are outside of users tasks,
as well,
as defined by the project requirements.
In terms of user tasks, we might have
requirements for guarding functionality,
what the interface can actually do,
usability, how certain user interactions
must work, learnability, how fast the
user can start to use the interface, and
accessibility, who can
use the interface.
We might also have some that
are generated by external project
requirements, like compatibility,
what devices the interface can run on,
compliance, how the interface
protects user privacy, cost,
how much the final tool can
actually cost, and so on.
We'll use these to evaluate the
interfaces we develop, going forward.