How might you need finding work in your chosen area of HCI?
If you're looking at designing for
some technological innovation like augmented or virtual interactions,
the initial phase might not actually be that different.
Your goal is to understand how people perform tasks right now without your interface.
So, initially, you want to observe them in their naturalistic environment.
Later though you'll need to start thinking about bringing
participants to you to experience the devices firsthand.
If you're interested in something like HCI for healthcare or education,
you have a wealth of naturalistic observations available to you.
You might even have existing interfaces doing what you want to do
and you can try to leverage those as part of your need-finding exercises.
Remember, no matter your area of application,
you want to start with real users that might be observing them in the wild,
talking to them directly,
or looking at data they've already generated.