Here are five quick tips for doing naturalistic observation.
Number one, take notes.
Don't just sit around watching for a while.
Be prepared to gather targeted information and observations about what you see.
Number two, start specific, and then abstract.
Right down the individual little actions you see people
doing before trying to interpret or summarize them.
If you jump to summarizing too soon,
you risk tunnel vision.
Number three, spread out your sessions.
Rather than sitting somewhere for two hours,
one day and then moving on,
try to observe in shorter 10 to 15 minute sessions several times.
You may find interesting different information,
and your growing understanding and reflection on
past exercises will inform your future sessions.
Number four, find the partner.
Observe together with someone else.
Take your own notes, and then compare them later.
So, you can see if you all interpreted the same scenarios or actions in the same way.
Number five, look for questions.
Naturalistic observation should inform the questions you decide to
ask participants in more targeted need-finding exercises.
You don't need to have all the answers based on observation alone.
What you need is questions to investigate further.