Sometimes it's not just enough to
watch people engaging in a task.
Sometimes we want to experience
a task for ourselves.
So that's what I'm going to do.
I listen to audiobooks a lot.
I don't really exercise.
I should, but I don't.
But I'm going to try this out.
So I've got my audiobook queued up,
I've got my mic on so
I can take notes as I run.
So I'm going to go on a jog and
see what I discover.
So what did I learn?
I learned that I'm out of shape for
one thing.
I already knew that but
I learned it again.
I also learned that this app
would be very useful for
anyone doing participant
observation on exercisers.
Because I kept having to stop
to record notes for myself,
which I could have done with this
app that I'm trying to implement.
But aside from that, I noticed that
unexpected things happen pretty often
that made me wish that I could
easily go back in my book.
Or sometimes there are just things
I just wanted to hear again, but
there was no easy way to do that.
I also notice that there's
definitely the need there for me.
I already planned to listen to
everything again now that I'm home
because there were notes I wanted to
take that I couldn't take easily.
I also noticed that while
sometimes I wanted to take notes,
sometimes I also just
want to leave a bookmark.
Now we do have to be
careful here though.
Remember you are not your user.
When you're working as a participant
observer, you can avail useful insights,
but you shouldn't over
represent your own experiences.
You should use this experience as
a participant observer to inform what
you ask users going forward