Let's zoom in a little bit more
on what the user actually does or
we can do naturalistic and participant
observation without having to directly
interact much with our users.
We need to get inside users heads
a little more to understand what they're
thinking and doing.
If you're trying to design interfaces
to make existing tasks easier,
one way to research that is to look at
the hacks that users presently employ.
How do they use interfaces in
non-intended ways to accomplish tasks or
how do they break out of the interface
to accomplish a task that could have
been accomplished with an interface?
If you're designing a task meant to
be performed at a desk like this,
looking at the person's workspace can
be a great way of accomplishing this.
So for example,
I have six monitors around.
And yet, you still see
Post-It notes on my computer.
How could I possibly need
more screen real estate?
Well, Post-It notes can't be covered up.
They don't take away from
the existing screen real estate.
They're visible even
when the computer is off.
So, this implicit notes here is the way
to hack around the limitations of
the computer interface.
Now when you're looking at hacks,
it's important to not just look at what
the user does and
assume you understand why.
Look at their work around and
ask them why they're using them.
Find out why they don't just use
the interface that's currently in place.
You might find they just
don't know about them,
which presents a different
kind of design challenge.
Now hacks are related to another method
we can use to uncover user needs as
well, which are called errors.
Whereas hacks are ways users get around
the interface to accomplish their tasks,
errors are slips or
mistakes that users frequently make
while performing the task
within the interface.