Here are five quick tips for doing well in this course.
Number one, look over the assignments early.
Some of our assignments, you can sit down and do them in an hour.
But others require some advanced coordination to talk to users,
develop prototypes, or test with real people.
So, go ahead and at least read all the assignment descriptions.
Number two, start the assignments early.
That's not just typical teacher talks saying,
"You can't get this done at the last minute."
You probably can. But you're using interfaces like these in your everyday life.
By starting early, you're likely to get inspiration just in your day-to-day routine,
and that's going to make writing the assignments significantly
easier than trying to sit down and come up with something on the spot.
Number three, participate.
Interact with your classmates.
Post on the forums, read others posts.
The knowledge and experience you gain there is just as
valuable as anything you'll get listening to me and these videos.
Number four, select an application area to explore.
Next lesson, you'll hear about several of
the interesting areas of HCI research and development going on right now.
Developing in many of these areas is outside the scope of this class.
But I encourage you to pick an area in which you're interested,
and mentally revisit it throughout the course.
Number five, leave behind what you know or at least try.
HCI is a huge area.
Yet, many people believe that because they're already good at using computers,
they'd be good at designing user experiences.
But HCI above all else is about gaining a grounded understanding of the user's needs,
not assuming we already understand them.
So, while it's great to apply the courses' principles to your everyday life,
be cautious about designing to narrowly based only on your own experiences.