In education,
a learning goal is something we want you
to understand at the end of the course.
It's the knowledge contained within your
head that you might not have had when we
got started.
In this class we have three
major learning goals.
First, we want you to understand
some of the common principles in
human computer interaction.
These are the tried and true rules on
how to design good interactions between
humans and computers.
Second, we want you to
understand design life cycle.
That's how interfaces go from
conception to prototypes to evaluation.
And we especially want you to understand
the roll of iteration in this process.
Third, we want you to understand the
expense of the human computer inherent
interaction field and the current
applications available for HCI.
HCI is really everywhere,
from domains like healthcare,
to technologies like virtual reality, to
emerging techniques like sonification.
We want you to understand the broad
range of application areas for
HCI in the modern world.