While learning goal is something we want
you to know at the end of the course,
a learning outcome is something
we want you to be able to do.
This course really has
one learning outcomes but
there are some nuances to it.
The learning outcome for
this course is to be able to design
effective interactions
between humans and computers.
The first part of this
learning outcome is to design.
But what is design?
Well for
us design is going to take two forms.
First, design is an activity where
you're appl known principles
to a new problem.
For example we'll talk a lot about
the importance of getting users to write
kind of feedback at the right time.
That's a plan of principle of feedback
to some new design problem ww encounter.
But design is a second form as well,
design is also a process where
you gather information,
use it to develop design alternatives,
evaluate them with users and
revise them accordingly.
When designing interface for some tasks,
I would ask some potential users how
they perform some task right now.
I develop multiple different ideas for
how we can help them.
I give those to the users to evaluate,
and
I will use the experiences to try to
improve the interface on that time.
So let's take an example of this.
Imagine I was designing
a new thermostat.
On the one hand, designing a new
thermostat means applying known
HCR principles, like feedback and
error tolerance to some new design.
On the other hand, designing
a new thermostat means creating
different ideas, giving them to users,
getting their feedback and
then revising those designs.
Both these sides of design
are very important.
You don't want to ignore
decades of experience when designing new
interfaces, but simply applying known
principles to a new problem doesn't
guarantee you have a good design.
Designing is about both these things.
And in fact, these two things are a vast
majority of material that we'll cover in
this course.
We'll cover the principles uncovered
by a human factors engineering and
human computer interaction research.
And we'll cover the methods
used in the HCI.
We're gathering user requirements,
developing designs, and
evaluating new interfaces.