Learning strategies are how we plan to
actually impart that knowledge to you.
This is how we attempt to help you
achieve the learning goals and
learning outcomes.
Within these videos, we'll use a number
of different strategies to try to help
you understand the core principles and
methodologies of HCI.
We'll use learning by example.
Every lesson and, in fact,
this course, as a whole.
Is organized around a collection of
running examples that will come up
over and over again.
We use learning by doing.
Throughout the course we'll ask you to
engage in designing interactions to
solve different problems
in different contexts.
These aren't required,
since there's really no way we can
verify if you've done them, but
we really hope you'll take a few
minutes and think about these.
We'll also use learning
by reflection a lot.
We'll ask yo to reflect on times when
you've encountered these things in your
own every day life.
These strategies are useful because they
connect to your own personal experiences
but once again, there's a danger here.
One of the recurrent
points in HCI is that
when you are designing interactions,
you are not your own user.
Focusing too much on your own
experiences can give you a false sense
of expertise.
So I'll use some strategies to help
take you out of that comfort zone and
confront how little you might understand
these tasks with which you thought you
were so familiar.