[MUSIC]
So we've talked to our users.
We've gathered some
understanding of what they need.
We've created some ideas for
how we might address their need and
we've mentally simulated
those different alternatives.
Now it's time to start actually making
things we can put in front of users.
[SOUND] This is the prototyping stage.
Like brainstorming design alternatives,
this involves looking at the different
ideas available to us and
developing them a bit.
But the major distinction
is that in prototyping,
we want to actually build things
we can put in front of users.
But that doesn't mean building
the entire interface before we
ever even have a user look at it.
We want to get user feedback as
quickly and rapidly as possible.
And build up more sophisticated
prototypes over time
as we go through the design life cycle.
So we'll start with low fidelity
prototypes, things that can be assembled
and revised very quickly for
rapid feedback from users.
Then we'll work our way towards higher
fidelity prototypes, like wire frames or
working versions of our interface.