If you're working in an application area that relies
on traditional screens and input methods,
your prototyping process might be pretty straightforward.
It'll go from paper prototypes to wireframes
exploring iteratively more complete versions of the final interface.
For a lot of emerging domains though,
you'll have to get somewhat creative with your prototyping.
For things like gestural or voice interaction,
you can likely use Wizard of Oz prototyping by having a human
interpret the actions or commands that will ultimately be interpreted by the computer.
For augmented reality or wearable devices though,
you might have to get even more creative.
So take a second and brainstorm how you might go about prototyping in your chosen field.
Remember, your goal is to get feedback on your ideas from the user early.
What can you create that will get you that feedback?