In this lesson, we've talked about several methods for prototyping.
Our goal is to employ a lot of methods to get
feedback rapidly,and iterate quickly on our designs.
Through that process, we can work our way toward creating our ultimate interface.
The main goal of this prototyping process has been to
create designs we can evaluate with real users.
We're obviously not going to deploy a hand-drawn interface to real customers.
Its value is in its ability to get us feedback.
That's what the entire design life cycle has been leading towards: evaluation,
evaluating our ideas, evaluating our prototypes, evaluating our designs.
That user evaluation is the key to user-centered design.
Focusing on user evaluation ensures that
our focus is always on the user's needs and experiences.
So, now that we've researched users needs,
brainstorm some design alternatives,
and create some shareable prototypes,
let's move on to actual evaluation.