To discuss prototyping there
are a variety of different terms and
concepts we need to understand.
For the most part, these will apply to
where in the prototyping timeline those
concepts are used.
In the early prototyping,
we're doing a very rapid
revision on preliminary ideas.
This happens on our first few iterations
through the design lifecycle.
In late prototyping, we're putting the
finishing touches on the final design,
or revising a design
that's already live.
This happens when we've already
been through several iterations
of our design lifecycle.
At the various phases,
we'll generally use different types
of prototypes in evaluations.
Now, note that everything I'm
about to say is pretty general,
there will be lots of exceptions.
The first concept is representation,
what is the prototype?
Early on, we might be fine with
just some textural descriptions or
some simple visuals that we've
written up on a piece of paper.
Later on though, we'll want to
make things more visual and
maybe even more interactive.
We only want to put the work into
developing the more complex type of
prototypes once we vetted the ideas with
prototypes that are easier to build.
So in a lot of ways,
this is a spectrum of how easy
prototypes are to build over time.
A verbal prototype is literally
just a description, and
I can change my description on the fly.
A paper prototype is drawn on paper, and
similarly, I could ball up the paper,
throw it away, and
draw a new version pretty quickly.
But things like actual functional
prototypes that really work,
those take a good bit of time.
And so we only want to do those once
we've already vetted that the ideas that
we're going to build
actually have some value.
You don't want to sink
lots of months and
lots of engineering resources into
building something that actually works.
Only to find out there's some feedback
you could have gotten just based
on a drawing on a piece of paper
that would have told you that your
idea wasn't a very good one.
This brings us to our second concept,
which is fidelity.
Fidelity refers to the completeness or
the maturity of the prototype.
A low-fidelity prototype would be
something like paper or simple drawings,
very easy to change.
A high-fidelity prototype would be
something like a wireframe or an actual
functional working interface, something
that was harder to put together.
We want to move from easily changeable
low-fidelity prototypes to explore our
ideas, to higher-fidelity
prototypes to really test them out.
Note that fidelity and representation
are pretty closely related,
low-fidelity is really about a prototype
that's pretty far from being complete.
And the same thing is true for some
of our early methods of prototyping.
They describe different ideas, but
they very heavily correlate what kinds
of representations you're going to
use for different levels of fidelity.
Now these different kinds of prototypes
also lend themselves to different kinds
of evaluation structures.
Low fidelity prototypes can fine for
evaluating the relative
function of an interface, whether or not
it can do what's it's designed to do.
If a user looks at the interface
can they figure out what they're
supposed to press?
You can prototype that was just
a drawing on a piece of paper,
as opposed to a real
functional prototype.
Things like wireframes can be
useful in evaluating the relative
readability of the interface as well.
However, to evaluate actual performance,
like how long certain tasks take, or
what design leads to more purchases.
We generally need a higher
fidelity prototype,
through more iterations
of the design lifecycle.
So early on,
we're really just evaluating whether or
not our prototype even has the potential
to do what we want it to do.
Can a user physically use it?
Can they identify what
button to press and when?
For that we need additional detail
like font size and real screen layout.
We need a real prototype that looks
the way the final interface will look,
even if it doesn't work quite yet.
And then, to evaluate performance we
really need a prototype that's working,
or close to working,
to evaluate certain tasks.
And then the final concept
we need to understand,
is the scope of the interface.
Is it a horizontal prototype or
a vertical prototype?
Horizontal prototypes cover the design
as a whole, but in a more shallow way.
Vertical prototypes take a small
portion of the interaction and
prototype it in great detail.
So for example, if we were designing
Facebook, we might have a vertical
prototype specifically for
the status-posting screen and
a horizontal prototype for
the site in general.
Now, in my experience, we usually start
with horizontal prototypes earlier on,
and move toward the deeper
vertical prototype later.
But in reality, you'll likely move
back and forth among these more
frequently throughout you iterations
through the design lifecycle.
So, these are four the main
concepts behind prototyping.
There are other questions we
might ask ourselves as well.
Like whether we're prototyping
iterative or revolutionary changes, and
the extent to which the prototype
needs to be executable.
But in many ways, those fall
under these previous concepts.