Paper prototyping is great when we're designing flat interfaces for screens,
but what if you're designing a voice interface or a gesture interface?
How do you prototype that?
One way is called the Wizard of Oz prototyping.
Wizard of Oz prototyping is named as a reference to
the famous scene from the classic movie by the same name.
Pay no attention to that man behind the curtain.
The idea here is that we, behind the curtain,
do the things that the interface would do once it's actually implemented.
That way, we can test out the interactions that we plan
to design and see how well they'll work.
So, I have Morgan and we're going to do a Wizard of Oz prototype for
an interface to allow exercisers to consume and take notes on audio books.
So, I'll start by briefly telling her how the interface would work.
So, this interface is run by voice commands,
I'll simulate it on my phone,
and you'll say play to play the book,
pause to pause the book.
You'll say note to enter a note-taking viewer,
it will transcribe what you say,
and bookmark to just drop a bookmark wherever you are but without pausing.
So, whenever you're ready.
Let's do it.
All wealth consists of desirable things,
Pause.
That is things with,
Play, Which satisfy human wants directly or indirectly,
Bookmark, But not all desirable things are recognized as wealth. The affection,
Note.
Of friends for in,
This book is so good.
Oh, I just realized actually,
I guess I need a way for you to stop the note when you're done.
So, say close note when you're done taking note.
Close note.
All right, you can stop. Now, based on this prototype,
I can also ask for some feedback.
So, Morgan, do you think it should automatically start playing again
when you stop that bookmark or should it, what should it do?
Well, okay. So, I think I'd actually like to start playing from five seconds
back because I imagine saying note is going to step over some of the content.
Yeah, that makes sense and we can go through this and quickly
test out different ideas for how the interaction might work.
In practice, Wizard of Oz Prototypes can actually get very complex.
You can have entire programs that work by having
a person supply the requested input at the right time.
But as a concept,
a Wizard of Oz Prototype is a prototype where the user can now interact
authentically with the system while
a human supplies functionality that hasn't yet been implemented.