Paper prototyping involve drawing things simply on paper,
and it can be really good for experimenting with overall layouts,
especially because it tends to be a lot easier
to revise and tweak those pretty naturally.
After some feedback though,
you'll likely want to start formalizing your designs a little bit more.
One way of doing this would be called wireframing.
In wireframing, we use
some more detailed tools to mark up what an interface might look like.
For example, my paper prototype from earlier might become a wireframe like this.
This lets us experiment with some additional details like font size,
colors, and the challenges of screen real estate.
Now, there are lots of tools out there for wireframing that
come equipped with built-in common widgets and layouts.
But you can also do some rudimentary wireframing in something as simple as PowerPoint.
Google Drawings can be used the same way as well.
So, you don't need to get super fancy.
Although if you do a lot of wireframing,
you're probably want to find a more streamlined tool.
Some of the more popular paid products include Balsamiq and Axure.
These are both targeted more at professionals
working in user interface or user experience design,
especially on teams and collaborating with a lot of people.
If you're familiar with the suites of tools from either Microsoft or Adobe,
then Visio or InDesign might also be great options for you to use,
because you're already somewhat familiar with those interfaces.
But you don't actually have to buy a tool to do good wireframing.
There exists some free to use tools out there as well,
like the pencil project and frame box.
Those are great to use, especially if you're just getting started.
Of course., these are just the popular ones that I know about right now.
There are almost certainly more out there that I'm not familiar with,
and more will surely come available.
So, check with your classmates or colleagues to see what they would recommend.
I'm personally really excited to see what kind of prototyping options
emerge for areas like virtual reality and augmented reality,
where you can't really prototype on a 2D canvas like this.