Wire-framing is great for prototyping onscreen interfaces but,
again, what if you're working on something more physical or 3-dimensional?
In that case, you might want to construct a physical prototype,
but let's be clear, it doesn't have to actually work.
That's where a lot of designers get tripped up.
They think to get good feedback on
a design they have to have a working version, but you don't.
There are lots of elements you can test without actually implementing anything.
So, let's go back to our example of designing
a way for exercisers to take notes on audio books.
One of my alternatives might be a Bluetooth device that synchronizes with the phone,
with buttons for different interactions.
The individual will hold this while exercising and interact
by pressing different buttons for play or pause or take a note.
I've prototyped this just by taking my car's key fob.
We could just say that we pretend this button does this and that button does this.
It's probably not the exact shape I want but it's pretty close.
It's probably about the same size and I can test
the general idea of pressing buttons while exercising with this.
I can actually do a lot of testing with this I can tell Morgan how it works,
and watch carefully to see if the button she presses are
the right ones to evaluate the intuitiveness of the interface.
Or I could just ask her to go running while holding it and give me feedback on whether or
not holding something physical like this in her hand throws off her routine at all.
I can do a lot of prototyping without a working version