If you solved it,
well done on figuring it out despite
such a terrible representation.
Or congratulations on
recognizing by analogy,
that it's the same as a problem
you've seen in another class.
If you skipped it, I don't blame you.
It's not an easy problem.
But it's even harder when
the representation is so poor.
There were lots of weaknesses
in that representation.
Let's step through how
we would improve it.
The first thing we could do is
simply write the problem out.
Audio is a poor representation
of complex problems.
So here's a written
representation of the problem.
If the trouble you were having solving
the exercise was just remembering
all the rules, having this written
down would be a huge help.
But we can still do
a lot better than this.
Instead, we can represent
the problem visually.
Here we have the shapes,
the three circles and the three squares.
And we can imagine actually
moving them back and forth.
That arrow in the center, represents
the direction of the next move.
But we can still do better.
Right now we have to work to compare
the number of squares and circles, so
let's line them up.
This makes it very easy to compare and
make sure that the circles
always outnumber the squares.
And we can still do
the same manipulation,
moving them back and forth.
Now the only remaining problem is that
we have to keep in working memory,
the rule that squares may
not outnumber circles.
There is no natural reason why
need more squares than circles,
it's just kind of an arbitrary rule.
So let's make it more self evident.
Let's make the squares wolves,
and the circles sheep.
As long as the sheep
outnumber the wolves,
the sheep can defend themselves,
kind of.
But if the wolves ever outnumber
the sheep, they'll eat them.
But if there are no sheep, then there's
nothing for the wolves to eat, so
that's okay.
So now we have a new
representation of the problem,
one that will make the problem
much easier to solve.
The rules are more obvious, and
it's easier to evaluate whether or
not they're being met.
Finally, we can make this visualization
even a little bit more useful,
by actually showing the movements
between different states.
That way we can see that for
any state in the problem,
there's a finite number
of next legal states.
This would also allow us to notice
when we've accidentally revisited
an earlier state, so
we can avoid going around in circles.
So for example, from this state,
we might choose to move the wolf and
the sheep back to the left, but
we'll immediately notice that would
make the state the same as this one.
And it's not useful to backtrack and
revisit an earlier state.
So we know not to do that.
So these representations have made it
much easier to solve this problem,
than just the verbal
representation we started with.