What are the characteristics
of a good representation?
First, good representations
make relationships explicit.
Laying things out like this makes it
easy to tell that there are more sheep
than wolves.
Second, good representations bring
objects and relationships together.
Representing these as wolves and sheep,
makes that relationship that the sheep
must out number the wolves much more
salient than using squares and circles.
That brings the objects together
with the relationships between them.
Third, a good representation
excludes extraneous details.
For example,
sometimes this problem is described in
the form of having a river and a boat.
But those details aren't actually
relevant to solving the problem at all.
So, we've left them out of here.
All we need to know is they need to
move from the left to the right.
Doesn't matter if it's a river,
doesn't matter if it's a boat, this
is all the information that we need.
So we left out
the extraneous information.
Fourth, good representations
expose natural constraints.
We describe these as sheep and wolves
because it makes it easier to think
about the rule that wolves
may never out number sheep.
Now of course, this isn't the best
rule because we know that sheep
can't actually defend
themselves against wolves.
Three sheep and one wolf,
the wolf would still win.
However, if we visualize these
as guards and prisoners instead,
it involves holding and
working memory the idea that
prisoners inexplicably won't flee
if they're left without any guards.
So personally, I think the wolves and
sheep metaphor is better.
But perhaps the original name
of the problem is even better.
This was originally described as
the cannibals and missionaries problem.
It makes more sense that a missionary
could defend themselves against
a cannibal than a sheep could
defend themselves against a wolf.
But the cannibals and missionaries
problem makes it a little bit dark.
So let's stick with sheep and wolves.