There are a number of
things we can do here.
The simplest change we could make
would simply be to make the breakers
themselves writable.
Instead of writing a list on the left
that we have to then map up to
the breakers themselves on the right,
we could just write on each
breaker what it controls.
That way we just have to look at the
breakers themselves to find the breaker
that we're interested in.
But then they still have to
manually scan through all of them.
We could further augment this by having
a floor plan over here that actually
gives the numbers on the floor plan for
the breaker we want.
So all I have to do is jump straight
to the room that I'm interested in,
find the number,
go over the the list of breakers, and
the label written on it would then
confirm that I chose the right one.
Now, if we wanted to get really crazy
we could actually lay out the breakers
themselves to correspond
to the floor plan.
We can have a floor plan and
actually put the breakers on
the floors that they control.
Or we could even just put
the breakers in the rooms themselves.
So if the power goes
out to a certain room,
I just go find the breaker in that room.
But there we're starting to run into
some of the other constraints on
the problems.
So it's probably best to stick to what
we can control, without requiring
that the physical device be manufactured
differently in the first place.