Analogies and metaphors are powerful tools for helping users understand your interface.
If you can ground your interface in something they already know,
you can get a solid foundation in teaching them how to use your interface.
For example, The Wall Street Journal's website heavily
leverages an analogy to The Wall Street Journal print edition.
The headlines, the grids,
the text all appear pretty similarly,
so someone familiar with the print edition could
pretty easily understand the online edition.
If you've ever tried to explain a tool that you use to someone who's never seen it,
you've probably encountered something like this.
For example, both at Udacity and in the Georgia Tech OMSCS program,
we use Slack for communicating with each other.
If you've never actually seen Slack,
it's a chat app for organizations to talk in
different public and private rooms but listen to what I just said.
It's a chat app.
In my description, I leveraged the analogy to something you've already seen.
Now Slack is a pretty easy example because it is a chat app.
It's barely even an analogy to say it's like a chat app because it is a chat app.
It's a very full featured chat app with a lot of
integrations and things like that but it's fundamentally a chat app.
What about something harder? How about Medium?
Medium is a writing platform that's kind of like
a blogging service but also kind of like
a publishing service but also kind of like a news feed.
You write articles kind of like WordPress blog posts but you can publish them through
organizations which is kind of like
traditional newspapers or news aggregators like the Huffington Post.
My articles for example are published through Udacity.
So, it's not just like a blog because it's not just my personal blog.
There is a publisher element to it but
the actual content is very similar to a blog-like platform.
Articles are then published to interested people more like a news feed.
So if I scroll down,
I'll see the articles that Medium thinks I would be interested in
reading and in that way it's more like Facebook or Twitter.
So, notice that my entire explanation of Medium was
based on analogies to other services like WordPress,
Huffington Post, and Facebook.
But analogies and metaphors have a downside.
When you choose to use them,
users don't know where the analogy ends.
When I describe Medium's news feed is kind of like Facebook or kind of like Twitter,
users might wonder where the retweet or share options are.
Or when I describe it like a blog platform like WordPress,
people might wonder where the comments are and it doesn't
really supply comments in the way that we're used to.
So, while analogies are powerful ways to help users understand our interfaces,
we also need to pay special attention to what misconceptions they might introduce.