One of the challenges encountered by every new technology,
is helping the user understand how to use it.
Smart phone maybe pretty ubiquitous by now,
but we're still figuring out some elements of how to best use these things.
Typing efficiency on a touch screen for example
still hasn't caught up to efficiency with a full keyboard.
But that's because typing on a phone was also
a pretty straightforward transition from a regular keyboard,
because the on-screen keyboard was designed just as an analogy to the real one.
There are probably more efficient ways to enter text into a phone but it wouldn't be
as easily learnable as this straightforward analogy to a physical keyboard.
This illustrates both the positive and negative sides of using analogies in designs.
Analogies make the interface more learnable but they also may
restrict the interface to outdated requirements or constraints.
So, take a moment and think about how this applies to your chosen area of HCI.
If you're looking at things like gestural interfaces or touch-based interfaces,
what analogies can you draw to other interfaces to make your designs more learnable.
And at the same time, what do you risk by using those analogies?