In designing interfaces, we want to
leverage analogies to the real world,
and principles from past
interfaces whenever possible,
to help the user learn the new
interface as quickly as they can.
But there's a challenge here.
Why are we designing technology if
we're not providing users anything new?
It's one thing to take the technology
they're already using, and
make it more usable.
But generally, we also want to enable
people to do things they've never
done before.
That means there are no analogies, no
expectations, no prior experiences for
them leverage.
How do you tell someone that's used
to control their own thermostat that
they don't need to anymore.
So, while we need to leverage analogy
and prior experience wherever possible.
We also need to be
aware that eventually,
we're going to do something interesting,
and they're going to break down.
Eventually, we're going to have to teach
the user to use the unique elements of
our interface.