Every interface requires the user to do some learning to understand how to use it.
Very often, we visualize this as a learning curve.
A learning curve plots expertise against experience.
Generally, as the user gains more experience,
they also gained more expertise.
Here, our user starts with no experience at all,
and so they also have no expertise at all.
Our goal is for them to end with an expertise above this line of proficiency.
However, the shape and steepness of this curve can vary.
Ideally, we want a learning curve that grows quickly with relatively little experience.
This is actually what we call a steep learning curve,
although usually when you hear steep learning curve,
it means the exact opposite.
Technically, steep is good because steep means we're
increasing very quickly with relatively little experience.
People often use steep to mean the opposite,
and that's because steep calls to mind connotations of a high difficulty level,
like climbing a steep mountain.
So, steep is actually a poor representation of this concept.
So, instead, lets for us call this a rapid learning curve,
which means that expertise grows very quickly with relatively little experience.
Rapid calls to mind probably the proper
connotations that a rapid learning curve is rapid learning,
which is probably something we want.
Interfaces that are more difficult to use would have slower learning curves.
Here, the user needs a lot more experience to reach the same level of proficiency.
So, how do we help our user reach proficiency faster?
For one, if we're consistent with
existing conventions and use analogies that users understand,
we can actually start them off with effectively some initial expertise.
For example, when you download a new smartphone app,
you know that the three horizontal lines that often appear
in the top right likely indicate a menu.
That's a consistent convention used across multiple apps.
So, using it means that when users open your app,
they already have some expertise.
From there, we want to make the ascension as rapid as possible.
One way we can do that is by using representations and affordances
that help the user immediately understand how to use the interface.
So, good design is in part about helping
users achieve proficiency as quickly as possible,
either through starting them off with some initial expertise or helping
them grow in their expertise with as little experience as possible.