A mental model is a person's
understanding of the way something in
the real world works.
It's an understanding of the processes,
relationships and
connections in real systems.
Using mental models we generate
expectations or predictions about
the world and then we check whether the
actual outcomes match our mental model.
So I'm holding this basketball
because generally, we
all probably have a model of what will
happen if I try to bounce this ball.
[SOUND] It comes back up.
[SOUND] You didn't have to see it
come up to know what would happen.
You use your mental model of
the world to simulate the event.
And then you use that mental
simulation to make predictions.
When reality doesn't match with our
mental model, it makes us uncomfortable.
We want to know why our
mental model was wrong.
Maybe it makes us curious.
But when it happens over and
over, it can frustrate us.
It can make us feel that we just
don't and never will understand.
As interface designers, this presents
us with a lot of challenges.
We want to make sure that the users
mental model in our systems matches
the way our systems actually work.
We can do that in two primary ways,
one by designing systems that act the
way people already expect them to act.
And two, by designing systems that,
by their very nature,
teach people how they'll act.
That way we can minimize the discomfort
that comes from systems acting ways that
users don't expect.