As we design interfaces,
we will no doubt encounter instances where the user makes mistakes.
Sometimes this might be because our users are stressed or distracted,
but other times it might be because our users fundamentally don't
understand our interfaces or even don't understand their own goals.
As designers though, we know there's really no such thing as user error.
Any user error is a failure of
the interface to properly guide the user to the right action.
In designing interfaces, there are
two kinds of user error that we're interested in avoiding.
The first are called slips.
Slips occur when the user has the right mental model,
but does the wrong thing anyway.
Take this box for example,
prompting a user closing a program on whether they'd like to save their work.
In all likelihood, the user knows exactly what they want to do,
and typically, it's going to be to actually save their work.
If you ask them to explain what they should do,
they would say, "Click Yes."
But imagine if the order of these buttons was flipped
so that the No was on the left and Yes was on the right.
A user might click on the left just because they used to seeing Yes on the left,
even though they know they really want to click Yes.
Or imagine that No is selected by default.
So that if a user just presses enter when this dialog comes up,
it automatically says No.
In that case also,
they knew that they wanted to save their work,
but what they did didn't match the goal they wanted to accomplish.
A mistake on the other hand,
happens when the user has the wrong mental model and does the wrong thing as a result.
Take this prompt for example.
The users asked if they want to revert to the original file.
That's really just a backwards way of asking whether they want to save,
but this is foreign terminology to many users.
Their mental model of what saving is
doesn't tell him necessarily what to do in this instance.
What's more, they don't actually have a choice here.
Without a cancel button,
they're forced to choose knowing one option could mean losing their changes.
Here the problem is a mismatch between
their internal model and the way the system is working,
or at least the way it describes itself.
So, slip occurs when the user knows
the right thing to do but does the wrong thing anyway,
but a mistake occurs when the user doesn't even know the right thing to do.