Norman also divides mistakes in
the multiple categories, in this case,
three categories.
Rule based mistakes, knowledge base
mistakes and memory lapse mistakes.
Rule based mistakes occur where
the user correctly assesses the state
of the world but
makes the wrong decision based on it.
Knowledge based mistakes occur where the
user incorrectly assesses the state of
the world in the first place.
Memory lapse mistakes are similar
to memory lapse slips, but
this focuses on forgetting
to fully execute a plan
not just forgetting to do
something in the first place.
If the user clicks the wrong
button in this dialog,
it could be do to multiple
different kinds of mistakes.
Maybe they correctly knew they
wanted to save their changes but
they didn't realize that clicking
no is actually what would save,
that would be a rule-based mistake.
They knew they wanted to save,
but they made the wrong decision
based on that knowledge.
Or perhaps they didn't even realize
they wanted to save in the first place.
Maybe they didn't think they made any
changes, when in actuality they did.
That would be a knowledge based mistake.
They applied the right rule
based on their knowledge but
their knowledge was inaccurate.
If they were to shut down their computer
and never come back and answer this
dialogue in the first place, that might
be considered a memory lapse mistake.
They didn't fully execute the plan
of closing down the application.
So in our designs,
we want to do everything we can
to prevent all these
different kinds of errors.
We want to help prevent routine errors
by leveraging consistent practices
like designing dialogues
the way users are used to.
We also want to let our interface off
load some of the demands on working
memory from the user to the computer
to avoid memory lapse errors.
And we want the leverage good
representations to help users develop
the right mental of models to
minimize these rule-based and
knowledge-based errors.
And while errors are inevitable,
we should make sure to leverage
the tolerance principle to make sure
the repercussions can never be too bad.