I would argue this is a slip.
Morgan knows who she
means to message but
the phone's behavior tricks her into
sending things to the wrong people.
What's more, this might be either an
action based slip or memory lapse slip.
Maybe Morgan is tapping
the wrong person,
or maybe she's forgetting to
check who she's messaging.
So take a second and brainstorm a design
for this that can prevent this from
happening in the future without over
complicating the interaction too much.
I would argue that the best way
to do this is simply to show
more pervasive reminders of who
Morgan is currently texting.
We could show the recipient's picture
on the send button, for example.
That way,
the interaction is no more complex, but
Morgan also has to directly acknowledge
who she's messaging to send a message.