Just like mental models, learned
helplessness is also a topic related as
much to education as it is to HCI.
If you've ever spent any
time in a teaching role,
you very likely encountered students
that are very resistant to being taught.
And the reason is they have learned
that no matter what they do,
they never succeed.
They've learned to be helpless
based on their past experiences.
In all likelihood, there have
actually been situations where
you've been the one learning
that you're helpless.
In fact, if you're a parent,
I can almost guarantee you've
been in that situation.
There are times when your child
was crying and inconsolable and
you had no clue why.
We had one of those right
before we filmed this video.
Nothing you did helped.
And you learned that you were helpless
to figure out what your child wanted.
So if you're a parent and
you're dealing with learned
helplessness as an interface designer,
just imagine that you are the user and
the interface is your screaming child.
What feedback would
you need from your child to
figure out how you can help them?
And how can you build that kind
of feedback into your interface?
>> [SOUND]