Generally, when we're
developing interfaces,
we're going to be experts
in those domains.
It's rare that you design an interface
to help people do something that you
yourself don't know how to do.
But as a result, there's risk for
something called expert blind spot.
When you're an expert in something,
there are parts of the task that you do
subconsciously without even
really thinking about them.
For example, a professional basketball
player knows exactly where to place
their hands on the ball
when taking a shot.
I know exactly what to do
when I walk in the studio.
Amanda knows exactly what to do
when she gets behind the camera.
And yet, if we were suddenly
asked to train someone else,
there are lots of things
we'd forget to say or
lots of things we would
assume would just be obvious.
That's exactly what you're doing
when you're designing an interface.
You're teaching the user how
to use what you've designed.
You're teaching them without the benefit
of actually talking to them,
explaining things to them, or
demonstrating things for them.
You're teaching them through
the design of the interface.
So, you have to make sure that you don't
assume that they're an expert too.
You have to overcome that expert blind
spot because we are not our users.
We are not the user.
That can be the motto of all of HCI.
I am not my user.
Say it with me, I am not my user.
One more time, I am not my user.
Now type it.