Mental models are not
a uniquely HCI principle.
In fact, if you search for mental models
online, you'll probably find just as
much about them in the context of
education, as the context of HCI.
And that's actually a very
useful analogy to keep in mind.
When you're designing an interfce
you're playing, very much,
the role of an educator.
Your goal is to teach your
user how the system works
through the design of your interface.
But unlike a teacher,
you don't generally have the benefit of
being able to stand here and
explain things directly to your user.
Most users don't watch tutorials or
read documentation or if they do,
they don't want to.
You have to design interfaces that
teach users while they're using them.
That's where representations come in.
Good representations show the user
exactly how the system actually works.
It's an enormous challenge, but
it's also incredibly satisfying
when you do it well.