So let's talk a little bit about mental
models in the context of the climate
control systems we see on automobiles.
So this is my old car,
it's a 1989 Volvo.
It, sadly, does not run anymore.
But let's talk about how the climate
control system would work back when
it did run.
So, it's a hot day outside.
Looking at these controls, how would
you make the air temperature colder and
the air come out faster?
The natural thought to me would be to
turn the fan speed up over on the right,
and the air temperature to
the blue side over on the left.
But this doesn't actually make
the temperature any colder,
it just disables the heat.
This dial over here in the top right,
has to be turned on to make the air
conditioning actually work.
So just turning this thing over to
the blue side doesn't actually turn on
the air conditioning.
So to make it colder, you have to both
slide this lever over to the left, and
turn this dial to the red area.
It's kind of hard to see in this, but
this little area over here on the left
side of this dial is actually red.
The red area on the air conditioning
control designates the maximum coldness.
What?
This also means you can turn on both
the heat and the air conditioning at
the same time and have neither of them
blowing out if your fan is turned off.
None of these really match my mental
model of how this system works and
the colors used here do nothing
to correct my mental model.
There's a control here
that if you turn it to blue
doesn't make the car any colder.
And if you turn this other control
to red, it does make the car colder.
What?
So back in 1989,
there was a lot of room for
improvement on designing the climate
control system for a car like this.
Let's see if we actually did improve
that by talking about my new car,
which is a 2015 Nissan Leaf.
So in the 26 years since my old Volvo
came out, have we gotten better at this?
Well yeah,
we've gotten a good bit better,
although there's still a good
bit of room for improvement.
So, here's the climate
control system from my Leaf.
I have one dial,
that turns the fan speed up and down.
One dial that turns the temperature
of the air coming out up and down.
And so as far as that's concerned,
it's pretty simple.
But this interface still has some
things that are pretty confusing.
So for example,
it has an automatic mode,
where it tries to adjust the air
temperature and the fan speed to bring
the temperature of the car to
the temperature that I want.
So I press auto.
Now it's going to change the fan speed,
and change the air temperature, if
I didn't already have it at the lowest,
to try and get the car cooler faster.
The problem is that I want to turn auto
off, I don't actually know how to do it.
Pressing auto doesn't
actually turn it off.
If I turn it so
that it doesn't only circulate air
inside the car, then it turns auto off.
But that might not be what I wanted.
Maybe I wanted it to go to
a certain air temperature without
just circulating the air in the car.
I turn auto back on,
it's going to turn that back on.
Don't know why.
So right now, as far as I know,
the only way to turn auto off is
to turn the circulation mode off.
It also lets me turn AC and
heat on at the same time,
which I don't understand at all.
Why would I ever need that?
So there are some things that
the system really should do better, or
some things that it should constrain so
the user doesn't do things
that don't make sense in the context
of wanting to set the temperature.