Matching our interface design to users' mental models is
a valuable way to create interfaces that are easily learnable by users.
Here are five tips or, in this case,
principles to leverage for creating learnable interfaces.
These principles of learnability were proposed by Dix, Finlay,
Abowd, and Beale in their book, Human-Computer Interaction.
Number one, predictability. Look at an action.
Can the user predict what will happen?
For example, graying out a button is a good way to help
the user predict that clicking that button will do nothing.
Number two, synthesizability.
Not only should the user be able to predict
the effects of an action before they perform it,
they should also be able to see the sequence of actions that led to their current state.
That can be difficult in graphical user interfaces but something
like the log of actions that they can see in the undo menu can make it easier.
Command line interfaces are actually really good at this.
They give a log of the commands that have been given in order.
Number three, familiarity.
This is similar to Norman's principle of affordances.
The interface should leverage actions with which the user
is already familiar from real-world experience.
For example, if you're trying to indicate something is either good or bad,
you'd likely want to use red and green instead of blue and yellow.
Number four, generalizability.
Similar to familiarity in the Norman's principles of consistency,
knowledge of one user interface should generalize to others.
If your interfaces tasks that are similar to other interfaces tasks,
like saving and copying and pasting,
it should perform those tasks in the same way.
Number five, consistency.
This is slightly different than Norman's principle of consistency.
This means it's similar tasks or operations
within a single interface should behave the same way.
For example, you wouldn't want to have ctrl x cut some texts if texts are selected,
but close the application if there is no text selected.
The behavior of that action should be consistent across the interface.
Using these principles can help the user leverage their existing mental models of
other designs as well as develop a mental model of your interface as quickly as possible.