The most powerful tool in our arsenal to
help ensure users have effective mental
models of our systems is representation.
We get to choose how things
are visualized to users, and so
we get to choose some of how
their mental model develops.
Using good representations can make all
the difference between effective and
ineffective mental models.
So to take an example, let's look at
some instructions for assembling things.
So here are the instructions for
a cat tree that I recently put together.
At first, I actually thought this
was a pretty good representation.
You can kind of see how things fit
together from the bottom to the top.
The problem is that this representation
doesn't actually map the physical
construction of the cat tree itself.
You can even see some bizarre mismatches
even within this representation.
Up here, it looks like this
pillar is in the front, but
the screw hole that goes into it
is actually shown in the back.
But we're not looking up into
the bottom of that piece,
because in the middle piece,
they actually map up pretty well.
At least with the way
they're shown here.
Again, that isn't the way
the actual piece works.
So anyway, the point is,
this is a poor representation for
the way this furniture actually worked,
because it wasn't a real mapping between
this representation and the real pieces.
Lately I also put together
some office furniture, and
that actually had a very
good representation.
These are two of the steps from a hutch
I put together to go over my desk.
For the piece on the left, there was
a perfect mapping between the way this
piece worked and the way the screw holes
were actually aligned on the piece.
One clever thing they did is
they actually showed this little
screw hole right here that
isn't used for this step.
That helped me understand the mapping
between this piece and my piece.
And understand that when I saw that
screw hole that didn't have a screw for
it, that was okay.
It would be natural to
think we only need to show
what users actually need to do.
But including that screw hole
helps users understand the mapping
between this representation and
the actual piece.
This more complicated step over on
the right actually ended up being pretty
intuitive as well.
Although it's small and
the details hard to see, the arrows they
put along here made it pretty easy to
see the direction you had to move things
in order to put these pieces together.
That's especially useful
in places like up here,
where the screw hole actually
isn't visible in this diagram.
But I can see that there is a screw hole
here because of the way they represented
this screw going into that hole.
I can look at the arrangement of
these pieces and get a good feel for
how the pieces are meant
to fit together.
So this representation helps me
understand the problem in a way
that the other representation did not.