Let's watch that animation again.
The hiker goes up the hill on one day,
stays the night.
And then goes back down
the hill the next day.
And we want to know,
was the hiker ever at the same point
at the same time on both days?
And the answer is yes.
Describe the way we
describe it right here,
it might actually seem odd that
there is a point where the hiker is
in the same place at
the same time on both days.
That seems like a strange coincidence,
but
what if we tweak
the representation a little bit?
Instead of one hiker going up and
then coming down the next day.
Let's visualize the two
days at the same time.
If we represent the problem like this,
we'll quickly see the hiker
has to pass himself.
To show it again,
we know the answer is yes,
because there's a time when the hiker
would have passed himself if he was
going in both directions
on the same day.
And to pass himself, he has to be
in the same point at the same time.
That representation took a hard
problem and made it very easy.