So in some contexts, it's now no harder
to construct an actual interface than it
is to construct a prototype, so we might
skip the prototyping phase altogether.
However, prototypes also allowed
us to gather feedback from users.
Even though we can now easily
construct an interface,
we don't want to immediately roll out
a completely untested interface to
everyone who visits our site.
We might be able to fix it quickly, but
we're still eroding user trust in us and
wasting our user's time.
That's where the second facet
of this comes in, AB testing.
AB testing is the name given to rapid
software testing between typically two
alternatives, A and B.
Statistically it's not any
different from T-tests.
What makes AB testing unique is that
we're usually rapidly testing small
changes with real users.
We usually do it by rolling out the B
version, the new version to only a small
number of users, and ensuring that
nothing goes terribly wrong, or
there's not a dramatic
dip in performance.
That way we can make sure a change is
positive, or at least neutral, before
rolling it out to everyone, but look
where testing feedback coming in here.
They're coming automatically with
the real users during normal
usage of our tool.
There's no added cost to
recruiting participants and
the feedback is received instantly.
So for a quick example,
this is the overview page for
one of Udacity's programs and it
provides a timeline the students should
dedicate to the program in
terms of number of hours.
Is number of hours the best
way to display this?
I don't know, we could find out.
Instead of showing 420 hours maybe
I say this as 20 hours per week.
In this interface all I
have to do is edit it and
I immediately have a new version of
this interface that I can try out.
Now I can click Start Experiment and
try this out.
I could find out.
Does phrasing this as ten hours per
week, does it increase the number?
Does it decrease the number?
If it decreases it,
I can very quickly roll this back.
If it increases it, I can very
quickly roll this out to everybody.
I'm going through the same
design life cycle.
I understand that the need is for
the user to know where the timeline is.
I've got a design in mind,
which is to show the timeline
in number of hours per week.
I prototype it.
It just happens to be here
that the prototype is live.
And I immediately roll it out.
I look at how users use it,
I evaluate it, and
I decide if I want to roll back that
change, or roll it out to everybody.
I can go through a microcosm, a very
rapid iteration to really design life
cycle by using live prototyping and
AB testing.