If you're watching this course in the order it was originally produced,
you've now learned the foundational principles of
HCI and the research methods behind developing interfaces.
Now at the beginning of the course,
we also previewed some of the open areas of HCI development and research.
Now, what we'd like to do is give you a jump-start in
looking into what areas are most interesting to you.
In the lessons that follow,
we'll replay the preview videos for each topic from the beginning of the course,
and then provide a small library of information on each topic.
We certainly don't expect you to go through every portion of all these lessons.
Find what's interesting to you and use these materials as your jumping off point.