Human-computer interaction is a massive field with lots of subdomains.
This course has been a combination of the fundamental methods and principles of HCI,
but there are lots of directions you could go from here.
In this lesson, I've attempted to give you some ideas of where you might look next.
You might be interested in the research side of HCI and
exploring more about how technology influences the way people think and act.
You might be interested in the design side and
creating excellent user interfaces and experiences.
You might be interested in collaboration and helping
people interact across technology or you
might be interested in artificial intelligence and
designing interfaces that adapt to the user's needs.
Whatever your interest, there's a rich amount of content in HCI in front of you.
Now, the last thing we need to think about is,
how do you best get that content?