Human-computer interaction was concerned with the interaction between users
and tasks as mediated by things with computing power.
Nowadays, that's more and more common,
it's a relatively recent phenomenon that things like
watches and cameras were examples of computers.
Where a device doesn't have computational power behind it though,
there are still lots of design considerations to make.
In fact, many of our principals and many of our methods
apply just as well to non computational interfaces.
What makes human factors engineering particularly interesting,
is that it deals with more constraints, physical constraints.
Things like the height of the user or the size of
a hand come up in human factors engineering.
What's interesting though is that as many devices
start to have computational resources added to them,
human factors engineering and
human-computer interactions start to interact more and more.
My watch for example has no computational resources to it,
it's completely within the human factors area,
but smartwatches see some interesting interactions between human factors and HCI.
Human factors determines the size of the watch,
which determines the size of the battery or the sensors that can be placed inside.
Those things then influence what we can do from the HCI perspective.
So, if you're dealing with anything related to ubiquitous computing,
wearable devices, contextual computing,
human factors engineering is a great place to start.
So, we'll throw you some resources in the notes below.