Likely the most significant subfield of HCI is user interface design.
Colloquially, user interface design most often
refers to design between a user and some rectangular screen,
be it a traditional computer,
a tablet, a laptop,
a smartphone, and so on.
For a long time, user interface design in
HCI were actually pretty much synonymous because
the vast majority of interaction between users and
computers happened to via a rectangular onscreen interface,
connected to a mouse and keyboard.
It's relatively recent that we've started to see
interaction break out of that literal box,
and to a certain extent, the term UI design,
a user interface design,
captures this as well.
Interfaces don't have to be screens.
Colloquially though, I find most classes on user interface design,
focus on designing screens and interacting with screens.
That's a massive and well-developed field.
In fact, a lot of this course's material comes from the user interface design space.
There are also some more narrow things that
user interface design is concerned with though.
UI design has its own set of design principles that apply more
narrowly to the design of traditional computer software or Web sites.
Some of these principles guide how people visually group things together,
and these are called Gestalt grouping principles.
When things are close together,
we mentally put them into groups.
You'll likely see two groups of three,
and one group of six.
When there are implicit lines,
we see a continuation.
You'll likely see this as a cube,
even though the lines are broken.
We also group things together based on similarity.
You probably see this as four blue squares,
two gray diamonds, and three orange circles.
While right now you see this as a three by three grid of green circles,
watch what happens when they move.
Even after they stopped moving,
you likely still see the diamond that was formed by those moving circles.
These Gestalt principles in some ways,
applied a user-interface designs emphasis on designing with good grids in mind.
Just the way magazines and newspapers have done for centuries.
We've already discussed this example a lot,
and part of it is because this new interface leverages the analogy to the old interface.
But its value isn't just in the analogy,
its value is also in the way it instantiates
the same Gestalt principles that guided the layout of a newspaper.
Finally, user interface design touches on one of my favorite topics, typography.
Typography is often covered in user interface design courses.
So generally speaking, while in HCI we've taken special care to talk about
general methods that deal with any kind of computer interface between users and tasks,
user interface design zooms more closely in on the design of interfaces on screens.
If you want to study user-interface design some more,
we'll add some links to related courses and materials online to the notes below.