For a lot of people,
HCI and user experience design are essentially the same thing.
For me though, UX design is a little bit more
prescriptive while HCI is a little bit more descriptive.
HCI describes how people learn and interpret interfaces
while UX design prescribes what you should do with that information.
But in many ways, let's just apply the HCI.
The content is the same.
The question is how you use it.
If you choose to continue your studies in UX design though,
there are a few new things you'll encounter.
You'll see an increased focus on the mood and the joy of the user.
We want them to have a great experience not just accomplish a task.
You'll see more attention paid to
the user's motivations behind engaging with the interface.
You also see a greater emphasis on the interaction between the user,
the interface, and the contexts all around them,
as these are all parts of the user experience.
These are all things we've talked about but
user experience gets into prescribing these with more specificity.
So, if you want some more information on user experience design,
we'll put some resources in the notes below.