Early in our conversations,
we described how HCI is generally about an interaction between design and research.
We use research findings to inform our designs,
and we use the success of our designs to create new research findings.
As you explore more HCI though,
you'll find that there's plenty of room to specialize in one side of the other.
Professional designers focus almost exclusively on the creation side,
but there are lots of people who focus exclusively on the research side of HCI.
Many universities like Georgia Tech and
Carnegie Mellon have research faculty dedicated to
understanding the way people interact with technology
at individual group and societal levels.
So, if you're more interested in understanding how
people interact with interfaces than in designing new ones,
you might be interested in taking more of a research bent on HCI.
This class is actually built from
the research perspective more than the designer perspective,
so you've already got a great foundation.
We'll add some links below if you want to explore some more.