HCI research broadens to a field called human-centered computing.
While much of HCI research is concerned with
the immediate interactions between people and computers,
human-centered computing is interested more generally in
how computers and humans affect each other at the societal level.
There's a lot of really fascinating research going on in this area.
Some of the questions people are addressing are,
how did participants in
the Arab Spring use tools like Facebook and Twitter to coordinate?
How can information visualizations be employed to help
people better understand their diet and their energy usage?
How does access to computing resources influence early childhood education?
Now, notice that these issues don't necessarily
involve designing new interfaces or creating new tools.
They involve looking at the way people interact with computers more generally,
and not just specific tools,
but the ubiquity of technology as a whole.
So, if you find this interesting,
we'll put some more materials in the notes below.