[MUSIC]
Over the many years of HCI development,
experts have come up with a wide variety
of principles and heuristics for
designing good interfaces.
None of these are hard and fast rules
like the law of gravity or something.
But they're useful guidelines to keep
in mind when designing our interfaces.
Likely, the most popular and
influential of these is Don Norman's
six principles of design.
Larry Constantine and Lucy Lockwood
have a a similar set of principles of
user interface design, with some
overlaps but also some distinctions.
Jacob Nielsen has a set
of Ten Heuristics for
user interface design that can be
used for both design and evaluation.
And while those are all interested
in general usability, there also
exists a set of seven principles
called Principles of Universal Design.
These are similarly concerned with
usability, but more specifically for
the greatest number of people.
Putting these four sets together, we'll
talk about 15 unique principles for
interaction design.