There are a few things
we could do actually.
Maybe we could put a small letter next
to each light switch that indicates
which light in the room
that switch controls.
K for kitchen, C for counter top,
B for breakfast room.
Maybe we actually put icons
that demonstrates which
kind of light is
controlled by each switch.
So the counter top lights
are kind of sconce lights, so
maybe we put an icon that looks
like the counter top lights.
But likely the easiest thing is actually
the way the system really was designed.
I just didn't notice it until
I started writing this video.
The lights from left to right in
the room are actually controlled by
the light switches from
left to right on the wall.
This switch controls
the light over there.
the light right here.
And this switch controls
the light back there.
That actually forms
a pretty intuitive mapping.