Our next principle is perceptibility.
Perceptibility refers to the user's
ability to perceive the state of
the system.
Nielsen states that the system should
always keep users informed about what is
going on, through appropriate
feedback within reasonable time.
That allows the user to perceive
what's going on inside the system.
Universal design notes that the design
should communicate necessary information
effectively to the user,
regardless of ambient conditions or
the user's sensory abilities.
In other words,
everyone using the interface should be
able to perceive the current state.
Note that this is also similar
to Norman's notion of feedback.
He writes that feedback must be
immediate, must be informative, and
that poor feedback can be
worse than no feedback at all.
But feedback is so ubiquitous, so
general, that really, feedback could be
applied to any principle we talk
about in this entire lesson.
So instead we're going to reserve
this more narrow definition for
when we talk about errors.
And our lesson on feedback cycles covers
the idea of feedback more generally.
Things like light switches and oven
dials, actually do this very nicely.
I can look at a light switch and
determine whether the system it controls
is on or off, based on whether
the switch is up or down.
Same with the oven dial.
I can immediately see
where the dial is set.
But there's a common household control,
that flagrantly violates this
principle of perceptibility.
Here's our ceiling fan,
you might have one just like it.
It has two chains.
One controls the light,
one controls the fan speed.
But both only when the switch
on the wall is on.
Now first, the mapping here is awful.
There's no indication
which control is which.
But worse, the fan chain,
which is this one,
doesn't give any indication of which
setting the fan is on currently.
I don't honestly even know
how many settings it has.
[SOUND] I don't know if pulling
it makes it go up and then down,
up and then off, down and then off.
Whenever I use it, I just pull it, wait
ten seconds and see if I like the speed,
and then pull it again.
And this is all only if
the wall switch is on.
Now, of course people have resolved
this with dials or other controls, and
yet these dang chains still seem to be
the most common approach despite this
challenge of perceptibility.