Depending on your expertise with the computers,
there's a strong chance you found yourself on
one side or the other of the following exchange.
Imagine, one person is watching another person use a computer.
The person using the computer repeatedly right-clicks and selects cut to cut things,
and then right-click, and selects Paste to paste them back again.
The person watching insists that they can just use Control X and Control
V. The person working doesn't understand why the person watching cares.
The person watching doesn't understand why
the person working what use the more efficient method.
In reality, they're both right.
This is the principle of flexibility.
These two options are available because of the principle of flexibility,
from both Nielsen's heuristics and the principles of universal design.
Nielsen specifically comments on the use of accelerators, which are hotkeys.
He says that accelerators may often speed up the interaction for the expert user,
such that the system can cater to both inexperienced and experienced users.
He advises that we allow users to tailor frequent actions.
Universal design says something similar.
They noted that the design should accommodate
a wide range of individual preferences and abilities.
Another set of design principles from Dicks et al also
have a category of principles called Flexibility Principles,
that advocate user customizability in supporting multiple designs for the same task.
Here, Nielsen is most interested in catering to both novice and expert users.
While the principles of universal design are more interested
in accommodating users of various abilities and preferences.
But the underlying principle here is the same, flexibility.
Wherever possible, we should support
the different interactions in which people engage naturally,
rather than forcing them into one against their expertise or against their preference.