The principle of flexibility
in some ways appears to
clash with the principle of equity.
But both come from the principles
of universal design.
The principle of flexibility said the
design should accommodate a wide range
of individual preferences and abilities.
But the principle of equity
says the design is useful and
marketable to people with
diverse abilities, and
it goes on to say we should provide
the same means for all users,
identical whenever possible and
equivalent when not.
And we should avoid segregating or
stigmatizing any users.
Now, in some ways,
these systems might compete.
This says we should allow every user
to use the system the same way,
whereas this one says that
we should allow different,
flexible methods of
interacting with the system.
In reality, though, these are actually
complementary of one another.
Equity is largely about helping all
users have the same user experience,
while flexibility might be
a means to achieve that.
For example, if we want all our
users to enjoy using our interface,
keeping things discoverable for novice
users and efficient for expert users
allows us to accommodate a wide range of
individual preferences and abilities.
User experience in this instance means
treating every user like they're within
the target audience and extending
the same benefits to all users,
including things like privacy and
security.
We might do that in different ways, but
the important note is that the
experience is the same across all users.
That's what equity is about.
One good example of equity in action are
the requirements for password resets.
We want to design a system so
that both expert and
novice users experience
the same level of security.
Security is part of the user experience.
Now, experts, we would assume,
understand the value
of a complex password.
Novices might not.
So if we don't have
requirements around passwords,
novices might not experience the same
level of security as experts.
So password requirements can be seen
as a way of making sure the user
experience across novices and experts
is the same with regard to security.
In the process, we might actually
frustrate novice users a little bit.
You could actually see this as a
violation of the flexibility principle,
that we're not flexibly accommodating
in the kind of interaction that novices
want to have.
But the important thing, is we're
extending the same security benefits to
everyone, and
that's equitable treatment.
And that's also a good
example of how at times,
the different design principles
will appear to compete, and
you have to decide what the best
approach is going forward.