Ease and comfort are two similar ideas
that come from the principles of
universal design.
And they also relate to
equitable treatment,
specifically in terms of
physical interaction.
The ease principle, which interestingly
uses the word comfort, says the design
can be used efficiently and comfortably
and with a minimum amount of fatigue.
The comfort principle notes
that appropriate size and
space is provided for approach,
reach, manipulation and
use regardless of the user's body size,
posture or mobility.
Now, in the past,
these principles didn't have an enormous
amount of application to HCI.
Because we generally assume that
the user was sitting at their desk with
a keyboard and a monitor.
But as more and more interfaces
are becoming equipped with computers,
we'll find HCI dealing with
these issues more and more.
For example, the seat control in your
car might now actually be run be
a computer that remembers
your settings and
restores them when you
get back in the car.
That's an instance of HCI
trying to improve user ease and
comfort in a physical area.
Mobile interfaces are great
examples of this as well.
When deciding the size of
buttons on a mobile interface,
we should take into consideration that
some users might have tremors that
make it more difficult to interact
precisely with different buttons.
As we get into areas like wearable
computing and virtual reality,
these issues of ease and comfort are
going to become more and more pertinent.