The structure principle is concerned with the overall architecture of a user interface.
In many ways, it's more closely related to
the narrower field of user interface design than HCI more generally.
It comes from Constantine and Lockwood,
and they define it as their structure principle, which says that,
"Design should organize a user-interface purposefully,
in meaningful and useful ways,
based on clear, consistent models that are apparent and recognizable to users,
putting related things together and separating unrelated things,
differentiating dissimilar things and making similar things resemble one another."
It's a long sentence,
but what it really says is we should organize our user interfaces in
ways that helps the user's mental model match the actual content of the task.
What's interesting to me about the structure principle is that it
borrows from a form of UI design that predates computers entirely.
We find many of the principles we learned in designing newspapers and
textbooks apply nicely to user interfaces as well.
For example, this is the Wall Street Journal print edition from several years ago,
and here's the Wall Street Journal website.
Notice that many of the structural principles present in
the print version are present in the website as well.
Now, part of that is for brand consistency,
but part of it is because the very same ideas we used in developing
magazines and newspapers still apply to the development of websites.
Lines and spacing still separate different categories of articles,
headlines are still in bold,
while the article text is smaller.
Now, there are, of course, differences because the website can, for example,
link to articles while physical papers cannot,
which is why these are all shorter than the articles in the actual paper are.
But we see a lot of the same principles at work in
the website that were at work in the physical layout.
Those are largely parts of structure.
Organizing things in intuitive ways that group together similar parts,
separate dissimilar parts, and help the user navigate what they're consuming.