We can't constrain away all errors all the time though.
So, there are two principles for how we deal with
errors that do occur, feedback and tolerance.
Tolerance means that users shouldn't be at risk of causing too much trouble accidentally.
For this Nielsen writes that,
"Users often choose system functions by mistake,
and will need a clearly marked 'emergency exit' to
leave the unwanted state without having to go through an extended dialogue.
Support, undo and redo."
For Constantine and Lockwood,
this is the tolerance principle.
They write, "The design should be flexible and tolerant,
reducing the cost of mistakes and misuse by allowing undoing and redoing,
while also preventing errors wherever possible."
It should be becoming clear why
that Control-Y issue with Visual Studio was so significant.
Undo and redo are fundamental concepts of tolerance,
and that Control-Y issue where Control-Y removes the line in
Visual Studio gets in the way of redo allowing us to recover from mistakes.
For Dix et al., this is the principle of recoverability.
Now, Nielsen's definition is most interested in supporting user experimentation.
The system should tolerate users poking around with things.
Universal design simply says,
"The design minimizes hazards and
the adverse consequences of accidental or unintended actions."
Dix et al. also refers to this as the principle of recoverability.
Now, Nielsen's definition is most interested in supporting user experimentation.
The system should tolerate users poking around with things.
That actually enhances the principle of discoverability.
Because if the user feels safe experimenting with things,
they're more likely to discover what's available to them.
The principles from Constantine and Lockwood,
and the principles of universal design are more
about recovering from traditional mistakes.
Jef Raskin poses this as a more humorous law of interface design,
"A computer shall not harm your work or through inactivity,
allow your work to come to harm."
So, we first have to make sure that the system
prevents the user from doing too much damage accidentally.
Either by constraining them away from making those mistakes,
or allowing an easy way to recover once those mistakes have been made.