Second, the system should give plenty of
feedback so that the user can understand
why the error happened and
how to avoid it in the future.
Norman writes that feedback must be
immediate and it must be informative.
Poor feedback can be worse
than no feedback at all.
Because it's distracting, uninformative,
and, in many cases, irritating and
anxiety-provoking.
If anything has ever described the
classic Windows Blue Screen of Death,
it's this.
It's terrifying.
It's bold.
It's cryptic.
And it scares you more
than it informs you.
Nielsen writes that error messages
should be expressed in plain language
(no codes),
precisely indicate the problem, and
constructively suggest a solution.
Note this tight relationship
with recoverability.
Not only should it be possible
to recover from an error,
the system should tell you exactly
how to recover from an error.
That's feedback in response to errors.
For Constantine and Lockwood,
this is the feedback principle.
The design should keep users
informed of actions or
interpretations, changes of state or
condition, and errors or exceptions...
through clear, concise, and
unambiguous language familiar to users.
Again, the old Windows blue screen
of death doesn't do this very well.
Because the language is not familiar,
it's not concise, and
it doesn't actually tell you
what the state or condition is.
The new one does a much
better job of this.
Notice as well that Norman, Constantine,
and Lockwood are interested in feedback
more generally,
not just in response to errors.
That's so fundamental that we have
an entire lesson on feedback cycles
that really is more emblematic of
the overall principle of feedback.
Here we're most interested in
feedback in response to errors,
which is a very important
concept on its own