We've talked about a bunch of different design principles in this lesson.
How these design principles apply to your design tasks will
differ significantly based on what area you're working in.
In gestural interfaces, for example,
constraints presented a big challenge because we
can't physically constrain our users' movement,
we have to give them feedback or feedforward in different ways.
If we're working in particularly complex domains,
we have to think hard about what simplicity means.
If the underlying task is complex,
how simple can and should the interface actually be.
We might find ourselves in domains with enormous concerns regarding universal design.
If you create something that a person with a disability can't use,
you risk big problems both ethically and legally.
So, take a few moments and reflect on how these design principles
apply to the area of HCI that you've chosen to investigate.