Our first principle is discoverability.
Don Norman describes it by asking, is it
possible to even figure out what actions
are possible and where and
how to perform them?
Nielsen has a similar principle.
He advises us to minimize the user's
memory load by making objects, actions,
and options visible.
Instructions for
use of the system should be visible or
easily retrievable whenever appropriate.
In other words,
when the user doesn't know what to do,
they should be able to easily
figure out what to do.
Constantine and
Lockwood have a similar principle
called the visibility principle.
The design should make all
needed options and materials for
a given task visible without
distracting the user with extraneous or
redundant information.
The idea behind all three of these
principles is that relevant function
should be made visible, so the user
can discover them as opposed to having
to read about them in some documentation
or learn them through some tutorial.
Let's take an example
of this real quick.
Here in PowerPoint, there are a number
of different menus available at the top,
as well as some toolbars.
The effect here is that I can browse
the different functions available to me.
I can discover what's there.
For Nielsen, this means that I don't
have to remember all of these.
I just have to recognize them
when I see them in the tool bars.
For example, I don't have to remember
Arrange as some keyboard I have
to type in manually to bring up some
ideas about how I might arrange things.
All I have to do is recognize Arrange
as the right button when I see it.
Now while this might be true at the
application level, it's not often true
at the operating system level, because
the operating system doesn't command so
much screen real estate all the time and
probably for good reason.
So for example, on a Mac,
I can use Command Shift 4 to
take a screen shot only of
a certain area of my screen.
However, the only way I know of
to find that is to Google it or
read it in a manual.
It isn't discoverable or
visible on it's own.
And you might never even
realize it's possible.
So the principle of discoverability
advocates that functions be visible to
the user, so
that they can discover them, rather then
relying on them learning them elsewhere.
I actually use a PC more than a Mac.
And whenever I come back to my Mac
after not using it for awhile,
I have to Google that again.
I know it's possible, but
I never remember the command
that actually makes it happen.
Constantine and Lockwood's principle
of visibility would add on to this that
we shouldn't get too crazy.
We want to make functions discoverable,
but
that doesn't mean just throwing
everything on the screen.
We want to walk a line between
discoverability, and simplicity