Discoverability is one of the challenges
for designing gesture-based interfaces.
To understand this, let's watch Morgan
do some ordinary actions with her phone.
[MUSIC]
[SOUND]
We just saw Morgan do four
things with the phone.
Reject a call, take a screenshot,
take a selfie, and make a phone call.
For each of those,
this phone actually has a corresponding
gesture that would have made it easier.
She could have just turned the phone
over to reject the call or said, shoot,
to take the selfie.
The problem is that these
are not discoverable.
Having a menu of voice commands kind
of defeats the purpose of saving
screen real estate and simplicity
through gestures and voice commands.
So, brainstorm a bit.
How would you make these gesture
commands more discoverable?