Norman and
Nielsen both talk about the need for
a mapping between interfaces and
their effects in the world.
Norman notes that mapping is actually
a technical term coming from mathematics
that means a relationship between
the elements of two sets of things.
In this case, our two sets
are the interface and the world.
For example, these book icons
might help you map these quotes
to the books from which they were taken.
Nielsen describes mapping by saying the
system should speak the users' language,
with words, phrases, and
concepts that are familiar to the user,
rather than system-oriented terms.
Follow real-world conventions, making
information appear in a natural and
logical order.
A great example of this,
is the fact that we call cut, copy, and
paste, cut, copy and paste.
Surely there could have been more
technical terms like duplicate instead
of copy.
But using cut, copy, and paste
forms a natural mapping between our
own vocabulary and
what happens in the system.
Note that these two principles
are subtly different, but
they're actually strongly related.
Nielsen's heuristic
describes the general goal,
while Norman's principle
describes one way to achieve it.
Strong mappings help make information
appear in natural and logical order.
A great example of this is setting
the arrangement of different monitors.
This actually comes from my
display in my home office.
This visualization creates a very
natural mapping between the way
the system treats the monitors, and
they way they're actually
laid out in the world.
If there's a mismatch, or
if something doesn't make sense, I can
easily look at this and map it with
the arrangement of the monitors in front
of me and figure out what's going on.
This could instead be shown as
just a list of pixel locations.
And that would still present all
the exact same information, but
in a way that isn't as easily
mapped out to the real world.
Now, mappings and
affordances are similar principles, but
they have a clear and
important difference.
We can see that difference
in our color meter again.
Affordances were about creating
interfaces where their designs suggested
how they're supposed to be used.
The placement of this notch
along this horizontal bar,
kind of affords the idea that
it could be dragged around.
The horizontal bar visualizes the space
which makes it seem like we could move
that notch around to set our color.
However, that design on its own wouldn't
necessarily create a good mapping.
Imagine, if instead of the bar
fading from white to black,
it was just white the entire way.
It would still be very obvious
how you're supposed to use it.
But it wouldn't be obvious what the
effect of using it would actually be.
It's the present of that
fade from white to black
that makes it easier to see what will
happen if I actually drag that around.
I can imagine it's going to make
the colors fade from white to black.
That creates the mapping to the effect
of dragging it around on that meter.
So mapping refers to creating interfaces
where the design makes it clear what
the effect will be when using them,
not just creating interfaces where it's
clear how you're supposed to use them.
With this color meter, the arrangement
of the controls makes clear what to do
and the visualization underneath, makes
it clear what will happen when I do it.